<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[小马宝嘟嘟的Mommy]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T22:39:05+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessie125.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jessie]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[niechao125@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sarkozy Under Formal Investigation-萨科齐受到正式调查]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/sarkozy-under-investigation/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T20:52:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/sarkozy-under-investigation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>French politics</strong><br/>
<strong>法国政治</strong></p>

<p>Mar 19th 2013, 20:11 by S.M. | NEW YORK</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/03/blogs/charlemagne/20130323_eup504.jpg" alt="萨科齐受到正式调查" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>“A THUNDERBOLT”, is how one French paper greeted the news that Nicolas Sarkozy was placed under formal judicial investigation, late on March 21st. The former French president is to be investigated for “abuse of frailty”, in connection with an illegal party-financing case linked to Liliane Bettencourt, the elderly billionaire heiress to the L’Oréal cosmetics empire.</p>

<p>尼古拉斯•萨科齐于3月21日受到正式的司法调查，法国媒体将这场调查称之为“（政治界和法律界的）地震”。这位法国前总统因涉嫌收取法国亿万富翁、欧莱雅集团女继承人莉莉亚娜•贝当古的非法政治献金而受到调查。</p>

<p>The Bettencourt case, which began as a dynastic dispute and turned into a saga that mixes alleged tax evasion, a tropical island, domestic servants, fabulous wealth and political party-financing, has been underway for several years. Nearly a dozen people have been put under formal investigation, including Eric Woerth, the former treasurer of Mr Sarkozy’s UMP party and an ex-minister. Until now, it looked as if Mr Sarkozy had escaped such a fate. Last November investigating judges held him for 12 hours of questioning, as a witness in the case, but decided not to pursue a formal investigation.</p>

<p>“贝当古事件”始于家族内斗，后演变为涉及偷税漏税，热带岛屿，家佣，巨额财富以及政治竞选筹资的家族传奇，并连续上演多年。将近十几个人接受了正式调查，其中包括萨科奇所在的人民运动联盟（注释1）的前预算部长埃里克•沃尔斯。至今为止，萨科齐似乎已逃脱这一立案调查。去年11月，调查法官对萨科齐进行了12小时的问询，只是作为“需要律师在旁协助的证人”而接受问询，法官决定不对其进行正式调查。</p>

<p>On March 21st, however, investigating judges in Bordeaux questioned Mr Sarkozy again, and confronted him with various witnesses, including Mrs Bettencourt’s former butler, Pascal Bonnefoy, and other former domestic staff. This time, the investigating judge decided that he had enough evidence to go ahead.</p>

<p>然而，调查法官于3月21日在波尔多市向萨科奇进行了再一次的问询，并与多名证人进行了对质，包括贝当古女士的前管家帕斯卡•博纳富瓦以及其他几位前家佣。调查法官认为他这次已有足够的证据对萨科奇进行正式调查。</p>

<p>The case centres around whether or not Mr Sarkozy requested or received illegal sums from Mrs Bettencourt to help to finance his successful 2007 election campaign. Under French law, no private individual can contribute more than €4,600 ($5,960). Investigators are looking into allegations that €150,000 was transferred by Mrs Bettencourt’s former wealth manager to Mr Sarkozy’s party. The heiress’s former butler, whose tape of private conversations at her house triggered part of the investigation, alleges that there have been several meetings between Mr Sarkozy and the Bettencourts. The family’s mansion is in Neuilly, a posy suburb of Paris where Mr Sarkozy was mayor for many years.</p>

<p>这一事件聚焦于萨科齐是否要求或者获得贝当古女士的非法资金为自己2007年的成功竞选筹资。根据法国法律的规定，个人的政治献金不能超过4600欧元（5960美元）。贝当古的私人理财经理曾将15万欧元转入萨科齐竞选团队“金库”，调查人员正对这一事件进行调查。这位女继承人的前管家在房子里录下贝当古的秘密谈话也受到调查，该管家称萨科奇和贝当古家族会面频繁。该家族的宅邸位于巴黎的花园式纳依市，萨科齐曾在该市做了多年的市长。</p>

<p>For his part, Mr Sarkozy has denied all allegations. According to leaked testimony after his hearing by investigators last November, he said that: “The Bettencourts never gave me a penny, and I never asked anything of them”. The former president acknowledges dining with the Bettencourts at their mansion before his election, and meeting Liliane Bettencourt once afterwards, but in neither case, he says, did he request donations. Mr Sarkozy’s lawyer has called the decision to put his client under formal investigation “inconsistent” and “unfair”, and said that he will appeal.</p>

<p>萨科齐本人对这些指控加以否认。根据去年11月的调查听证会泄露的证词，他说：“贝当古家族从来没有给我一分钱，我也从未向他们问过钱”。这位法国前总统承认在他参与竞选之前曾在贝当古家族的宅邸与他们一起吃过饭，之后还和莉莉亚娜•贝当古见过一面，但是在这两次会面中绝对没有向他们提出捐款要求。萨科齐的律师表示，对萨科齐进行正式调查是“前后矛盾，不公平的决定”，他还将提出上诉。</p>

<p>As politicians digested the news, some UMP members seized on the idea of a conspiracy. Christian Estrosi, a former minister under Mr Sarkozy, denounced an “obvious hint of politics”, noting that the judge’s decision came two days after a Socialist minister, Jérôme Cahuzac, resigned in connection with a tax-fraud investigation. Henri Guaino, a deputy and former Elysée adviser to Mr Sarkozy, said that the judge had &ldquo;dishonoured&rdquo; the justice system. Others did not go this far, but did not hesitate to criticise the judicial decision. François Fillon, Mr Sarkozy’s former prime minister, declared the move “extravagant”.</p>

<p>当此事从政界中淡化，人民运动联盟的一些成员利用了“阴谋论”这一说法。萨科齐手下的前部长克里斯蒂安•埃斯特鲁斯谴责这一调查是明显的政治行为，并且指出法官是在杰罗姆•卡于扎克因涉嫌税务欺骗而离职的两天后的做出的这一决定。萨科齐的前代理顾问亨利•盖伊诺称法官是败坏国家的司法体系。虽然有些人认为没有严重到这个地步，但是也直言不讳的批判这一司法决定。萨科齐手下的前总理弗朗索瓦•菲永表示这一立案调查行为“荒谬之极”。</p>

<p>Although Mr Sarkozy is presumed innocent during a formal investigation, this sort of probe can go on for years, and can mark public opinion even if the suspect is acquitted. It comes at a particularly awkward time for the former president, who had begun to hint at a political come-back in time for the 2017 presidential election, something he had previously ruled out after his defeat last year by François Hollande. Polls even suggested that the French had begun to forgive him. One, in Paris-Match magazine, shows that, if a run-off vote were held today, 53% would back Mr Sarkozy compared with just 44% for Mr Hollande.</p>

<p>虽然一场正式调查推测萨科齐可能是无辜的，但是这一调查可以进行数年，即便犯罪嫌疑人无罪释放，多少也会受到舆论的影响。这一正式调查来的也真不是时候，这位法国前总统在之前暗示将重回政坛，参加2017年的总统竞选（去年被弗朗索瓦•奥兰德击败后，萨科齐曾否认继续参与总统竞选）。民意调查显示，法国人民也开始渐渐遗忘萨科奇。《巴黎竞赛报》上的一项民意测试显示：如果在现在进行一场决赛选举的话，萨科齐将拥有53%的支持率，而奥兰德只有44%。</p>

<p>It would be a mistake, however, to assume that this rules out for ever Mr Sarkozy’s return. He could yet be acquitted. And the French have a remarkably forgiving approach even to those found guilty of political wrongdoing. Indeed, Mr Sarkozy himself knows something about this. Alain Juppé, a one-time conservative prime minister, was once convicted for political corruption in connection with a fake jobs scandal at the Paris town hall. Mr Sarkozy brought him back into government, and appointed him foreign minister.</p>

<p>如果说这次正式调查使萨科齐重返政坛的梦破碎了，那就大错特错了，他有可能被宣告无罪。而且法国人的饶恕程度超乎想象，他们甚至能宽恕那些有政治不当行为的人。萨科齐本人对此也有所了解。前保守派总理阿兰•朱佩曾涉嫌在市政厅“设虚职领薪”的政治腐败行为被判处监禁。后来萨科齐让他回归政坛，任命为外交部长。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syria: Entanglement at Home and Abroad-叙利亚纠缠于国内外势力的交锋]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/Syria/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T20:52:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/Syria</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The rebels are buffeted by internal ructions and regional diplomacy</strong><br/>
<strong>反对派在内乱和地区外交的双面夹击中前行</strong></p>

<p>Mar 30th 2013 | BEIRUT |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130330_MAP004_0.jpg" alt="萨科齐受到正式调查" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>Has Khatib resigned or not?</strong><br/>
<strong>哈提卜是否真正辞职了？</strong></p>

<p>EARLIER this year things had been going rather well, militarily and politically, for Syria’s eternally fractious opposition and its rebel allies. Western governments had promised to channel more aid to the new Syrian National Coalition, an umbrella group in exile, for passing on to fighters battling Bashar Assad’s regime on the ground. Moaz al-Khatib, the coalition’s head, had emerged as a cannier and more popular politician than his predecessors seeking to unite Syria’s opposition. Yet on March 24th it was thrown into disarray when Mr Khatib resigned.</p>

<p>今年早些时候，叙利亚极端反对派及其盟友在军事行动和政治上都进展得相当不错。西方国家曾承诺向流亡“伞形集团”，即新成立的叙利亚国家联盟提供更多的援助，派遣歼击机对巴沙尔•阿萨德政府进行地面打击。在力图联合叙利亚反对势力上，现任国家联盟领导人穆瓦兹•哈提卜比前任更为精明，且是一位更受欢迎的政治家。然而，3月24日哈提卜的辞职，使得叙利亚再一次陷入混乱。</p>

<p>A widely respected former preacher at one of Damascus’s biggest mosques, Mr Khatib had become frustrated by the coalition’s refusal to broaden its membership and listen to new ideas. A case in point was the recent election of Ghassan Hitto to be prime minister of an interim government. Disgruntled members of the opposition accused the Muslim Brotherhood of empowering Mr Hitto, a hitherto little-known businessman who had spent many years in Texas. Several coalition members resigned in protest, while the head of the opposition’s military wing, Selim Idriss, said he would not accept Mr Hitto’s authority.</p>

<p>曾在大马士革其中一家最大的清真寺担任牧师且广受尊敬的哈提卜对该联盟拒绝扩大阵营以及听取新的建议的行为感到很失望。最近选举加萨尼・希托为“过渡政府”总理就是这样的一个事例。愤愤不平的反对者指责“穆斯林兄弟会”授权给多年在（美国）德克萨斯州经商且迄今鲜为人知的希托。有几位联盟成员辞职以示抗议，反对势力的军事派首领塞利姆•埃德瑞斯（自由军总参谋长）表示他不会接受希托当局。</p>

<p>Mr Khatib, with an American nod, has been wary of forming an interim government, thinking that it would make it harder for the opposition to negotiate with the Syrian regime, which he had controversially declared himself open to doing. The Qataris and the Muslim Brotherhood, which apparently favour Mr Hitto, take a harder line, insisting that Mr Assad should go as a precondition for any negotiations.</p>

<p>获得美国首肯的哈提卜哈提卜在建立一个“过渡政府”上一直都是小心行事，他认为很难让反对派和叙利亚政府进行谈判，他曾经主张和叙政府公开谈判而颇受争议。大力支持希托的卡塔尔和穆斯林兄弟会对此采取更加强硬的态度，强调谈判的前提就是阿萨德下台。</p>

<p>Such turmoil could turn the coalition into “a dead body”, says Fawaz Tello, an independent member of the opposition. Rivalry between foreign backers is partly to blame, says Salman Shaikh, who heads the Qatari branch of the Washington-based Brookings Institution, a think-tank. The opposition took Syria’s official seat at an Arab League meeting on March 26th—in Qatar. Mr Khatib, however, still headed the Syrian delegation, perhaps a sign that Qatar recognises his importance.</p>

<p>一位独立的反对派成员Fawaz Tello表示，这样的骚动可能会使该联盟解体。驻华盛顿的智库布鲁金斯学会多哈研究中心主任萨勒曼•谢赫称，国外支持势力的竞争是造成这一事态的部分原因。3月26日，反对派取代叙利亚政府参加了在卡塔尔举行的阿盟峰会，但仍是哈提卜率领叙利亚代表团出席此会，这也许表明卡塔尔意识到他的重要性。</p>

<p>In any event, Western governments may find it increasingly hard to influence the fighters in the field, let alone the opposition in exile. Recently the United States and several European countries have intensified their efforts to aid the rebels. Britain and France want to arm them, despite the recent refusal of the majority of European Union members to lift the current arms embargo.
不管怎么样，西方国家也许会发现越来越难以影响到叙利亚国内的反对势力了，更不用说流亡在外的反对派了。美国和欧洲几个国家最近加大了对反对派的援助。尽管最近多数欧盟成员国拒绝解除对叙利亚的武器禁运，英国和法国还是想对其提供武器。</p>

<p><strong>Hush-hush</strong><br/>
<strong>秘密行动</strong></p>

<p>The American administration remains loth to arm the opposition directly but the CIA has, at the least, been quietly sharing intelligence and training fighters. According to an investigation by the New York Times, the agency has been involved in a covert operation to arm the rebels and has been trying to vet the groups that receive arms through Turkey and Jordan, paid for by Gulf Arabs. It has also apparently sought to block the transfer of anti-aircraft weapons, lest they fall into jihadist hands.</p>

<p>美国政府仍不愿直接向反对派提供武器，但是至少中央情报局一直在秘密地提供情报和训练飞行员。《纽约时报》的一份调查报告指出中央情报局秘密地向反对派援助武器，试图帮助让反对派通过土耳其和约旦，并且由海湾阿拉伯国家支付费用来获得武器。情报局还力图限制防空武器的转移，以免这些武器落入激进分子的手中。</p>

<p>According to Hugh Griffiths of the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI), a Swedish think-tank, Qatari planes started to fly in weapons in January last year. Jordan and Saudi Arabia later got involved. The number of flights increased from December, with large consignments of weapons bought in Croatia. “At a conservative estimate they have transferred at least 3,500 tonnes,” says Mr Griffiths. “If it all were to get into Syria—which it hasn’t—it would definitely change the balance of power.”</p>

<p>瑞典智库-斯德哥尔摩国际和平研究所专家休•格里菲思表示，去年一月，卡塔尔空军开始运送武器装备，沙特和约旦空军也随后加入，自12月以来，从克罗地亚采购大量武器的飞机数量不断增加。格里菲思说：“保守估计的话，他们至少已经交付3500吨武器装备，如果这些武器全部进入叙利亚-虽然目前还没有-终将打破双方的军事平衡。”</p>

<p>One aim of Western policy is to counter Mr Assad’s allies, who are still trying to bolster his regime. America’s secretary of state, John Kerry, recently failed on a trip to Baghdad to persuade the Iraqi government to stop letting Iranian planes fly weapons through Iraq’s airspace. But some say Mr Assad has been getting fewer arms from Russia and Iran than the opposition has been getting from elsewhere. Hizbullah, the Lebanese party-cum-militia, may be helping Mr Assad to create an irregular force to fight alongside his army.</p>

<p>西方政策的一个目的是反击仍在支持阿萨德政府的国家。美国国务卿约翰•克里最近在访问巴格达时，没能说服伊拉克政府阻止伊朗的运载武器飞机经过伊拉克领空。但是有人认为阿萨德从俄罗斯和伊朗获得的武器要比从别的地方得到武器的反对派少得多，黎巴嫩真主党（政党和民兵组织）也许会帮助阿萨德创建一支非正规军和他的军队一起作战。</p>

<p>Western governments may be too late to achieve their aim of boosting moderates among the increasingly Islamist-leaning rebels. Islamist fighters, including Jabhat al-Nusra, which America considers a terrorist group, are better armed and organised. Some weapons, including M79 anti-tank missiles meant for more moderate groups, seem to have fallen into the hands of Jabhat al-Nusra and other Islamists.</p>

<p>西方国家想要在日益倾向伊斯兰教的反对派中实现温和战略，可能为时已晚。美国认为包括Jabhat al-Nusra在内的伊斯兰教武装分子是恐怖主义组织，他们装备齐全且很有组织。一些武器，如原本为温和反对组织提供的M79反坦克导弹似乎已落入Jabhat al-Nusra和其他伊斯兰教武装分子的手中。</p>

<p>As international involvement grows, Syria’s neighbours are struggling to avoid being dragged in. Turkey and Jordan fear that Mr Assad may retaliate against them. On March 26th Jordan closed its main border crossing with Syria.Two days before, Israel, which has kept out of the fight, fired a missile into Syria after its troops were shot at on the Golan Heights. Clashes have broken out in the Lebanese city of Tripoli, where Lebanese Sunni fighters allied to Syria’s rebels have become bolder. As foreigners get entangled, a risk is growing that Syria’s war will spill over its borders.</p>

<p>随着国际干预的增多，叙利亚周边国家尽力避免牵涉其中，土耳其和约旦担心阿萨德会报复他们。3月26日，约旦关闭了通往叙利亚的主要边境通道。两天前，还未牵扯到这场战争的以色列向戈兰高地南部叙利亚境内发射了一枚导弹，造成叙利亚武装人员受伤。黎巴嫩（北部）城市的黎波里爆发了冲突事件，支持叙利亚反对派黎巴嫩逊尼派武装人员在该市也愈发活跃。随着国外势力的介入，叙利亚战火可能会向其周边国家扩散。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barack Obama in Israel-奥巴马首次访问以色列]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/obama-in-israel/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T15:22:48+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/obama-in-israel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>How much can the president do?</strong><br/>
<strong>奥巴马总统在巴以关系中能发挥多大的作用？</strong></p>

<p>Mar 19th 2013, 20:11 by S.M. | NEW YORK</p>

<p><img src="http://photocdn.sohu.com/20130322/Img369867836.jpg" alt="奥巴马首次访问以色列" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>ON THE eve of Barack Obama’s first trip to Israel as president, commentators are lobbing a lot of unsolicited advice his way. At the Washington Post, Jennifer Rubin recommends channeling George W. Bush, who affirmed the Jews’ biblical tie to the land and avoided all criticism of Israeli settlements in his 2008 speech to the Knesset. In a New York Times op-ed, from the opposite perspective, Rashid Khalidi insists that Mr Obama “must forthrightly oppose the occupation and the settlements and support an inalienable Palestinian right to freedom, equality and statehood.”</p>

<p>在奥巴马奔赴以色列开启他连任总统后的首次出访（注释1）之前，一些评论家对他这次“值不值得”访问提出很多的激辩。《华盛顿邮报》专栏作者珍妮弗•鲁宾（注释2）建议参照乔治•布什2008年在以色列议会演讲中提出的建议，即肯定以色列在该地区的宗教归属性，以及避免对以色列定居点的批判。而拉希德•卡里迪不支持这种观点，在《纽约时报》专栏报导中，他坚决认为奥巴马必须直截了当地反对以色列占领并定居（加沙地带）行为，支持巴勒斯坦人民享有自由，平等及国家独立的权利，这些权利是不可剥夺的。</p>

<p>The president is unlikely to tack in either direction. If his previous statements are any guide, he will steer a middle path: affirming the unshakable bond between America and Israel, affirming the rights of Israelis and Palestinians to live in peace and security, pressuring both sides to recognise the rights and interests of the other, and gamely encouraging the parties to return to the table for peace talks.</p>

<p>But such platitudes are unlikely to bear much fruit, as my colleague pointed out a few weeks ago, and all the advice is merely a projection of different perspectives on the conflict. Mr Khalidi came close to admitting the limited role the American president can expect to play when he wrote that “peace has to be made between Palestinians and Israelis, not between Mr Obama and his critics”, but he still framed the question as “what should Barack Obama&hellip;do about the Israeli-Palestinian conflict?”</p>

<p>奥巴马不可能只走其中一条“路线”。如果推断他之前的讲话内容，可以看出他将会采取“中间路线”：强调美以两国牢不可破的关系，强调巴以两国人民有享有安定生活的权利，促使两国认可对方的权利及利益，鼓励两方重新进行和平谈话。我同事在几个星期之前指出这种陈词滥调不可能有太多的效果，所有的这些建议只不过是隐射奥巴马对巴以冲突问题的不同看法而已。当卡里迪写到：“巴以两国必须实现和平，而不仅仅是奥巴马和对其批判者之间的和平”，言外之意指美国总统希望能在巴以之间发挥有限的作用，但是卡里迪还是提出来了一个问题：奥巴马在巴以冲突中应该怎么做？</p>

<p>As we explained in last week&rsquo;s paper, one thing Mr Obama can do is tell both sides that two states is the only solution. But the administration is dampening already low expectations. The president has said that his primary goal on his tour of Ramallah, Tel Aviv and Jerusalem is simply “to listen”. An adviser has stated that the president will focus on &ldquo;the broader role of public opinion in peacemaking&rdquo;. As the the Los Angeles Times reports, Mr Obama has some work to do making friends with the Israeli public:</p>

<p>就如我们在上周报道中所解释的，奥巴马能做的一件事是：告诉双方，唯一的解决办法就是两国方案。巴以对和平谈判已不抱太大希望，但是美国政府的做法更是火上浇油，奥巴马说，这次拉姆安拉市，特拉维夫市及耶路撒冷之行的主要目的仅仅是为了“倾听”。一位顾问称：奥巴马此行主要是讨论公众舆论在和平问题上发挥的更大作用。据《洛杉矶时报》报道，奥巴马得下些功夫才能和以色列民众称兄道弟。</p>

<p>A poll published Friday in the Maariv newspaper found that 38% of Israelis defined Obama&rsquo;s attitude toward their country as &ldquo;hostile&rdquo; compared with 33% who found it &ldquo;favorable.&rdquo; More worrisome for Obama, only 10% of respondents said their opinion of the president was favorable, while the rest said their view was indifferent, unfavorable or even &ldquo;hateful.&rdquo; Other surveys have found more positive views, but Obama clearly does not enjoy the sort of demonstratively warm relationship with the Israeli public that his two predecessors had.</p>

<p>周五（以色列）《晚报》刊登的民意调查显示：38%的以色列人民认为奥巴马对以的采取敌对态度，而33%则觉得他的态度是友好的。让奥巴马更加郁闷的是，参与民意调查的人中，只有10%对奥巴马的评价不错，其他的人的态度则是冷淡，或是不喜欢，有人甚至讨厌。虽然其他的问卷调查显示出更多以色列人们对他的正面评价，但是，奥巴马明显没有像前两任总统那样享受这种与以色列人们之间的友好关系。</p>

<p>But charming average Israelis is at best a first, small step toward helping the two sides settle their differences. Even popular American presidents have had a very hard time brokering deals between Israelis and Palestinians. Just ask Bill Clinton, beloved by Israelis, who visited the region four times during his presidency, choreographed the historic handshake between Yitzhak Rabin and Yasser Arafat at the White House in 1993 and invested heart and soul into 14 days of Camp David talks in 2000. In his memoir, Mr Clinton summarised the final status agreement that wasn’t:</p>

<p>但是取悦每一个以色列人充其量是帮助巴以双方解决分歧的第一小步。可是受欢迎的美国总统们都难以帮助巴以两国达成一致协议。你可以问问深受以民喜欢的比尔•克林顿，他在就任总统期间四次出访以色列，1993年精心安排伊扎克•拉宾（注释3）与亚西尔•阿拉法特（注释4）的历史性会面，2000年全心投入历时14天的戴维营会谈（注释5）。克林顿在回忆录里总结这一最终没有达成协议的会谈：</p>

<p>I said these parameters were nonnegotiable and were the best I could do, and I wanted the parties to negotiate a final status agreement within them. After I left, Dennis Ross and other members of our team stayed behind to clarify any misunderstanding, but they refused to hear complaints. I knew the plan was tough for both parties, but it was time – past time – to put up or shut up. The Palestinians would give up the absolute right of return; they had always known they would have to, but they never wanted to admit it. The Israelis would give up East Jerusalem and parts of the Old City, but their religious and cultural sites would be preserved; it had been evident for some time that for peace to come, they would have to do that. The Israelis would also give up a little more of the West Bank and probably a larger land swap than Barak’s last best offer, but they would keep enough to hold at least 80 percent of the settlers. And they would get a formal end to the conflict. It was a hard deal, but if they wanted peace, I thought it was fair to both sides.</p>

<p>“我说，这些前提条件是不容商讨的，也是我能提供的最佳方案，我希望双方在此条件之内磋商并达成一个最终决议。我离开之后，丹尼斯•罗斯和其他成员留在那里澄清任何误解，但不愿倾听他们的抱怨。我知道双方都很难接受这个方案，但是时候做出最后的抉择了，不成功则成仁（其实时机早就过去了）。巴方必须放弃让以方归还全部土地的要求，他们早就知道必须放弃这一想法，但就是不愿承认。若以色列放弃东耶路撒冷及一部分部分耶路撒冷旧城，但是他们的宗教及文化遗址还是会保留下来，实现和平的时机已非常明显，他们必须去实现它。以色列也需要放弃约旦河西岸的一些土地，或许交换的土地要比巴拉克最后要求的还要多一些，但是他们能有足够的领土供80%以上的人居住。他们能正式的结束这一冲突。虽然这份协议很难达成，但如果他们都希望和平的话，我想这对双方都是公平的。</p>

<p>The big picture hasn’t changed much since 2000: the sticking points remain Jerusalem, land swaps and the Palestinian right of return. But some details make an agreement today even less likely. Binyamin Netanyahu and Mahmoud Abbas are constrained ideologically and practically in ways Mr Rabin and Mr Arafat were not: Bibi is no peacemaker, and the division of Palestinian leadership between Mr Abbas’s Fatah in the West Bank and the militant Hamas in Gaza makes it much harder for Mr Abbas to act. The number of Jewish settlers has more than doubled, multiplying facts on the ground and complicating any agreement on territory. Instability in Egypt, turmoil in Syria and the hostility of Iran pose immediate and near-term threats which overshadow the long-simmering, existential conundrum of the Palestinian question.</p>

<p>自2000年戴维营会谈结束后，巴以局势还是没有太大改观：症结仍然是耶路撒冷的归属，土地交换以及巴勒斯坦要求以方归还土地问题。但是现在双方已不太可能在一些细节问题上达成协议了。本亚明•内塔尼亚胡和穆罕默德•阿巴斯都受到意识形态以及现实状况的约束，而拉宾与阿拉法特没有受到这种约束的影响：《圣经》不是和事佬，巴勒斯坦领导层的两派纷争（阿巴斯在西约旦河的法塔赫势力与加沙地带的哈马斯（注释6）军事力量）让阿巴斯的和谈计划难上加难。犹太定居者的数量增加了一倍多，使得两国就领土达成协议复杂化。当前埃及社会不稳定，叙利亚局势动荡，伊朗的敌视态度对世界构成直接和暂时性威胁，这也冲淡了长期以来存在的巴勒斯坦问题。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1: 这是奥巴马就任总统以来首次访问以色列，也是他连任以来的首次出访。奥巴马只在2008年以总统竞选人的身份造访过该国。</p>

<p>注释2：珍妮弗•鲁宾（Jennifer Rubin）是《华盛顿邮报》博客作者，新保守主义作家珍妮弗•鲁宾在《华盛顿邮报》上的博客“向右转”（Right Turn）既有报道又有评论，她经常触及外交政策问题，只要博客上一有的新内容似乎就能成为新闻。在《评论》杂志上发表了引发热议的《犹太人为什么憎恨萨拉•佩林》等文章后，鲁宾的名字总是伴随着争议。</p>

<p>注释3：伊扎克•拉宾：以色列政治家、军事家。1974年至1977年出任以色列总理；1992年起再次出任总理，直至1995年被刺身亡。他是首位出生于以色列本土的总理，首位被刺杀和第二位在任期间辞世的总理。1994年10月14日，阿拉法特、佩雷斯、拉宾分享诺贝尔和平奖。</p>

<p>注释4：亚西尔•阿拉法特（1929年8月27日—2004年11月11日），全名拉赫曼•阿卜杜勒•拉乌夫•阿拉法特•古德瓦•侯赛尼，毕生致力于争取恢复巴勒斯坦人民合法民族权利的正义事业。1989年，当选巴勒斯坦国总统。自1993年起是巴勒斯坦当局的领导人、自1969年起任巴解组织主席及巴解组织最大派别法塔赫的领导人，1996年，巴勒斯坦民族权力机构成立后，阿拉法特任主席，是1994年诺贝尔和平奖的获得者之一。病逝于2004年，享年75岁。</p>

<p>注释5：戴维营会谈：美国，以色列和巴勒斯坦三国就巴以冲突进行的秘密会谈，历时21天。</p>

<p>注释6：哈马斯：由“伊斯兰”、 “抵抗”、“运动” 三个阿拉伯语缩写而成。哈马斯成立于1987年12月，创始人为谢赫•艾哈迈德•亚辛。集宗教性、政治性为一体的哈马斯主张用武力消灭巴土地上的犹太复国主义者，反对同以色列和平共处，主张建立一个以耶路撒冷为首都的独立的巴勒斯坦国。哈马斯拥有正式成员２万多人及下属军事组织。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pakistan & Iran: Gas, but Not the Useful Sort-“西气东输”非权宜之计]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/16/gas/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-16T20:42:13+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/16/gas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gas, but not the useful sort</strong><br/>
<strong>“西气东输”非权宜之计</strong></p>

<p>Barren ground for a new pipeline
在贫瘠的土地上修建一条新天然气管道</p>

<p>Mar 16th 2013 | ISLAMABAD |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130316_ASP002_0.jpg" alt="Pakistan &amp; Iran: Gas" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>IT WAS smiles and handshakes all round on Pakistan’s border with Iran, as the presidents of the two countries posed on March 11th to mark the start of the construction of the Pakistani part of a pipeline that is supposed to bring Iranian natural gas to a country starved of energy. Blackouts cripple industry and bring daily misery to Pakistani households. The new pipeline is supposed to be completed by the end of 2014.</p>

<p>3月11日，巴基斯坦和伊朗两国总统面带微笑，互相握手，在巴伊边境出席天然气管道项目巴方段（注释1）的奠基仪式，这条天然气管道计划将向巴提供伊朗天然气，以缓解能源不足危机。供电量不足（灯火管制）使巴基斯坦工业一蹶不振，人们每晚在黑暗中度日。该新管道预计在2014年底竣工。</p>

<p>Yet ending misery appears not to be among the chief political motives. Rather, Iran hopes that the project will lessen the country’s international isolation. Pakistan’s relations with its neighbour have usually been chilly. But under President Asif Ali Zardari, they have warmed. That is indicative of Pakistan’s tilt away from the United States, which lobbied the government in Islamabad against the deal and which has been pushing the idea of an alternative pipeline running from Turkmenistan, through war-ravaged Afghanistan, and then into Pakistan and India. Instead, Pakistan has also begun talks with Iran about an oil refinery at its Gulf port of Gwadar. Pakistan recently decided to hand control of the new deep-sea port there to the Chinese, another development that concerns the United States, not to mention India.</p>

<p>然而，结束巴基斯坦人民的这种困境并不是伊朗的主要政治目的，恰恰相反，伊朗希望这个项目能缓解本国的国际孤立状态。但巴总统扎尔达里加强与伊朗的关系，这也表明巴基斯坦与美国关系渐行渐远，美国反对巴基斯坦政府参与这一项目，并一直提出建设一条从土库曼斯坦出发，途径饱受战争蹂躏的阿富汗，最后到达巴基斯坦和印度的天然气管道。与此同时，巴基斯塔已开始与伊朗就在瓜达尔海湾港口建立一家炼油厂进行对话。巴基斯坦最近已决定把这个深海港口的控制权移交给中国，这一事态的发展是美国忧心忡忡，更不用说印度了。</p>

<p>The new pipeline comes from the giant South Pars gasfield and will snake into southern Pakistan. Iran has already built all but the final 320km (200 miles) of its bit of the pipeline, according to the deputy oil minister, Javad Owji. Now Pakistan has to build about 800km.</p>

<p>这条管道从（伊朗）南帕尔斯油气田进入巴基斯坦南部。伊朗石油部副部长贾瓦德•奥吉称，伊朗计划在伊方段铺设800公里管道，剩余320公里（200英里）已差不多完成。</p>

<p>That it has to pass through the insurgency-ridden province of Balochistan is only one cause for doubting its completion. It is also not clear how Pakistan, which is strapped for cash, will finance its part of the pipeline, especially if hit by international sanctions for dealing with Iran. What is more, this is the last week that the current government, led by Mr Zardari’s Pakistan Peoples Party, has in office. According to polls, the opposition party of Nawaz Sharif, who is close to Iran’s foe, Saudi Arabia, looks set to lead the next government after an election, likely in May.</p>

<p>这条管道必须经过暴乱频繁的巴基斯坦的俾路支省，这使得人们质疑管道能否顺利完成。由于资金缺乏，巴基斯坦能否提供巴方段管道建设的费用还是未知数，如果因与伊朗的合作而受到国际制裁，那就更不好说了。而且扎尔达里政府于上周完成（五年）任期。据民意调查显示，与伊朗宿敌沙特关系密切反对派纳瓦兹•谢里夫很可能在五月进行的总统大选后成为下一任政府领导人。</p>

<p>For five years, Mr Zardari’s administration has sat on the country’s energy crisis, with little action beyond get-rich-quick schemes for his cronies. The Iranian gas is not cheap. Exploiting Pakistan’s domestic reserves, which produce gas at about half the price, has been neglected. So, too, have imports of liquefied natural gas. Little has been done to deal with appalling inefficiencies in the country’s electricity system.</p>

<p>扎尔达里政府在这五年任期里对国家的能源危机坐视不理，没有付出什么行动，而是致力于为其亲信寻求一夜暴富的方法。伊朗石油价格不低，利用巴基斯坦的国内储备生产价格要低一半的石油并没有受到关注，所以进口液化天然气就更不用说了。该国的电力系统运作出奇的低效，政府也没有采取什么措施来解决这个问题。</p>

<p>But even though the announcement of the Iranian pipeline looks like a gimmick, the Americans’ idea of gas all the way from Turkmenistan is a pipe dream. Beleaguered Pakistanis have longer to wait before gas flows into homes, or blackouts are a thing of the past.</p>

<p>但是即便这次伊方管道项目的开工仪式看起来像一个小把戏，美国层想要建设一条从土库曼斯坦进入巴基斯坦的天然气管道，这想法已成白日梦了。在家家户户能够使用到天然气，或灯火管制成为过去式之前，困难重重的巴基斯坦还得需要等上一段很长的时间。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：3月11日，巴基斯坦和伊朗两国在边境举行的输气管道铺设的奠基仪式。伊朗已经完成了在本国境内的管道铺设，现在开始铺设的巴基斯坦段的总长为785公里。</p>

<p>注释2：巴基斯坦国民议会于2013年3月16日完成5年任期，现期满解散。巴基斯坦内阁也于同日解散。临时政府预计在未来几天内组建完成，新一轮大选将于5月举行。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[China's One-child Policy-中国的独生子女政策]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/one-child-policy/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:02:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/one-child-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>A low-fertility trap in China&rsquo;s largest city</strong><br/>
<strong>中国最大都市-上海陷入低生育率危机</strong></p>

<p>Mar 15th 2013, 12:41 by J.P</p>

<p><img src="http://images.qianlong.com/mmsource/imghylanda/20130311/29/14978900502636975149.jpg" alt="独生子女" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>THIS week The Economist looks at the backlash against the one-child policy in China. The article points out that the bureaucracy created to run the policy, the family-planning commission, has lost its separate identity and will be merged with the health ministry into a new Health and Family Planning Commission. Normally in China (as elsewhere) power and bureaucracy go together, so this loss of bureaucratic autonomy probably signals a loss of influence, and may presage scrapping the policy itself (though officials say that won’t happen).</p>

<p>《经济学家》了解下本周有关中国独生子女政策的反对呼声。这篇文章指出中国政府撤销曾经成立的计划生育委员会（负责实施计划生育政策），将其与国家卫生部的职责整合组建国家卫生和计划生育委员会。在中国（其他国家也一样），权利和国家政府一般是联系在一起的，因此这次官僚自主性（注释1）的缺失也许意味着政府影响力的下降，或许预示这项计划生育政策终会取消（虽然官方对此予以否认）。</p>

<p>But even if it does, how much difference would ending the one-child policy make? Our report focuses on Shanghai and, by chance, China’s biggest city has a great deal of evidence that bears on that question. Most of it suggests the answer is not much.</p>

<p>但就算是取消这项政策，又会有多大的影响呢？ 我们本次报道主要聚焦上海，碰巧这座中国最大的城市（上海）拥有关于这一问题的大量事实，且大部分证明：影响并不大。</p>

<p>Under the current policy, adults who were only children themselves are permitted to have two children. According to research by Stuart Basten of Oxford University*, that provision applies to 70% of the city’s couples. In other words, the weight of the one-child policy bears down relatively lightly on Shanghai. Even so, Shanghainese couples have extremely low fertility. The city’s total fertility rate—the number of children a woman can expect to have during her lifetime—was a mere 0.64 in 2002-03 (one of the lowest rates ever recorded in peacetime) before rising slightly to a still-low 0.89 in 2007. The Shanghainese are not having larger families even though they are allowed to.</p>

<p>当前的计划生育政策允许都是独生子女的成人生第二胎，牛津大学的斯图尔特-巴斯顿的研究显示，上海有70%的夫妇都享有这项规定，换句话说，独生子女政策对上海造成的压力相对比较少。即便是这样，沪籍夫妇的生育率相当的低。该城市的总生育率 — 每个妇女一生孕育的孩子—2002至2003年仅为0.64人（创和平时期以来的最低点），2007年生育率缓慢上升，为0.89人，但仍然很低。即便这一政策使上海人能抚养更多的小孩，但是他们都不想拥有大家庭。</p>

<p>The reason is that the one-child policy seems to have changed social norms. After two generations of growing up alone, people now expect to have only one child. In 2003 and 2008, the city’s family-planning bureaucrats (the Shanghai Municipal Population and Family Planning Commission) asked 38,000 men and women aged 20-45 about how many children they wanted. They found the average ideal family size was just 1.07, with 81% of respondents saying they wanted only one child and just 15% saying they wanted a second. Admittedly, not all the respondents would necessarily be allowed a second child, and some people may have been extremely cautious about replying to any questions from some of the feared and hated bureaucrats in China. All the same, the figure is strikingly low. It is also worth noting that the share of those saying they wanted no children doubled between the two surveys, though only to 8%.</p>

<p>原因在于独生子女政策似乎改变了社会规则。自两代人都是出生在独生子女家庭，他们都希望只生一个小孩。在2003年和2008年，上海计划生育机构（上海市人口和计划生育委员会）对38000位年龄在20-45岁的男女进行了问卷调查，即他们想要几个孩子。调查发现，他们理想中的家庭平均人口为1.07人，这些人中有81%称有一个孩子就够了，只有15%的人想要两个孩子。当然，他们并不是都能准许生第二胎，有些人可能在回答中国一些疑心重重及让人反感的官方机构提出的问题时表现得相当谨慎。不管怎么说，这数字出奇地低。值得注意的一点是，在这两次调查中发现，丁克族的比例翻了一倍（尽管只占8%）。</p>

<p>This does not mean the one-child policy has had no effect (though a few demographers do argue that). Nor does it mean the policy is alone responsible for changing social norms. The cost of educating children and the difficulty of finding accommodation big enough for a family with two children are also factors. But the one-child policy does seems to have forced desired family size down further and faster than would have happened without it. And now that expectations of a small family have taken root, they may well stay low, even if the policy that gave rise to them is scrapped.</p>

<p>这并不是说独生子女政策没有什么作用（尽管一些人口学家都认为影响力不大）。也不是意味着这项政策只是为了改变社会规则。子女受教育的费用以及很难找到供一家四口居住的房子也是其中的原因。但是独生子女政策似乎迫使家庭理想规模变小，并且这一变化速度快于没有政策的情况。因为现在“小型家庭”观念已深入人心，所以即便引发这一观念的政策被取消，这些观念还有可能保持低下。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：官僚自主性：是指官僚机构或个人超越其法定的地位和职能，超越政治家的控制，在公共决策过程中发挥主导作用的现象。官僚自主性现象由来以久，可以说它是伴随着政府的产生而产生，但在现代民主制建立之前，它合理而自在地存在着，而作为一个“问题”被提出在西方则是近一百多年的事，因其对政治与行政二分原则的背离而受到关注的，近几十年已发展成为所有现代政府面临的普遍而又难以克服的问题，并成为政治学研究的重点之一。政治学研究官僚自主性问题的主要动因在于揭示官僚制与民主政治之间的悖论问题，即官僚制因民主政治发展的需要而建立，但其发展本身实际上又损害着民主政治发展的基本原则。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[AIDS Research-艾滋病研究-不再闻“艾”色变]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/04/AIDS-research/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-04T13:32:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/04/AIDS-research</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cured of HIV?</strong><br/>
<strong>终结艾滋还远吗？</strong></p>

<p>Mar 4th 2013, 20:14 by G.C.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.wbrz.com/images/news/AIDSRESEARCH.jpg" alt="AIDS research" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>IN JOURNALISM, cynics suggest, three data points are enough to pronounce a trend. As of March 3rd, AIDS researchers hope that two might be sufficient. On that day Deborah Persaud of Johns Hopkins University announced to the Conference on Retroviruses and Opportunistic Infections in Atlanta, Georgia, that a patient under her care had been cured of HIV infection. The announcement was hedged in the usual caveats (“functionally cured” was the exact term used). But the bottom line was clear. Dr Persaud thinks her patient, a two-and-a-half-year-old girl whose identity is confidential, has joined Timothy Brown, a man known to many as the “Berlin patient”, as a human being who was once definitively infected with HIV and now no longer is.</p>

<p>在新闻界，愤世嫉俗者认为三个案例足以推断出一种趋势。自3月3日起，艾滋病研究人员则希望两个可能就足够了。在那一天，（美国）约翰霍普金斯大学的黛博拉•佩尔绍德在佐治亚州的亚特兰大召开的逆转录病毒和机会性感染会议上表示，她已治愈一位患有艾滋病毒的病人。这一消息也受到很多的质疑（确切的称“功能性治愈”）。但是情况很清楚。佩尔绍德博士认为她的病人（2岁半的女孩，具体身份未透露）和人称“柏林病人”蒂莫西•布朗[注释1]的病例相同，布朗曾确诊感染艾滋病毒，现已完全治愈。</p>

<p>The facts of the case that Dr Persaud was prepared to make public are limited (the patient is, after all, a child). But the pertinent point is that she was born infected because her mother was infected and was treated with standard anti-retroviral drugs almost immediately and for 18 months afterwards. She was then lost track of for five months. When the child returned to doctors’ attention, they found the virus had vanished—and six months later, despite the fact that the girl is no longer taking anti-AIDS medicine, there is no sign of HIV having returned in force.</p>

<p>佩尔绍德博士准备公之于众的案例是有局限性的（毕竟这仅是个孩子）。但是相关的内容是：因为小孩的妈妈感染了艾滋病毒，小孩在出生时被诊断出携带艾滋病毒，研究人员随即对其进行了18个月的标准性抗逆转录病毒治疗。此后五个月中止了治疗。当医生再次对该小孩进行检查时，发现她体内病毒已消失—6个月之后，虽然小女孩不用再服用抗艾滋病毒药物，但是她体内已没有艾滋病毒繁殖的迹象。</p>

<p>This is a result of great potential significance. Mr Brown’s cure was effected, accidentally, because his bone marrow (and thus the pertinent part of his immune system, which HIV infects) was destroyed and replaced during a course of treatment for leukaemia. That is hardly a viable approach for those who do not have that disease. But if HIV infection can be cured with drugs, as Dr Persaud’s observations suggest, a whole, new line of investigation opens up.</p>

<p>这一成功案例有潜在的重大意义。布朗先生的艾滋病意外地得到治愈，是因为在进行白血病治疗过程中，他的骨髓（以及受艾滋病感染的相关免疫系统部分）遭到破坏并得到移植。对于那些没有患白血病的艾滋病毒感染者来说，这不是一个可行的治愈方法。佩尔绍德博士的研究表明，如果药物能够治愈艾滋病患者，一项全新的调查研究即将开启。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：蒂莫西•布朗：当前定居柏林的美籍男子，十几年前患上艾滋病，几年前又被确诊为白血病。2007年，他在德国柏林大学夏里特医学院接受了造血干细胞移植，用以治疗白血病。经过骨髓移植后，原本几乎被判死刑的布朗奇迹般获得重生。经医学检测，布朗体内的艾滋病病毒消失，他由此成为世界首例被确认治愈的艾滋病患者。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aspiring Africa-有远大抱负的非洲]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/aspiring-africa/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T19:54:28+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/aspiring-africa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The world’s fastest-growing continent</strong><br/>
<strong>世界上发展最快的大陆</strong></p>

<p>Pride in Africa’s achievements should be coupled with the determination to make even faster progress</p>

<p>非洲取得成功获得的自豪感，应该和他们的决心结合起来获得更快的发展</p>

<p>Mar 2nd 2013 | From the print edition</p>

<!--more-->


<p>CELEBRATIONS are in order on the poorest continent. Never in the half-century since it won independence from the colonial powers has Africa been in such good shape. Its economy is flourishing. Most countries are at peace. Ever fewer children bear arms and record numbers go to school. Mobile phones are as ubiquitous as they are in India and, in the worst-affected countries, HIV infections have fallen by up to three-quarters. Life expectancy rose by a tenth in the past decade and foreign direct investment has tripled. Consumer spending will almost double in the next ten years; the number of countries with average incomes above $1,000 per person a year will grow from less than half of Africa’s 55 states to three-quarters.</p>

<p>这块世界上最为贫穷的大陆一片欣欣向荣。从殖民统治赢得独立后的半个世纪里，非洲从未有过这么好的局面。大部分非洲国家处于和平状态。携带武器的孩子越来越少，学生人数创历史新高。和印度一样，手机已屡见不鲜，在艾滋病毒最严重的国家，感染人数已减少了近3/4。人们的平均寿命在过去十年里增加了十分之一，外商直接投资额翻了三番。人们的消费在未来十年翻倍，在55个非洲国家中，人均年收入达一千美元的国家数量从原来的不足一半达到四分之三。</p>

<p>Africans deserve the credit. Western aid agencies, Chinese mining companies and UN peacekeepers have done their bit, but the continent’s main saviours are its own people. They are embracing modern technology, voting in ever more elections and pressing their leaders to do better. A sense of hope abounds. Africans rightly take pride in conferences packed with Western bankers keen to invest in their capital markets (see article). Within the next few months MasterCard will have issued South Africans with 10m debit cards. Even the continent’s politicians are doing a bit better, especially in economic management and striking peace deals. Average GDP growth is humming along, at about 6%. Governance is improving: our correspondent visited 23 countries to research this week’s special report and was not once asked for a bribe—inconceivable only ten years ago.</p>

<p>非洲人们当之无愧。西方援助机构，中国矿业公司以及联合国维和部队都尽全力帮助非洲，但是非洲人民才是这片大陆的主要救世主。他们学习现代技术，投票参与比以往更多的选举，望他们的领导者有更好的作为。每个人心中都充满了希望，非洲人民引以为自豪的是：参与会议的西方银行家热衷于投资非洲金融市场（详见文章）。在接下来的几个月里，万事达卡公司将向南非人民发行一千万张借记卡。连非洲政治家的处事能力也更加给力，特别是在经济管理和达成和平协议方面。年均国内生产总值也一路高歌，增长率约为6%。国家治理能力也在不断的改善：为了调查本周的特别报道，我们的记者在23个非洲国家进行了采访，但是并没有人要求受贿—这在十年前实属罕见。</p>

<p>This is a welcome transformation, but it is still incomplete. The danger is that Africa settles for today’s pace of change. Only if Africans raise their ambitions still further will they reach their full potential. They need to take on the difficult jobs of building infrastructure, rooting out corruption and clearing the tangle of government regulation that is still holding them back. And they should hurry.</p>

<p>这是一个可喜的变化，但是仍有待完善。非洲满足现在的转变步伐&ndash;这才是危险所在。只要非洲人民继续拥有雄心壮志，他们就能充分发挥自己的潜力。他们需要进行一些困难的工作，如基础设施建设，铲除腐败，清除仍然拖后腿的政府监管。他们应该抓紧时间。</p>

<p><strong>Don’t dawdle</strong><br/>
<strong>别游手好闲</strong></p>

<p>One reason is that so much more remains to be done. Poverty may have become less visible in Africa’s capitals but it remains widespread. The battle against hunger has not been won. The spread of wealth is uneven and winners from today’s boom all too often rush to fortify their gilded positions inside guarded compounds. The financiers who suggest that Africa could soon rival Asia have let their imaginations run riot. Whereas one is the workshop of the world, the other almost exclusively exports what grows in fields or is dug out from below them.</p>

<p>其中一个原因是：还有更多的事情有待完成。贫穷的情况在非洲国家的首都日益少见,但还是广泛存在。抗饥饿之路任道重远，财富分布不均，当今繁荣经济的受益者常常急于巩固他们在利益集团下“镀金地位”。那些认为非洲不久能与亚洲相抗衡的金融家已大肆吹嘘他们的幻想。然而，一个是世界工厂，一个却几乎只能出口土里长的或地下挖的原材料。</p>

<p>About a third of Africa’s GDP growth comes from commodities. This will not last. Today’s prices are near record highs and commodity markets have a habit of collapsing. Furthermore, recent gains in agricultural commodities may be undermined by climate change. Even now, savannahs are drying out, water tables are dropping and rains either failing or becoming more irregular. One in five Africans will be directly affected by 2020. Even as their continent prospers, many of them will continue to depend on agriculture and there is little they can do about the threats to the world’s environment.</p>

<p>大约三分之一的非洲国内生产总值增长率得益于商品。这种状况也不会持续太久。目前商品价格已近历史新高，商品市场定时陷入崩溃状态。而且，最近农产品的收益可能受到环境变化的影响。尽管这样，非洲热带大草原天气日益干燥，地下水位下降，降水要么趋少，要么不定时。2020年将有五分之一的非洲人直接受到影响。就算非洲大陆经济繁荣，许多人仍得继续依赖农业，对世界环境的威胁，他们已无能为力。</p>

<p>Another reason to push ahead is that Africa’s hard-won victories are vulnerable to relapses. Kenya is a model for other countries in east Africa but the campaign for elections on March 4th has been marred by violence (see article). New scourges—like Islamist extremism in the Sahara—could yet sow instability.</p>

<p>促进非洲发展的另一原因是：非洲来之不易的胜利随时都有溃败的危险。肯尼亚是其他东非国家的榜样，但是3月4号的总统竞选活动受到暴力事件的破坏（详见文章）。新的灾难—如撒哈拉地区的伊斯兰极端主义—可能已造成局势动荡。</p>

<p>And Africa must make the most of two transitions it is now going through. The move from the countryside to cities offers the chance of a one-off boost to productivity both on the farm and in the slums. If African states bungle this, they will create a dangerous unemployed urban class. At the same time, though Africa’s population is still growing rapidly—it will double to 2 billion by 2050—families there are becoming smaller. This promises a “demographic dividend”, as the number of workers relative to children and the elderly increases. The continent must make use of this bulge of labour, and the savings it produces, for development. If they squander it, Africans will grow old before they grow rich.</p>

<p>非洲必须充分利用正在经历的两个转变。农村到城市的人口流动为农场和贫民窟提供了一次性提高生产率的机会。如果非洲国家搞砸了话，就会形成城市失业族，数目惊人。与此同时，虽然非洲人口数量仍在继续增加—-到2050，人口将增加一倍至20亿—&ndash;家庭规模日趋变小。当劳动人口数量的增长率高于儿童和老年人口增长率，即为“人口红利（注释1）”。非洲必须利用好增长的劳动力以及创造的财富来取得发展。如果把这个都白白浪费的话，非洲人们就未富先老了。</p>

<p><strong>Break down your borders</strong><br/>
<strong>冲破边界</strong></p>

<p>Africa’s citizens are already striving to become more productive. Farmers have started using hand-held gadgets to gain access to weather reports. Slums too are teeming with technology. The internet is changing the way the continent does business. In Kenya a third of GDP flows through a mobile money-transfer system set up by a private telecoms company.</p>

<p>非洲人民已在不断的提高自己的劳动能力。农民开始利用小型手持工具获取天气预报。贫民窟的人们也都使用技术。互联网正在改变非洲经商的方式。在肯尼亚，三分之一的国内生产总值通过一家私营电信公司建立的移动转账系统进行资金流动。</p>

<p>But Africa’s entrepreneurs are often stymied by the state. The bottom third countries in the World Bank’s ease-of-business ranking are almost all in Africa. Their people could easily have better lives; abundant capital and technology offer big opportunities. The infrastructure is improving—only 5% of the 15,800 miles travelled for our special report was on unpaved roads—but the power grid is a disaster. On the whole, government officials should focus less on building things than getting out of the way. Useless regulations have created bottlenecks. East Africa’s main port in Mombasa is gummed up and land borders across the continent hold back lorries for days. Restrictions on employing migrants and on land ownership prevent businesses from expanding. Bureaucrats and customs officers inflate the cost of getting anything done. Shipping a car from China to Tanzania costs $4,000, but getting it from there to nearby Uganda can cost another $5,000.</p>

<p>但是非洲企业家创业经常受到国家的阻碍。在世界银行的商业环境宽松排行中，排名最后三分之一的国家几乎都是来自非洲。这些国家的人们能轻松的过上好的生活，雄厚的资本以及技术提供了许多巨大的机会。基础设施得到不断的改善—我们在这次特别报道之行中共行了15800英里，只有5%的路面是崎岖不平的—但是电网是一个问题。总的来说，政府官员应该把心思多放在解决问题上，而不是大兴国土建设。一些没有实际意义的调控措施形成了造成了的“瓶颈”。位于蒙巴萨岛的东非重要港口现是乱七八糟，运输车辆通过各国边界线时得耗些时日。对移民雇员以及土地所有权的限制使商业很难开展起来。政府官员及海关人员常使人们办事的成本增加。从中国海运一辆汽车至坦桑尼亚需花费4000美元，但是从坦桑尼亚到附近的乌干达有得花费5000美元。</p>

<p>If aspiring Africa wants a new dream, it should be creating a common market from the Med to the Cape. That would be a boon to trade, enterprise and manufacturing: it would also get rid of much of the petty corruption and save lives. A recent World Bank report pointed out that Africa could produce enough food to feed itself; alas, too few subsistence farmers get a chance to sell their produce (and usually get less than 20% of the market price). Why not rekindle pan-Africanism by opening borders drawn in London and Paris? Africa needs a reborn liberation movement—except this time the aim is to free Africans from civil servants rather than colonial masters.</p>

<p>如果有抱负的非洲想要一个新的未来，它应该建立一个囊括地中海至开普敦区域的共同市场。这将给贸易，企业以及制造业带来福音，剔除许多轻微的腐败行为以及拯救生命。世界银行最近发布的报道指出，非洲的粮食已实现自给自足。可是，很少有生计农民能够卖出自己的农产品（产品价格常常低于20%的市场价格）。为什么不开放与英国和法国交界的边境来重燃泛非主义（注释2）呢？非洲需要进行一场解放运动来获得重生，但是这次目标将非洲人民从国家官员而非殖民者统治者桎梏中解放出来。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：人口红利：是指一个国家的劳动年龄人口占总人口比重较大，抚养率比较低，为经经济发展创造了有利的人口条件，整个国家的经济成高储蓄、高投资和高增长的局面。</p>

<p>注释2：泛非主义：是全世界黑种人反对种族歧视和殖民统治的一个声势浩大的民族主义思潮。早在帝国主义忙于重新瓜分殖民地的同时，受民族自决口号影响的泛非主义思潮及其表现形式泛非运动就已兴起，其领袖是美国黑人学者杜波依斯。首次泛非大会于1900年在伦敦举行，至1974年第六届达累斯萨拉姆大会，先后召开六次大会，影响遍及非洲，加勒比，欧洲和美洲。泛非主义不但强调民族解放，也强调世界上无论哪里的非洲人后裔，都有共同的利害关系并需要互助合作。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Corporate Governance in Hong Kong-香港的公司治理]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/corporate-governance-in-hk/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-02T15:20:23+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/02/corporate-governance-in-hk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Of privacy and opacity</strong><br/>
<strong>隐私与不透明</strong></p>

<p>Hong Kong is making its financial markets less transparent</p>

<p>香港金融市场越发不透明</p>

<p>Mar 2nd 2013 | SHANGHAI |From the print edition
“HONG KONG residents shall have freedom of speech, of the press and of publication.” So begins Article 27 of Hong Kong’s Basic Law. Those rights, ever delicate, are under attack. Just as troubling, so too is Hong Kong’s reputation as Asia’s most transparent financial market.</p>

<p>香港特区《基本法》第二十七条：“香港居民享有言论和新闻出版自由”。这些曾为美好的权利如今受到侵犯。同样让人感到不安的是，就连亚洲最为透明的金融市场-香港现也受到挑战。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>As part of its effort to modernise the city’s corporate rule book, the government proposed last year that full Hong Kong identity-card (HKID) numbers and home addresses no longer be required of directors. The idea attracted little attention at first. But in recent weeks several Chinese corruption scandals have been exposed by newspapers relying on analysis of such data (mainlanders with ill-gotten gains often stash them in Hong Kong). That has led to a row over the trade-off between directors’ privacy and the public good.</p>

<p>为了让香港的企业规则现代化，去年，香港政府提出企业管理者不再需要提供香港身份证号码以及住址，这一想法刚开始并没有引起很多人的注意。但是在最近几周，新闻界根据资料分析（拥有不义之财的大陆人常把非法财产转移到香港）披露了中国的一些腐败丑闻。公司管理者的隐私和公众利益之间的利益权衡弄得满城风雨。</p>

<p>Many agree that home addresses need not be divulged: in Britain, for example, directors may provide a business address. But a surprising coalition now argues that the government must not obscure directors’ identity numbers. Since many local names are similar, the HKID serves as the only practical unique identifier available. Hiding several digits, as the government proposes, would make it hard to cross-reference databases to see executives’ cross-holdings or conflicts of interest.</p>

<p>很多人都认同家庭住址不应该泄露：例如，英国的企业管理者也许提供一个公司地址。但是让人惊讶的是，很多人一致觉得政府不得掩盖企业管理者的身份证号码。因为当地许多名字都差不多，香港特区的身份证是唯一实际可用的标识符。如果照政府提出的隐掉几位身份证号码的做法，交叉引用数据库很难了解到企业管理者的交叉持股信息或者利益纠纷。</p>

<p>Lee Chuek-yan, a trade-union leader and opposition legislator, cites examples of workers, who have been denied back pay by bosses professing bankruptcy, using identity numbers to track down other flourishing businesses owned by those same employers. Danny Lau of the Hong Kong Small and Medium Enterprises Association thinks only tycoons benefit from such secrecy: ordinary business people “benefit from more information because that means more trust”. Steve Vickers, a former senior police investigator, argues the reforms will make life easier for money-launderers and crooks.</p>

<p>工会领导人兼反对派立法者李卓人引用了工人的例子，一些公司老板自称破产而拒付拖欠工资，工人们利用这些老板的身份证号码查到他们拥有效益不错的公司。香港中小型企业联合会（主席）刘认为，企业大亨才是这种隐私特权的利益既得者：一般的商人从更多的信息中受益，因为这意味着公司更值得信赖。前姿势警方调查人员史蒂芬威克斯称，这些政策让洗钱者和诈骗者变得更加嚣张。</p>

<p>Conspiracy theorists have wondered if officials in Beijing, humiliated by exposés of corruption in the New York Times and elsewhere, have been putting the squeeze on Hong Kong’s government. In fact, these reforms were proposed before the recent scandals. Legitimate data-privacy issues arise, too. But the government has thrown away its chance of a fair hearing by attacking David Webb, a respected activist investor and online commentator.</p>

<p>阴谋论者怀疑，北京官员因纽约时报及其他国外新闻媒体曝光了其腐败事迹而蒙羞，于是向香港政府施加压力。事实上，这些改革政策在最近的丑闻曝光之前已被提出，隐私信息的立法提案也不断的发生。但是政府为了抵制魏大卫（一位德高望重的激进投资者兼网络评论者）取消了一场公平的听证会。</p>

<p>Troubled by the proposed reforms, Mr Webb published the sensitive directors’ data—all collated from public sources—on one convenient web page. Trouble came when the official privacy commissioner launched a “compliance check” on his publication, warning darkly that “misuse of personal data contained in public registers may be a contravention” of the data-privacy law. Mr Webb argues he is protected by Article 27; media outlets have rallied to his cause. But the legal cloud has forced him to take that page off his website.
Mr Lee’s party will meet the government this month to try to halt the reforms, but his block lacks the votes to force a change. Jill Wong of King &amp; Wood Mallesons, a law firm, believes directors should be held to a higher standard than ordinary citizens but reckons the reforms are “likely to go through”. If so, Hong Kong will have scored an own goal.</p>

<p>因反感那些改革措施，魏大卫从公共资源上整理出企业管理者的敏感信息并刊登在一个便捷网站。他随后惹祸上身，政府保密委员对他刊登的内容进行一致性审查，并隐晦地警告：滥用公共注册中的个人身份证号码属于违法行为。魏称他的行为受到（香港基本法）第二十七条法律的保护，各界媒体也纷纷支持他的做法。但是迫于政府压力，他不得不删帖。李将在这个月于香港政府进行会谈，试图阻止这些改革措施，但是他的阵营获得支持不多而无能为力，“金杜万盛国际”律师事务所认为，企业管理者的标准应该比普通市民更高，但估计这项改革提案“通过的可能性很大”。如果真是这样的话，那香港真为自己摆了一道乌龙。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Groupon Fires Its boss-Groupon炒了它的老板！]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/01/groupon-fires-its-boss/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-01T12:37:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/01/groupon-fires-its-boss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Discounted out</strong><br/>
<strong>团购网站遭遇瓶颈</strong></p>

<p>Mar 1st 2013, 5:07 by M.G. | SAN FRANCISCO</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/03/blogs/schumpeter/20130302_wbp504.jpg" alt="ANDREW MASON" /></p>

<p>ANDREW MASON (pictured), who was ousted on February 28th as the chief executive of Groupon, the online-coupon company he co-founded, was refreshingly blunt about his fate. Not for him the typical corporate clap-trap about this being the right time to seek a new challenge and to contemplate the future of the cosmos. Here’s an excerpt from his resignation memo:</p>

<p>2月28日，在线团购公司Groupon解雇了其首席执行官兼创始人安德鲁•梅森（如图），他本人直言不讳的简述了这一变数。不仅仅是他，外界舆论也随声附和地认为，这是他寻求新挑战及未来方向的最佳时期。以下是摘自安德鲁辞职声明中的一段话：</p>

<!--more-->


<p>“After four and a half intense and wonderful years as CEO of Groupon, I’ve decided that I’d like to spend more time with my family. Just kidding—I was fired today. If you’re wondering why…you haven’t been paying attention. From controversial metrics in our S1 [a securities filing] to our material weakness to two quarters of missing our own expectations and a stock price that’s hovering around one quarter of our listing price, the events of the last year and a half speak for themselves. As CEO, I am accountable.”</p>

<p>“作为首席执行官，我在Groupon经历了忙碌又精彩的四年半时光，现决定花更多的时间和家人在一起。这只是开个玩笑-我今天被解雇了。如果你想知道原因，那说明你一直都没留意过这个问题。从S1文件中备受争议的业绩指标，到两个季度业绩均未能达到公司自己的预期，再到徘徊在上市价格四分之一上下的股价，过去一年半中的所有事情都说明了一切。作为CEO，我应对此负责。”</p>

<p>Bravo, Mr Mason. Schumpeter salutes you for your honesty, your sense of humour and your desire to “give Groupon a relief valve from the public noise” surrounding your leadership of the company. The only snag is that Groupon is unlikely to get much of a break while it hunts for a new chief executive. (In the interim, it will be run by Eric Lefkofsky and Ted Leonsis, two of its board directors.)</p>

<p>梅森，你说得不错。熊彼特对你的诚实，你的幽默感，以及你的希望（外界对你领导能力的质疑使Groupon有一个喘息时间）都肃然起敬。唯一的困难是，Groupon在寻觅新一任执行官的时候，不大可能有太多的喘息机会。（在这期间由两位董事长埃里克•莱夫科夫斯基和副董事长泰德•莱昂西斯暂时担任执行官）</p>

<p>The online-coupon business has become ferociously competitive and people are becoming more picky when it comes to choosing from among the vast number of deals for spa treatments, haircuts and other things that are now available on the internet. The day before Mr Mason’s defenestration, Groupon revealed that it had made an operating loss in its latest financial quarter and its shares fell to $4.44 each in after-hours trading. The firm’s market capitalisation has plummeted from around $13 billion at its flotation in 2011 to around $3 billion today.</p>

<p>在线团购业务的竞争非常激烈，当人们在如养生，美发及其他网购服务上有更多的选择机会时，变得越来越挑剔。在梅森遭解雇的前一天，Groupon公司透露了最近一个季度的运营亏损，以及股票价格在盘后交易中降至4.44美元。公司的市值从2011年上市约130亿美元猛降到现在的30亿美元左右。</p>

<p>Groupon did create a new market, but it now faces plenty of copycats such as LivingSocial and has seen behemoths such as Google wade into the business too. Known for “exploding” offers that expired after a short period of time, the firm has been shifting steadily towards deals that stay valid for longer. And it has been building a new business line called Groupon Goods, which sells things such as watches and nail polish at discounted prices.</p>

<p>Groupon的确是创造了一个新的市场，但是现在它面对许多如“社会生活”（美国第二大团购网站）的“山寨”公司的竞争，如今像谷歌这样的大公司也涉足这一行业。众所周知，Groupon公司提供限时的大幅折扣产品，现已稳步趋向建立长期有效的交易关系。该公司现正在建立一个名为“Groupon产品”的新业务部门，以折后价售卖产品，如手表，指甲油。</p>

<p>Diversifying revenue streams makes sense. But in choosing to sell discounted goods, Groupon has plunged into another area that is intensely competitive. The company has also allowed its costs to balloon, particularly in its international operations. It will need to slash these without damaging growth, which will require a tricky balancing act. The firm’s international revenues fell 16% in its latest quarter.</p>

<p>收益来源多样化是权宜之计。但是在决定售卖折扣商品时，意味着Groupon公司迅速进入另外一个竞争激烈的领域，同时也得容许扩大成本，特别是在国际业务上的成本。公司需要削减成本而不阻碍经济增长，这一点需要仔细平衡协调。该公司的国际收益在最新季度中下降16%。</p>

<p>In his farewell missive, Mr Mason said his departure would give Groupon “some breathing room to break bad habits”. Perhaps it will, but curing them will not solve Groupon&rsquo;s biggest problem, which is that the underlying economics of its business model have always appeared shaky. The firm&rsquo;s share price may rise in coming weeks on hopes that a new leader can turn it around, but in the long term its stock is unlikely to be a good deal.</p>

<p>在他的辞职公开信中，梅森说，他的离开会使Groupon有喘息的机会来纠正旧习。也许会，但是这样做并不会解决Groupon的最大问题，即这种基本的商业模式经济一直都不太稳定。如果新任执行官能使公司经济好转，股价也许会在未来几个星期里回升，但是从长期来看，股价不可能有太多的增长。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[China's Poor-中国贫穷之我见]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/27/china-pool/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-27T16:29:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/27/china-pool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>World-class poverty</strong><br/>
<strong>世界级贫困</strong></p>

<p>Feb 27th 2013, 9:35 by S.C. | HONG KONG</p>

<p><img src="http://www.jydoc.com/uploads/jydoc/p35001/20091300127500778013.jpg" alt="贫穷山村的孩子" /></p>

<p>WHEN is 6.3 yuan worth more than $1.25? If you can answer that riddle, you can avoid widespread confusion about China&rsquo;s poverty line. You can also appreciate a rare example of China&rsquo;s government being treated unfairly by its own mouthpiece, Xinhua.</p>

<p>6.3元人民币什么时候比1.25美元更值钱？如果你能回答这一谜题，你就不会对中国的贫困线困惑不解，你也可以欣赏难得的一次中国政府受到其喉舌-新华社的不公平对待。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>China&rsquo;s poverty line is set at 6.3 yuan a day. Yesterday the State Council announced that 98.99m rural folk (or 10.2% of the total) fell below that line in 2012. That was 23.39m fewer than the year before, a remarkable rate of progress.</p>

<p>中国贫困线定为每天6.3元的生活标准。国务院昨天称，2012年中国有9899万(占全国人口的10.2%)农村人口的生活标准低于贫困线，同比上一年减少2339万人，这是一个显著的进步。</p>

<p>But in reporting this good news, Xinhua, the official news agency, felt compelled to point out that China&rsquo;s poverty line of 6.3 yuan a day was unusually stingy by world standards:
But the current poverty line, which is equivalent to just 1 U.S. dollars a day, is still lower than the World Bank poverty line of 1.25 U.S. dollars a day.</p>

<p>但是官方新闻机构-新华社在报道这则好消息时不得不指出：与世界标准相比，中国每天6.3元的贫困线标准显得异常的低。目前相当于每天1美元的贫困线标准依然低于世界银行所定的每天1.25美元的贫困线标准。</p>

<p>Here Xinhua is being unfair. Even though 6.3 yuan is now worth only $1 on the foreign-exchange markets, China&rsquo;s poverty line is in fact considerably higher than the World Bank&rsquo;s standard. A detailed explanation of this paradox can be found in this post on Free exchange, where the real nerds reside. A simpler version follows.
Prices differ a lot over time and between places. For example, 6.3 yuan stretches much further in rural China, where things are cheap, than $1 stretches in America. By the same token, 6.3 yuan stretched further in 2010 than it does today, because inflation has taken a bite out of the yuan&rsquo;s value in the past couple of years.</p>

<p>新华社的说法并不公平。尽管现在6.3元在外汇市场上的市值仅值一美元，事实上，中国的贫困线要比世界银行所定的标准高出许多。这似非而是的观点在“自由外汇专题（经济板块）”刊登的内容上有详细的解释，该专题也不乏那些在细节上“穷追死揪”之人。其简要观点如下：价格随时间和地区的不同而变化幅度很大。例如，6.3元在物价低廉的中国农村要比1美元在美国值钱得多。同样地，6.3元在2010年要比现在值钱，因为过去几年的通货膨胀使得人民币贬值了。</p>

<p>To correct for these price differences, the World Bank&rsquo;s poverty line is designed to hold purchasing power constant across space and time. It reflects what $1.25 could buy in one place (America) at one time (2005). According to the Bank, therefore, you are poor if you consume less than what $1.25 could have bought in America eight years ago.</p>

<p>为了校正这种价格差异，世界银行的贫困线标准旨在体现不随时间和地理位置变化的购买力。它反映出1.25美元在某时（2005年）某地（美国）的购买力。根据世界银行的标准，如果你每天消费的东西少于八年前在美国用1.25美元能够买到的东西，说明你是穷人。</p>

<p>According to China&rsquo;s poverty line, by contrast, you are poor if you earn less than what 6.3 yuan could have purchased in rural China in 2010. It turns out that 6.3 yuan spent in that part of China at that time could buy about as much as $1.83 in America in 2005. Therefore China&rsquo;s poverty line is significantly more generous than the World Bank&rsquo;s standard. And Xinhua could, in this rare instance, be a little more generous to its government.</p>

<p>相比之下，按照中国的贫困线标准，如果你的日收入低于2010年6.3元在中国农村的购买力水平，那就算贫穷。因此，2010年6.3元在中国农村购买力与2005年1.83美元在美国的购买力相当。因此中国的贫困线标准远高于世界银行的标准。新华社本可以在这难得的一次中对其政府更有雅量一些。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Specially Forced Out-驻阿美军被驱逐出局]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/26/specially-forced-out/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T20:33:16+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/26/specially-forced-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Americans in Afghanistan:Specially forced out</strong><br/>
<strong>驻留阿富汗的美军：被驱逐出局</strong></p>

<p>Feb 26th 2013, 12:03 by B.F. | KABUL</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/02/blogs/banyan/wardak_000_hkg2003082054954_595.jpg" alt="驻留阿富汗的美军" /></p>

<p>BY EXPELLING American special forces from an embattled province, Afghanistan’s government has thrown the NATO coalition into confusion. It has also turned attention to these elite but shadowy troops. Afghanistan’s national security council have given the forces two weeks to leave Wardak province, after accusing them of complicity in murders and disappearances.</p>

<p>阿富汗政府下令驱逐驻扎在一个四面楚歌之省的美国特种部队，北约联盟对此惶恐不安，阿富汗政府也将注意力转移到这些地下精英部队。自美军被指控在当地共谋实施谋杀和屠杀后，阿富汗国家安全委员会要求美军在两周内撤离瓦尔达克省。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The crimes were blamed directly on Afghan irregulars who had been recruited to work alongside the Americans, and Hamid Karzai’s government has made it clear that it holds America responsible. Residents of Wardak had long complained of the irregulars’ abuses, according to the statement from the president’s office. The government says it is taking action only after the coalition failed to do so itself.</p>

<p>这些罪行直接指向阿富汗的非常规士兵，阿富汗政府招募他们协助美国士兵实行任务的，哈米德•卡尔扎伊政府明确表示美国政府对此事负有责任。据阿总统发表的声明，瓦尔达克的居民一直以来抗议非常规军的暴行。阿富汗政府称，如果北约不能解决这一问题的话，将会采取行动。</p>

<p>The order was announced at a hastily convened press conference on February 24th and appears to have wrong-footed the coalition. Two days later the confusion persists. Officials in NATO’s headquarters in Kabul said it is unclear who stands accused of what. A joint commission of senior Afghan and NATO staff has been appointed to travel to Wardak, south-west of the capital, in order to clarify the situation. NATO officials said they didn’t want to dismiss the Afghan concerns, but they also stressed that a review had already confirmed that “no coalition forces have been involved in the alleged misconduct”.</p>

<p>这一命令于2月24日紧急召开的新闻发布会上下达的，北约联盟似乎对此慌了手脚。两天之后，北约还没有找到应对的方法。驻喀布尔的北约总部官员称，尚不清楚谁该受到什么样的指控。现已委派一支由阿富汗和北约高级官员组成的联合委员会前往首都西南面的瓦尔达克查明真相。北约官员说，他们不会对阿富汗人们的担忧置之不理，而且他们也强调，报告中已确认北约士兵没有涉嫌这些不端行为。</p>

<p>The manoeuvre against the special forces brings Mr Karzai into confrontation with a principal element in the coalition’s strategy. These forces are increasingly the only ones to play a lead role in combat with the Taliban; other units are being shifted into backseat roles, training and advising Afghan troops. Raids carried out by special-forces troops have been credited by both NATO and Afghan commanders with seriously weakening the Taliban’s control over territory. They are also being used to train the tens of thousands of civilians who are supposed to join the Afghan Local Police (ALP), a village-based defence force which has become a central plank in the effort to shore up security in rural areas. However many (or few) troops remain in Afghanistan after 2014, their commanders are expected to want plenty of special forces.</p>

<p>下令驱逐特种部队这一策略使卡扎布尔质疑北约联盟驻阿的主要目的。美军特种部队在对抗塔利班中有着与日俱增的唯一主导作用，其他的作战部队转而成为辅助作用，训练和指导阿富汗士兵。北约和阿富汗指挥官都认为特种部队实施的突袭行动大大的削弱了塔利班的领土控制力。他们也常常训练数以万计希望成为阿富汗当地警察（乡级防御部队）的平民百姓，该部队已成为加强农村地区安全的核心力量。然而2014年后，仍有很多（或者少数）美军驻留阿富汗，阿的指挥官希望大量特种部队在阿富汗驻留。</p>

<p>Yet both the special forces’ raids and the notion having militiamen recruited at the local level have always sat uneasily with Mr Karzai. It was only after much arm-twisting that he was persuaded to take up the ALP at all. In particular he has railed against the night raids, which are hugely unpopular among his Pushtun constituency. As the deadline for Mr Karzai’s government to assume responsibility for security draws near, he has become keener to exert Afghanistan’s sovereignty and to dictate what NATO can and cannot do in the provinces.</p>

<p>然而，卡尔扎布一直都不太接受特种部队的突袭行动和招募当地民兵的想法(注释1)。只有在经受外部施加的压力后，他才同意成立“阿富汗当地警察”小组。他特别谴责夜间突袭行动，支持他的普什图选区人们对夜袭非常的反感。当阿富汗政府承担安全责任的最后期限临近，卡尔扎布致力叫嚣行使阿富汗主权，规定北约在瓦尔达克能做和不能做什么。</p>

<p>What rankles the government about the allegations in Wardak is the notion that the Americans would be engaging unaccountable Afghan nationals to do their dirty work. In this he may glean the prospect of a future insult to the country’s sovereignty. Such proxy forces have long existed in Afghanistan and date from the earliest stages of the American war, when bags of dollars where handed to local strongmen to buy the loyalty and use of their militiamen. At the time, unsavoury behaviour was overlooked in return for hostility towards the Taliban. Such groups were sometimes forged into semi-formal paramilitary forces, to act as protection and added muscle. Both special-forces units and the Central Intelligence Agency have murky histories with this sort of local groups. The most notorious, the Kandahar Strike Force, as well as other groups active in Afghanistan’s south-east, were accused of murders. Locals felt they had been granted impunity because of their links with the Americans.</p>

<p>关于瓦尔达克的指控，阿富汗政府难以释怀的是：美军与道德败坏的阿富汗人一起做的卑鄙勾当。再这样下去，他将来也许会在国家主权上添加不光彩的一笔。这一代理部队长期驻军在阿富汗，可以追溯到美国战争初期，那时候用大量钱财收买和利用当地独裁者的民兵，当时对这一丑恶之举的审查使人们仇视塔利班。有时候，这种民兵组织会“伪装”成半正式的预备部队，进行防卫和增加作战能力。特种部队和中央情报局同这种当地部队有过不光彩的勾当。最臭名昭著的是，坎大哈突击队和活跃在阿富汗东南部的其他民兵组织被指控涉嫌谋杀。当地居民觉得，因为和美国的关系，他们已免受惩罚。</p>

<p>Who stands accused of the crimes in Wardak, and indeed even whether there are such American-backed groups there at all, are the questions central to the current confusion. “I genuinely don’t know who is operating there,” said one NATO official. The picture is further muddied because the main highway that runs through Wardak, the Kabul-to-Kandahar, is partly secured by another armed force of Afghans which is known to be working for private-security companies. And the NATO officials are quick to point out that the Taliban conjured similar allegations in the past, as propaganda. Whatever crimes were or weren’t committed in Wardak, Mr Karzai’s government blames the Americans for creating “parallel groups and structures” of Afghan forces outside the control of the government.</p>

<p>谁为瓦尔达克发生的罪行受指控和甚至是否存在美国幕后支持的民兵组织是关系当前混乱局势的问题。一位北约官员说，“我确实不知道这个地区是谁在执行任务。”这张图片十分模糊，这条穿越瓦尔达克，喀布尔至坎大哈的公路主干线有一部分是由另一支阿富汗武装部队防卫的，众所周知，这支部队是为私人保安公司效力的。北约官员迅速指出，以前塔利班提出相似的指控来虚张声势。不管瓦尔达克发生犯罪行为与否，卡尔扎布政府都会谴责美军在本国政府控制范围之外成立相似的阿富汗民兵组织和结构。</p>

<p>Local leaders from Wardak say they are adamant the abuses happened, but that they have little idea who the culprits are. “They are Afghans working with the Americans,” said Abdul Qadir Hotak, who lives in Wardak’s Jalrez district. “Sometimes they are wearing uniform and sometimes they are in local dress. They are not in the Afghan National Army though.”</p>

<p>瓦尔达克的当地领导人表示，他们坚信当地发生了暴行，但是关于谁是罪魁祸首却知之甚少。住在瓦尔达克Jalrez区的阿卜杜勒卡迪尔说，“他们是为美军跑腿的阿富汗人，他们有时候穿着制服，有时候身着便装。但是他们不是阿富汗国防军。”</p>

<p>All this comes at a time when America is labouring through lengthy negotiations with Mr Karzai over an agreement about the role and status of the American troops who linger past 2014. The announcement about the special forces in Wardak may not be unrelated. In earlier rounds of negotiation the NATO side have sometimes surprised observers by their willingness to hand authority back to Kabul; they have often backed down on points which had seemed non-negotiable only a couple of years ago. Mr Karzai may now be pressing them to make similar choices about the use of special forces.</p>

<p>此时恰逢美国与卡尔扎布就2014年后驻留阿富汗的美军所扮演的角色及地位的协议正进行漫长的谈判。撤离瓦尔达克美国特种部队的命令也许与之没有联系。在前几轮谈判中，北约心甘情愿将职权转移到喀布尔，这让观察员感到很意外，他们也常常在前几年看起来似乎无法进行谈判的观点上步步退让。卡尔扎布也许会就特种部队使用上促使他们做出相似的选择。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：sit with 有两种意思：
    a: 帮助，照顾：
    b: [用于否定句和疑问句]为…所接受；对…产生影响</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social-impact Bonds-社会效益债券]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/social-impact-bonds/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T19:40:16+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/social-impact-bonds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Commerce and conscience</strong><br/>
<strong>商业与良知</strong></p>

<p>A new way of financing public services gains momentum<br/>
一种公共服务融资方法取得很大发展</p>

<p>Feb 23rd 2013 |From the print edition</p>

<!--more-->


<p>AT HALF past six on a wet morning in central London, the city is already busy. Baristas are setting up inside coffee shops. Office cleaners are at work. And outreach teams from charities and local councils are on early-morning shifts to find rough sleepers and get them off the streets.</p>

<p>早上六点半，烟雨笼罩的伦敦市中心已开始熙熙攘攘，人们已忙碌起来。咖啡师在咖啡厅着手准备营业，办公室的清洁员打扫卫生，慈善外展队和市政委员会进行早班执勤，寻找露宿人员，并将其带离街道。</p>

<p>For most teams the priority is to find people who are newly homeless and help find them accommodation quickly, before they become settled in a pattern. Kath Sims, an outreach worker for a homelessness charity called St Mungo’s, is not looking for the new arrivals, however. She is trying to locate people in a specific group of 415 habitual rough sleepers, with the aim of prising them from the streets.</p>

<p>对于大多数外战队来说，最重要的是找到无家可归的人们，在他们习惯这种居无定所的生活模式之前，尽快帮助他们安顿下来。Kath Sims是（伦敦）无家可归者慈善组织“圣芒戈魔法”的一名外展工作者，她并没有寻找新的露宿者，而是试图找到415名当地习惯性露宿者形成的一个特殊群，让他们不再流浪街头。</p>

<p>That puts her at the front line of a big financial experiment, too. Her work is being funded by an instrument called a “social-impact bond” (SIB), which promises returns to private investors if social objectives are met. The bond raised £5m ($8m) from investors, to be shared between St Mungo’s and another organisation called Thames Reach (responsible for another 400-or-so homeless people).</p>

<p>这也使她站在一项大型金融试验的最前线，她所进行的工作得到了一家名为“社会效益债券”机构的赞助，该机构承诺，如果达到社会目标，个人投资者将会获得回报。这家债券机构从投资者融资5百万英镑（约8百万美元），为 “圣芒戈魔法”和另一家名为“泰晤士关爱”（负责400人左右的无家可归者）共享用。</p>

<p>The cash will fund a three-year programme, the success of which is measured by everything from the number of nights that the rough sleepers spend on the streets to their visits to hospital. As targets are met, payments will flow to investors from the Greater London Authority (GLA), the SIB’s commissioning body.</p>

<p>这些钱能资助一个为期3年的计划项目，其成功与否取决于露宿者晚上留宿街头的天数及去医院就诊的次数。如果达到预期的目标，“社会效益债券”机构的委托方即伦敦政府将会付款给投资者。</p>

<p>The arrangement suits all parties. The rough sleepers are frequent users of government services, including accident-and-emergency wards. Cutting their number should save the GLA enough money to fund payments to investors if goals are met. At a time when public spending is under pressure, the taxpayer stumps up only if results are achieved. Investors have the prospect of a return to entice them, of up to 6.5% if targets are met.</p>

<p>这一安排适用所有机构。露宿者是政府公共服务（包括事故急诊室）的“频繁用户”。如果达到目标，露宿者人数的减少是英国政府有足够的资金支付投资者。当公共支出面临不足之时，纳税人只要在目标实现的前提下进行纳税。投资者们有望得到收益回报来吸引纳税人的资金，如果目标实现的话，收益回报可能会高达6.5%。</p>

<p>As for organisations like St Mungo’s, they get upfront funding for a longer period than they would in a normal government contract. That matters. One of the people Ms Sims checks in on is a long-time rough sleeper with a history of violence, a drug habit to feed and a string of prison sentences. She needs time to build a relationship with him: stopping to say hello and roll him a cigarette is part of that process. Coaxing him into a hostel is not the right approach: he’d only end up in a fight and have an eviction on his record, which would make it much harder eventually to place him in permanent accommodation. The priority is to get his drug abuse under control by shifting him to methadone, at which point it becomes possible to think about accommodation. It all takes time.</p>

<p>对于如“圣芒戈魔法”的机构来说，相比一个正常的政府合同，他们获得前期资金的周期较长。这一点很重要。西姆女士探访了一位长期留宿街头的流浪者，他是一个有着暴力前科且多次服刑的吸毒人员。她需要时间和他建立一种关系：对其问好和为其卷烟是建立关系的一部分。哄劝他前往旅社不是一个权宜之策：这样会使他最终以打架的罪名而受到驱逐，从而更难为他安置到长期的住处。首先帮助他服用美沙酮，使他的毒品滥用得到控制，这样才有可能考虑安居的问题，这一过程需要时间。</p>

<p>The homelessness SIB is one of 14 that have now been issued or are in development in Britain, which pioneered the instrument back in 2010 with a bond funding a prisoner-rehabilitation programme in Peterborough. The idea is also winning fans elsewhere. New York city launched a SIB last year tackling recidivism among inmates at Rikers Island prison; Goldman Sachs is among the investors. Work is under way on three more American SIBs, one in New York state and two in Massachusetts. Jeffrey Liebman, a Harvard University professor who is providing technical assistance on all three, has just invited applications from other state and local governments to receive help setting up SIBs: 28 applied.</p>

<p>无家可归 “社会效益债券”现已发行或在英国得到发展，该债券早在2010年开创这一先河，即在（加拿大）彼得伯勒赞助一项“囚犯康复计划”。这一想法也获得世界各地人们的支持。纽约市在去年启动了“社会效益债券”计划，处理雷克岛监狱囚犯的再犯问题。高盛集团也在投资者之列。现已有另外三项美国“社会效益债券”工作正在进行中：一项位于纽约州，两项在马萨诸塞州。对这三项计划提供技术援助的哈佛大学教授杰弗里•利布曼邀请其他州和地方政府的申请接受建立“社会效益债券”机构：已有28个州和地方政府获得批准。</p>

<p>And there is rising emerging-market interest in SIBs, where they go under the name of “development-impact bonds”. According to Michael Belinsky of Instiglio, a start-up devoted to designing SIBs in poor countries, there is less scope for government savings to pay back investors in emerging markets because social safety nets are thinner. So international-development agencies are more likely to act as sponsors. Mr Belinsky is working on potential SIBs in India, to improve educational outcomes for girls in Rajasthan, and in Colombia, to reduce teenage-pregnancy and school drop-out rates.</p>

<p>“社会效益债券”以“发展影响债券”之名面向社会，有着不断上涨的新兴市场利率。致力于在贫穷国家建立“社会效益债券”的新兴公司Instiglio的迈克尔•别林斯基称：因为社会保障体系日趋薄弱，政府偿还新兴市场投资者的储蓄没有多大盈余。因此国际发展机构更有可能作为赞助商。别林斯基先生现在印度致力于即将发展的“社会效益债券”，为（印度）拉贾斯塔邦和哥伦比亚的女孩改善教育成果，降低少女怀孕率和学校失学率。</p>

<p>As the buzz about SIBs increases, the questions will also become more searching. Projects which take many years to have an effect (the impact of pre-school education on university admissions, say) will not interest investors. Good data are crucial for measuring outcomes: that can be a problem in developing countries.</p>

<p>随着有关建立“社会效益债券”的风声四起，问题也变得更加的透彻。需要多年才能产生效果的项目工程（例如，学前教育对大学招生录取的影响）不会引起投资者的兴趣。良好数据对衡量成果至关重要：在发展中国家可能是一个问题。</p>

<p>The hardest questions concern the returns that investors will demand if SIBs are to attract serious amounts of money. The Peterborough SIB dangles an annualised return of up to 13% if reoffending rates go down by enough; but investors lose everything if recidivism does not fall by at least 7.5%. That sort of equity risk is not going to appeal to many, acknowledges Nick Hurd, the British government minister for civil society. “SIBs need to evolve so that they become more like a debt instrument.”</p>

<p>涉及回报最难的问题是：如果“社会效益债券”吸引大量资金，投资者将会有所要求。如果再犯率大大下降，彼得伯勒“社会效益债券”机构年回报率达到13%，这一点仍有待推敲，如果再犯率高于7.5%以上，投资者将血本无归。很多人对这种股票风险不“感冒”。英国政府民间团体部长尼克赫德表示： “社会效益债券”需要改进，变得更像一种类似的债务证券。</p>

<p><strong>Sibling rivals</strong><br/>
<strong>同行竞争对手</strong></p>

<p>Signs of just such an evolution are becoming apparent. The New York city SIB reinforces Goldman’s reputation for dealmaking as much as its philanthropic image: a guarantee from Bloomberg Philanthropies, a foundation, caps the amount of money the bank can lose if recidivism targets are not met. Some think this model, with philanthropists ensuring that a portion of investors’ principal is returned, is the way to bring in more capital.</p>

<p>这种改善的迹象变得越来越明显。位于纽约市的“社会效益债券”机构加强高盛公司交易声誉和慈善形象：彭博慈善基金会的担保规定了再犯率没有达到预期目标的银行损失上限额。有些人认为，除了慈善家确保投资者的一部分本金得到回报，这一模式是吸引更多资金的方法。</p>

<p>Another option is to blend the returns from SIBs with other assets. Allia, a British charity devoted to social investment, this month made a SIB available to retail investors for the first time. Of every £1,000 invested, £780 goes to a fixed-rate loan to a social-housing provider, which when repaid with interest will give investors their money back. Another £200 will go into an SIB providing therapeutic support to troubled children in Essex, which offers investors the potential for a return. (Fees eat up the other £20.) These are still early days, but big ideas often start small.</p>

<p>另一个方法是融合“社会效益债券”机构的收益和其他资产。英国慈善机构“阿利亚”致力于社会投资，这个月首次将“社会效益债券”提供给零售投资者。每1千英镑的投资资金里，780英镑作为固定利率贷款提供给社保住房提供者，一旦本息和利息得到偿付，投资者的资金将会得到偿还。剩余的200英镑将投入“社会效益债券”，为埃塞克斯的困难儿童提供医学治疗，这也为投资者提供了潜在的收益。（还有20英镑用于其他费用）现在还是起步阶段，千里之行，始于足下。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blood Bars and Debt Bunnies-血库酒吧和债务兔]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/02/blood-bars/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T18:00:56+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/02/blood-bars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Clicking your way to sound financial habits</strong><br/>
<strong>一路点击，测试理财习惯</strong></p>

<p>Feb 2nd 2013 | ATLANTA |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130202_FNP002_0.jpg" alt="Blood bars and debt bunnies" /></p>

<p>ONE way to learn basic financial literacy is to sit in a classroom and listen to someone drone on about retirement accounts and financial charges. An alternative is to run a nightclub for vampires and rake in money by getting your customers the blood-type they want, while socking away enough cash for retirement (a long one—you’re undead).</p>

<p>学习理财常识的一个方法就是：坐在教室听某人喋喋不休的讲着退休金账户以及融资费用相关的知识。另外一种方法就是开一家吸血鬼夜总会，给他们提供所需血型，大捞一笔，或者为退休存储足够的钱（如果你是不死之身，这一过程遥遥无期）。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>That is the scenario of “Bite Club”, a video game created by Doorways to Dreams (D2D) Fund, a Boston-based non-profit organisation that works on improving the finances of low- and middle-income consumers. D2D released its first prototype game in 2009, and its library now totals five games. The other titles include “Farm Blitz”, which challenges players to harvest crops from Uncle Felix’s farm while staving off ravenous rabbits (the bunnies represent debt); and “Celebrity Calamity”, in which you are a money manager who keeps a Hollywood starlet happy by keeping her out of debt.</p>

<p>这是波士顿非盈利机构“梦想基金之门”（注释1）创作的电子游戏《齿痕俱乐部》中的情节，该基金会致力于改善中低收入消费者的财政状况。2009年，“通向梦想基金会”发布首个《虐杀原形》游戏（注释2），其程序库现共有5种游戏。其他游戏分别是《农场闪电战》，即要求玩家避开贪婪的兔子（兔子代表债务），从菲利克斯大叔的农场收获农作物，以及《名人灾难》，在这个游戏中，玩家扮演一位资金经理人，让一位好莱坞新秀远离债务困扰，使其无后顾之忧。</p>

<p>Although the scenarios vary, the five games share a few crucial attributes. Like “Angry Birds” or “Tetris”, they have no extensive back stories and are easy to understand. They rely on real-world decision-making: players have to spend on necessary expenses while also saving for retirement and avoiding excess debt.</p>

<p>尽管情节迥异，但是这五种游戏有着共同的一些重要特性。如《愤怒的小鸟》和《俄罗斯方块》，不需要许多的背后操作指示，容易理解。这些游戏依靠现实决策：玩家必须花费必要的费用，同时也得为退休储蓄资金，避免过多债务。</p>

<p>Most importantly, they seem to help people. D2D recently released a paper showing the results of a randomised control trial, in which participants took financial self-confidence and financial-knowledge quizzes and then were assigned either to play “Farm Blitz” or to read a pamphlet before taking the quizzes again. Both groups improved on both measures, and although the pamphlet-readers improved more, the comparison that matters most is not whether D2D’s games are better than reading, but whether they are better than nothing.</p>

<p>最为重要的是，他们似乎是在帮助人们。“梦想基金之门”最近发布的一份报告显示了一次随机控制试验的结果，在这个试验中，参与者进行金融自信和金融知识测试，然后被指定玩《农场闪电战》或者阅读说明书之后再进行测试。在这两种测试措施中，两组都有所改善，尽管说明书阅读者的改善效果更佳，这一比较最重要的不在于“梦想基金之门”游戏要比阅读说明书要好，而是在于聊胜于无。</p>

<p>Financial-literacy education can be off-putting, after all. D2D’s least popular game is “Refund Rush”, in which players act as a financial adviser helping clients decide what to do with their tax refunds. Wouldn’t you choose vampires?</p>

<p>毕竟，金融扫盲教育可能会使人感到不愉快，“梦想基金之门”欢迎指数最低的游戏《职业理财师》，玩家扮演一位金融顾问，帮助客户决定如何利用退税资金。为何不选择吸血鬼呢？</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：D2D FUND（“梦想基金之门”）官网：<a href="http://www.d2dfund.org/">http://www.d2dfund.org/</a></p>

<p>注释2：虐杀原形（Prototype）是由Radical Entertainment公司制作，美国动视发行于2009年6月9日发售的开放式科幻自由动作冒险游戏，玩家将扮演一位由病毒集合成的生物体，还要与军队和各种变异生物战斗。该游戏以高超的自由度、肆无忌惮破坏与暴力杀戮为卖点，应用Radical公司独立开发的钛合金游戏引擎IV(Titanium game engine)，游戏的风格类似侠盗猎车手系列，不同的是，当主角抓住路人或敌人时便可以吸收他们的记忆、能力，甚至能变成他们的样子以进行伪装。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[War Crimes in Bangladesh: Justice Delayed-孟加拉迟来的正义]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/26/bangladesh/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-26T20:34:09+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/26/bangladesh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>A first conviction for war crimes sparks controversy</strong><br/>
<strong>首次对战争罪行的定罪引发争议</strong></p>

<p>Jan 26th 2013 |From the print edition</p>

<p>MORE than 41 years after the deaths of as many as 3m people in Bangladesh’s war of secession from Pakistan, a Bangladeshi war crimes tribunal has given its first verdict. On January 21st it sentenced Abul Kalam Azad to death in absentia for genocide and murder committed during the nine-month war in 1971. The verdict is being seen as a victory for Sheikh Hasina, the prime minister, and her Awami League party, who have made the tribunal an important part of her term in office.</p>

<p>孟加拉国曾为脱离巴基斯坦引发的战争致使3百万人丧生，近42年过去了，如今孟加拉国战争军事法庭对此进行首次裁决，于1月21日对阿布尔•卡拉姆•阿扎德在1971年长达9个月的战争中所犯下的种族灭绝及屠杀罪行进行缺席审判，处以死刑。这一裁决是谢赫•哈西娜总理和其人民联盟政党的一大胜利，也是她任期的一个重要垫脚石。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Bangladeshis have waited decades for justice and the aims of the tribunal are broadly popular, but critics say the process has been politicised to target allies of Sheikh Hasina’s main opponent, former prime minister Khaleda Zia, head of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP). There have also been questions raised about its impartiality. In December The Economist reported on contacts by e-mail and Skype between the presiding judge in one of the tribunals and a lawyer in Belgium who was not an official part of the court. The judge eventually resigned and was replaced. The verdict on Mr Azad came from a second tribunal.</p>

<p>孟加拉国期待正义已有数年，这次审判的目的深得人心，但是批评家认为这次裁决已被政治化，主要是针对谢赫•哈西娜&lt;注释1>即孟加拉国国民党领导人兼前总理卡莉达•齐亚。也有很多人质疑这次裁决的公正性。12月，《经济学家》报道此次审判的其中一位首席法官和一位比利时律师联系的邮件内容及网络电话记录，这位法官最终辞职，被取而代之。第二次开庭审判对阿扎德做出了判决。</p>

<p>In the judgment Mr Azad is described as a former leader of the youth wing of Jamaat-e-Islami, a party in then East Pakistan and still Bangladesh’s biggest Islamic party today. Its youth wing was the main source of paramilitaries supporting Pakistan in its efforts to prevent East Pakistan’s independence. Its members are alleged to have abducted and murdered dozens of civilians. Mr Azad himself was accused of killing at least 12 Hindus and of rape. He then became a well-connected political figure in Bangladesh and a presenter of popular Islamic television programmes. He fled the country last year and is believed to be in Pakistan.</p>

<p>这次审判把阿扎德描绘成伊斯兰大会党青年团前领导人，该党现在仍然是孟加拉国（当时的东巴基斯坦）最大的伊斯兰党。这一青年团是协助巴基斯坦人们阻止东巴基斯坦独立的主要辅助军事力量，该团成员也涉嫌绑架和杀害许多的平民百姓。阿扎德本人被指控杀害至少12名印度教徒和涉嫌强奸罪。他曾在孟加拉国政治界人脉广泛，而且在炙手可热的伊斯兰电视节目中担任主持人。他去年叛逃孟加拉国，据信现在在巴基斯坦。</p>

<p>Mrs Zia has found it impossible to distance her party from Jamaat-e-Islami, an ally whose support the BNP needs if it is to win the election, likely to take place this year. Among the ten other senior figures to be tried are two leading party officials, both former ministers in Mrs Zia’s 2001-2006 government. It may be that almost the entire leadership of Jamaat will be hanged before the polls. So, too, may two members of Mrs Zia’s party, including one of her close advisers. Sheikh Hasina will hope that the taint of 1971 will make the BNP-Jamaat alliance so toxic to voters that she will be returned to power.</p>

<p>齐亚（音译）&lt;注释2>觉得不能和伊斯兰教党对立，因为孟加拉国国民党需要该联盟的支持，来赢得今年可能举行的大选。十个被审的高级官员中有两个是大会党重要官员，而且还曾在齐亚2001—2006年执政期间担任部长。整个伊斯兰教领导势力也许会在民意调查之前全军覆没，齐亚所在党派的两名成员（其中包括她的一名亲密顾问）也不例外，谢赫•哈西娜希望1971年发生的这一丑闻来丑化该国国民党-伊斯兰教联盟，从而使自己获得选民的支持，重新执掌政权。</p>

<hr />

<ol>
<li><p>谢赫•哈西娜（1947年9月28日－），孟加拉国总理。哈西娜出生于1947年9月28日，其父是孟加拉国国父、首任总统谢赫•穆吉布•拉赫曼。1975年8月15日，其父穆吉布及其亲属15人在首都达卡被政变军人杀害，哈西娜当时在德国，幸免于难。1981年2月，哈西娜出任孟加拉国人民联盟主席。1996年6月23日至2001年7月15日之间出任孟加拉国总理。2008年12月29日举行的议会大选中，哈西娜率领的人民联盟取得压倒性胜利，再次获得组阁权.</p></li>
<li><p>卡莉达•齐亚 (Begum Khaleda Zia)1945年8月15日生于迪纳杰布尔县。她是孟加拉国前总统齐亚•拉赫曼的遗孀。卡莉达•齐亚1960年入苏伦德拉纳特学院学习，1963年毕业。在校期间与齐亚•拉赫曼上尉结婚。1981年5月齐亚•拉赫曼遇刺后，她开始步入政坛，1982年3月任孟加拉国民族主义党副主席，1984年当选主席。1991年2月，民族主义党在大选中获胜。同年3月，卡•齐亚出任总理，成为孟加拉国历史上第一位女总理。2001年10月至2006年10月再次出任总理。</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literary Protest-笔尖上的抗议]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/literary-protest/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-23T21:20:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/literary-protest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Local hero</strong><br/>
<strong>平民英雄</strong></p>

<p>Jan 23rd 2013, 4:52 by The Economist | CHENGDU</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/original-size/images/2013/01/blogs/analects/li_chengpeng.jpg" alt="李承鹏" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>LIU XIAOBO, China’s first non-Tibetan to wear the laurel of a Nobel peace prize, languishes quietly in prison and the artist known as Ai Weiwei remains better known abroad than at home. But a number of writers and activists whose names are not so famous overseas have gained a following within China by daring to tweak the tail of the Communist Party.</p>

<p>中国第一位获得诺贝尔和平奖的非藏族人士刘晓波遭囚禁，静度余生，著名艺术家艾未未在国内的知名度远不及在国外的知名度。但是许多不为国外所熟知得作家和积极份子敢于揭共产党所短，在国内得到许多人的支持。</p>

<p>Perhaps chief among them would be a former sports writer, Li Chengpeng. Mr Li has recently stirred up a storm with a new book, a collection of sharp essays on his country’s social ills, titled “Everybody in the World Knows”. During his book tour in January he was adored by fans, physically attacked by enemies and finally silenced by the Chinese authorities.
也许这些人的主要人物是前体育记者李承鹏，他的新书《全世界人民都知道》是一部辛辣批判国家的社会弊病的杂文集，在最近弄得满城风雨。在一月的新书签售活动中，李承鹏受其粉丝追捧，遭受其反对者掌掴并被官方禁言。</p>

<p>Thousands of supporters turned out to meet the author in Chengdu, Beijing and Shenzhen. On January 12th, just before he appeared at his book signing in Chengdu, Mr Li took stock of the rules that had been laid down for the aunch and announced to his 6.7m followers on Sina Weibo, China’s homegrown version of Twitter: “I am not allowed to speak, not allowed to give opening remarks, I am not even allowed to say ‘Happy New Year’ or ‘Thank you all’.” Instead he wore a black mask over his mouth and the words “I love you all” written on his shirt. The crowd roared its approval, and snapped up copies of his book by the armload.</p>

<p>数千支持者在成都，北京和深圳参加他的签售会。1月·12日，在他四川签售活动之前，李仔细估量了上级对这次签售活动所下达的命令并在微博（中国版本的推特）上对其670万关注者说：“不准我说话，不准我致开场白，连“新年好，谢谢你们”也不准说。”他戴着黑色的口罩，在其衬衫上写上“我爱你们”。在场的群众欢呼雀跃，抢购李的新书。</p>

<p>His reception in Beijing went less smoothly. One self-proclaimed Maoist hurled a kitchen knife at him and another punched him in the face. Some Maoists regard him as a traitor for his criticism of the Communist Party. Since the knife-throwing incident, and then further cries of treason at the book signing in Shenzhen, the police have chosen to rein in Mr Li. He texted at least one reporter to explain that he was being taken away for a chat. An appearance in Guangzhou was cancelled suddenly.</p>

<p>他的北京签售也并非顺利。一位自称“毛派”人士向李扔了一把菜刀，某人对李脸上“赠”与一掌掴。李承鹏因批判共产党，一些“毛派”人士将其视为“汉奸”。自深圳新书签售会上的掷刀事件以及随即的“卖国贼”呼声，警方已对李进行约束，李对相关记者证实他被警方带走就此事做笔录，广州签售会也随即取消。</p>

<p>Li Chengpeng is no stranger to threats and government pressure. Working as a sportswriter from the early 1990s to 2009, he chose to focus his reporting on rampant corruption, which culminated in a book called “Chinese Football: The Inside Story”, published in January 2010. It detailed match-fixing and bribery across the country and brought down the wrath of incensed trainers, “patriotic readers” and government censors. Chen Yiming, trainer of the Chongqing Lifan club, brought a suit against Mr Li in 2009 which succeeded in incurring fines of 200,000 yuan ($32,000) and the demand that the published reporting be retracted publicly. Mr Li refused and in December 2012 a Guangzhou court overturned the verdict on appeal. Mr Li was found not guilty of libel, and his articles were judged to be “non-damaging”. Mr Chen, the trainer, was forced to pay the court’s costs.</p>

<p>李承鹏对威胁和政府的施压已是司空见惯。他在90年代初期至2009年期间从事体育专栏报道工作，之后专注报道泛滥猖獗的腐败问题，其书名为《中国足球内幕》，并在2010年1月出版，详细介绍了全国假球和贿赂等黑幕，以及打击了足球教练员的嚣张气焰。重庆力帆俱乐部教练陈亦明（音译）在2009年对李提起诉讼，成功胜诉，法院判决李赔偿20万（3.2万美元）以及召回发表的足球报道，李承鹏拒绝接受并上诉，2012年12月广州一家法院推翻这一判决。李承鹏被判无罪，其文章也被判定对社会没有危害。教练员陈不得不支付法庭费用。</p>

<p>Seasoned at playing the provocateur, Mr Li moved from reporting on sport to writing essays on politics and society soon after the Sichuan earthquake of 2008, which killed more than 80,000 people. His writing on the struggles of common people after the disaster brought his work to a whole new audience of internet-savvy young Chinese. He went on to publish a novel in 2011, “Li Kele Protests Demolitions”. Mr Li’s “Li Kele” was an immediate hit; the descriptions of ordinary people who united together to fight faceless forces and venality propelled the writer into the arms of a more organized new audience: China’s advocates for social reform.</p>

<p>李承鹏在发起“挑衅活动”方面有丰富的阅历，他以前是报道体育新闻，自2008年四川地震（死亡人数超过8万）之后不久，他开始写有关政治方面的文章。对老百姓灾后重建的文章吸引了网络上一批全新的年轻人。2011年，他出版了一本小说《李可乐抗拆记》，这本书立即得到强烈反响，小说中关于平民老百姓联合反抗幕后势力以及腐败问题的描绘使作者融入一个更有组织的新读者群：中国社会改革的提倡者。</p>

<p>Later that year Mr Li announced that he would be running for public office in Chengdu as an independent. Although his election campaign was never allowed to get under way (candidates for office are carefully screened by the Communist Party and eventually Mr Li failed his background check), he gained a new degree of credibility. Here, it seemed, was a man who would back up his words with actions.</p>

<p>此后，李承鹏宣布将以无党派身份竞选成都公职，虽然他的竞选活动尚未允许启动（竞选公职的候选人需经过共产党的精心筛选，李最终未能通过背景调查），但是他的公信力获得提高，还有一个人似乎用行动来支持李的文章。</p>

<p>At the book launch in Chengdu, an elderly man named Liu Shahe sat behind Mr Li. Mr Liu is one of the signatories of Charter 08, the document demanding a list political reforms that Liu Xiaobo, the Nobel laureate, was jailed for drafting. Mr Li tweeted Mr Liu’s words to him—“You man of words, just keep writing”—and said the encouragement from the older man had reduced him to tears.</p>

<p>在成都签售会上，一位老人站在李的身后，老人名叫流沙河，是《08宪章》的其中一名签署者，该文书要求一系列政治改革，诺贝尔奖获得者刘晓波因起草该文书被囚禁。李在微博上写上刘对他所说的话-“文人，写下去即是胜利”&ndash;称这位老人的鼓励让他潸然泪下。</p>

<p>Since that relatively thunderous clap, Mr Li seems to be trying to turn his volume down a notch. In a recent post to his blog, Li said he would be doing small events only, with friends and close supporters. He urged his fans to pay attention to “bigger issues like corruption, food safety and pollution” and not focus so much on the man and his book.</p>

<p>自这件事传得沸沸扬扬以来，李似乎试图低调行事。他在最近的一篇博文中说他将和朋友以及联系密切的支持者只做做小事，他敦促粉丝们关注更大的问题，如腐败，食品安全，污染问题等，而不是过多集中在他本人和这本书上。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia: Forced Into Extinction-沙特阿拉伯：被迫消失在历史长河中]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/21/arabia-forced-extinction/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T19:40:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/21/arabia-forced-extinction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Forced into extinction</strong><br/>
<strong>被迫消失在历史长河中</strong></p>

<p>Jan 21st 2013, 18:25 by M.R. | CAIRO</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/blogs/pomegranate/20130126_map501.jpg" alt="沙特阿拉伯：被迫消失在历史长河中" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>LIKE much that moves in Twitter-mad Saudi Arabia these days, it started with a single message. A lady in Dammam, the hub of the oil industry on the kingdom’s Gulf coast, tweeted a complaint from a local shopping mall. Agents of the Committee for the Promotion of Virtue and Prevention of Vice (CPVPV), she said, were causing an unpleasant scene. The government-salaried vigilantes, a bearded auxiliary police force familiarly known to Saudis as the Hayaa, had marched officiously into an educational exhibit featuring plaster models of dinosaurs, turned off the lights and ordered everyone out, frightening children and alarming their parents.</p>

<p>就如最近发生在沙特阿拉伯的诸多事件，“推特”（音译）的流行，导火线源于一条的简单短信，这一事件也不例外。沙特阿拉伯波斯湾海岸石油港口达曼一位女士在“推特”发微博抱怨当地一家购物商场。她称“扬善惩恶委员会”工作人员是造成这一不愉快场面的罪魁祸首。政府自卫队即沙特人们熟识的满面胡须的“哈亚”辅助警察队强行进入以一家恐龙石膏模型的教育展览馆，切断电源并命令所有人离开，使孩子们及其父母受到惊吓。</p>

<p>It was unclear precisely why the religious police objected to the exhibit, which apparently had been innocently featured at shopping centres across the Gulf for decades. Malls are one of the few public spaces where Saudis mix socially, and so often draw the Hayaa’s attentions. Gone, however, are the days when its agents can go about their business unchallenged.</p>

<p>该展览馆数年来一直是海湾购物中心的特色,宗教警察为何反对这一展览的目的尚不明确。购物中心是沙特人社交的少数公共场所之一，因此常常引起哈亚的注意。然而，委员会工作人员不能像以前那样为所欲为的处理问题了。</p>

<p>Within minutes of the incident, a freshly minted Arabic Twitter hashtag, #Dammam-Hayaa-Closes-Dinosaur-Show, was generating scores of theories about their motives. Perhaps, suggested one, there was a danger that citizens might start worshipping dinosaur statues instead of God. Maybe it was just a temporary measure, said another, until the Hayaa can separate male and female dinosaurs and put them in separate rooms. Surely, declared a third, one of the lady dinosaurs had been caught in public without a male guardian. A fourth announced an all-points police alert for Barney the Dinosaur, while another suggested it was too early to judge until it was clear what the dinosaurs were wearing.</p>

<p>在该事件发生后的几分钟之内，一个刚形成的阿拉伯“推特”主题标签（达曼-哈亚关闭恐龙展览）引起了关于宗教警察动机的诸多推测。有人认为，人们可能会信仰恐龙而不是上帝，这也许是一种危险；有人则觉得这也许只是哈亚区分雌雄恐龙且将其放置在单独房间之前的一个临时措施；当然，还有人则宣称一只雌性恐龙在没有雄性恐龙的“保护下”，当众被人”猥亵“；另外还有人称所有现场警察提高对巴尼恐龙标本警惕，而其他人认为，除非先了解恐龙身上穿的什么，现在评价还为时过早。</p>

<p>Several contributors injected bawdy innuendo into their comments. Noting that one of the displays showed a dinosaur riding on the back of another, one message declared that this was obviously sexually suggestive and possibly could be categorised as a Westernising influence. &ldquo;I confess,&rdquo; declared one penitent, &ldquo;I saw a naked dinosaur thigh and felt aroused.&rdquo; Another tweet provided this helpful tip to the suspicious CPVPV: &ldquo;No, no, that long thing is a tail!&rdquo;</p>

<p>一些撰稿人在其评论中进行了含沙射影的讽刺，指出有一展览展出一只恐龙骑在另外一只恐龙的背上，有人称这明显暗含“性”内容且可能将其视为是西化影响的产物。一位忏悔者称，”我承认，赤裸的恐龙大腿刺激了我的性欲望。“另外一位”推特“用户向多疑的扬善惩恶委员会提供了一条有益的建议：”不，不，这长长的东西是一条尾巴！“</p>

<p>But most of the messages singled out the religious police for ridicule. &ldquo;They worried that people would find the dinosaurs more highly evolved than themselves,&rdquo; explained one. &ldquo;It’s the Hayaa that should be stuffed and mounted so future generations can learn about extinct animals,&rdquo; quipped another. This message adopted a more pedantic tone: &ldquo;Dinosaurs are a paleontological life form from an ancient geological era, and our clerics are a paleontological life form from an ancient social era.&rdquo; &ldquo;Hello? Stone Age? We have some of your people; can you please come and collect them?&rdquo; pleaded one tweep. Another wrote: &ldquo;If the dinosaurs were still alive they’d be saying, thank God for extinction.&rdquo;</p>

<p>但是大多数评论针对宗教警察进行讥讽。有人解释，”他们担心人们会发现恐龙的进化比他们更加高级“。有人嘲弄，”哈亚应该有标本让后代了解灭绝了的动物。“ 这条评论采用了一种更为迂腐的语气：”恐龙是古老地质时期的一种古生物学生命形式，牧师是古老社会时期的一种古生物学生命形式。一位“推特”用户“ 用恳求的语气讽刺 ，”拜托？石器时代？我们有你们的一些同类，麻烦来“收了”他们？“另一位用户写道：“如果恐龙现在还没有灭绝，它们可能会为自己的灭绝而感谢上帝。”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gun Control-美国枪支管制]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/gun-control/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-16T20:30:06+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/gun-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Obama fires the opening shot</strong><br/>
<strong>奥巴马打响美国控抢对策的第一枪</strong></p>

<p>Jan 16th 2013, 22:50 by Economist.com | NEW YORK</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/blogs/democracy-america/guns590.jpg" alt="Gun control-美国枪支管控" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>GRACE MCDONNELL’S parents gave one of her paintings to Barack Obama. The seven-year-old, who dreamed of being a painter, was shot dead in her classroom last month. The picture now hangs in the president’s study as a reminder to act. Even in a country as accustomed to gun violence as America, the murder of 26 people, including 20 children, in a Newtown, Connecticut school last month was especially shocking. On that day a tearful Mr Obama said serious action was needed to prevent any more tragedies. On January 16th Mr Obama, along with Vice-President Joe Biden, who headed the president’s gun task-force, unveiled the most sweeping gun-control proposals Washington, DC has seen for two decades. Whether they will be implemented or make much difference is another matter.</p>

<p>格蕾丝-麦克唐娜（音译）的父母送给奥巴马一副由格蕾丝作的画。这个曾经梦想成为画家的7岁小女孩于上个月在其教室被枪杀。这幅画现挂在总统的书房，提醒人们采取行动。甚至是枪支暴力泛滥的美国，上个月在纽镇发生的康尼狄格州校园枪击惨案造成26人丧生，其中包括20名小孩，这一事件震惊世界。奥巴马在惨案发生这一天含泪发表讲话，表示要采取行动，阻止类似悲剧再次发生。1月16日，奥巴马和负责限枪事宜的副总统乔-拜登在白宫公布二十年来最为全面的枪支限制提案，这些对策能否付诸实施或带来多大改观得另当别论。</p>

<p>The president’s plan was inspired not just by the children killed in Newtown, but by the more than 30,000 deaths caused by guns every year. Mr Obama announced 23 executive orders, which do not need congressional approval. These include strengthening the system of background checks (which is notoriously ineffective) and providing more support to law-enforcement agencies. Another order seeks to make schools safer by ensuring that each one has an emergency management plan (most of them, including the Newton one, already do).</p>

<p>纽镇发生的儿童枪击事件以及每年有超过3万人死亡枪支泛滥的现状促使奥巴马制定这一计划。奥巴马公布了无需国会批准的23项行政法令。其内容包括加强购枪背景检查体系（这体系的办事效率低下，人尽皆知）和加大对执法机构的投入。另一法令是加强学校安保，确保每一个学校有紧急事务管理计划（许多学校，包括纽镇所在的小学，现已有该计划）。</p>

<p>But Mr Obama will need congressional backing for the main part of his plan: a proposal to renew an assault-weapons ban that went into effect in 1994 but expired ten years later. The ban would include, as it did back in 1994, a ban on high-capacity ammunition magazines, containing more than ten rounds. The trouble is that ban, especially the magazine part of it, proved impossible to enforce.</p>

<p>但是奥巴马需要国会的支持他计划中的主要部分：恢复1994年生效并于2004年到期的禁止攻击性武器方案。这一禁令包括1994年实行禁止拥有超过10发高性能供弹装置的规定。困难的是，这一禁令，尤其有关弹药方面，不可能实施。</p>

<p>States, meanwhile, have jumped the gun. Andrew Cuomo, New York’s governor and a gun-owner, signed the NY Safe Act on January 15th. The state, which already had strong gun laws, has now banned military-style assault weapons, and has mandated universal background checks, including on buyers of ammunition. Martin O’Malley, Maryland’s governor, is about to introduce a sweeping gun-control package which echoes many of New York’s measures. Colorado’s governor has called for background checks for private gun sales, which are currently exempt. Deval Patrick, the governor of Massachusetts, wants to limit gun sales to one a month. Of course, one can do quite a lot of damage with one gun a month.</p>

<p>同时，很多州已经开始提前行动了。1月15日，纽约州长兼枪支业主安德鲁-库摩（音译）签署了《纽约安全法案》。纽约州早已有严格的枪支法律，现已禁止使用军事化攻击性武器，以及授权进行包括弹药购买者的全面背景检查。马里兰州长马丁-奥马莱（音译）效仿纽约州实行的许多措施，即将采取全面控抢计划。科罗拉多州长提倡对目前豁免的私人枪支销售进行背景调查。马萨诸塞州长德瓦尔-帕特奈克（音译）想要限制每人每月只能买一支枪。当然，就算是一个月一支枪还是可以造成巨大破坏。</p>

<p>Cities, too, are taking a stand. Since the Newtown shooting, more than 100 more mayors have joined Mayors Against Illegal Guns, the 800-strong coalition founded by Michael Bloomberg, New York’s mayor.</p>

<p>许多城市也表明立场。自从纽镇的枪击事件以来，又有100多位市长参与了纽约市长迈克尔&#8221;布隆伯格发起的 “反对非法枪支”这一由800位市长组成的强大联盟。</p>

<p>Welcome as these state and city actions are, without federal backup they are not much use. They may also be vulnerable to recision by the Supreme Court. Would-be killers need only cross state lines to places with weak gun laws to get access to weapons. Nor is it clear whether the president’s plan would have prevented the Newtown massacre. There, the shooter did not have a background check; he used his mother’s guns.</p>

<p>尽管这些州和市采取的行动受到欢迎，但没有联邦政府的支持，也不会有多大成效。美国最高法院很有可能废除这些措施。潜在杀手只需越过州界限，到枪支管控不严格的地方就能得到武器。总统公布的计划能否避免类似纽镇枪杀杀事件尚不明朗。因为在该事件中，枪击凶手使用其母亲的枪，本人并没有受到背景调查。</p>

<p>Mr Obama faces steep opposition, and not just from congressional opponents: even his fellow Democrat, Harry Reid, the majority leader of the Senate, has indicated that the assault-weapons ban will be a hard sell. While states like New York and California are moving to strengthen gun laws, other states are doing the opposite. Lawmakers in Arizona and Texas, for instance, intend to introduce bills that would loosen gun restrictions. A Kentucky sheriff has said he will not enforce any new gun laws that he deems unconstitutional.</p>

<p>奥巴马面对居高不下的反对意见，不仅仅是国会共和党的反对：其民主党派人士兼参议院多数党领袖哈里-瑞特（音译）指出这一禁止攻击性武器法令如同“强买强卖”。尽管很多州如纽约州和加利福尼亚州正加强枪支法律，但他州的做法却相反。例如，亚利桑那州和德克萨斯州的立法者打算推行放松枪支限制的法案。肯塔基州的一位地方司法官称他不会实施任何新的违反宪法的枪支法律。</p>

<p>Most shockingly, gun sales have soared in recent weeks. In the month since the Newtown shooting 250,000 more people have joined the National Rifle Association, which has vowed to oppose the ban. The group is getting so cocky that it launched a free shooting app this week. For an extra 99 cents, players can use a MK-11 sniper rifle to shoot coffin-shaped targets.</p>

<p>最让人震惊的是，枪支销售量在最近几周急剧上升。自纽镇枪击事件以来，已有25万多人加入了誓言反对这一禁令的美国步枪协会，该协会表现越来越“嚣张”，在这周推行了一个免费射击应用游戏。玩家只要支付额外的99美分，就可以使用MK-11狙击步枪射击棺材型目标。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[French Foreign Policy-法国外交政策]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/french-foreign-policy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-14T21:20:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/french-foreign-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>France goes it alone</strong><br/>
<strong>单打独斗</strong></p>

<p>Jan 14th 2013, 12:55 by S.P. | PARIS</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/blogs/charlemagne/20130119_eup501.jpg" alt="法国外交政策" /></p>

<p>FRANCE’S decision on January 11th to begin air strikes against Islamist rebel positions in northern Mali, designed to prevent “the establishment of a terrorist state” in the African Sahel, contained elements of both surprise and familiarity.</p>

<p>法国决定1月11日对马里北部伊斯兰叛军武装据点进行空袭，以防止其在非洲撒赫勒地区建立恐怖主义国家，这一决定让人惊讶但又有点司空见惯。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The surprise was that François Hollande, the president, a Socialist leader not known for decisive action and untried in foreign policy, moved so swiftly to order French fighter jets and attack helicopters into action. Using warplanes based both in France and at a permanent base in nearby Chad, the French struck rebel columns advancing out of Islamist-held territory and towards Bamako, the Malian capital. Such groups, with ties to Al-Qaeda, have ruled a big chunk or the north of the country since March last year.</p>

<p>众所周知，法国总统兼社会党领导人弗朗索瓦•奥朗德在外交政策上不会果断决策和进行尝试性行动，而这次却迅速下令法国战机和武装直升机采取行动，这一反差让人感到惊讶。从法国开赴的战机以及乍得长期基地的战机击败驻在伊斯兰教领土至马里首都巴尔科地区的叛军部队。自去年3月以来，这个与基地组织联系的团伙占领马里大部分地区或北部地区。</p>

<p>The French government said that the weekend air strikes, part of what it is calling Operation Serval, had stopped the rebel advance, and helped Malian troops to regain control of the town of Konna; one French helicopter pilot was killed, as well as a dozen Malian soldiers. On the third day of air attacks, the French struck deeper into Islamist-held territory, targeting training camps and logistics centres, according to Jean-Yves Le Drian, the defence minister.</p>

<p>法国政府称周末进行的“薮猫行动”空袭打击已阻止叛军进攻，帮助马里军队收复了孔纳镇，已有一位法国直升机飞行员和十二位马里士兵丧生。法国国防部长Jean-Yves Le Drian称，空袭的第三天，法军深入挺进伊斯兰教地区，重点打击叛军训练营和物流中心，</p>

<p>France has certainly been in the lead in pushing for intervention in Mali. It drafted a United Nations Security Council resolution authorising a regional African force to retake rebel-held territory, which was unanimously passed last October. In a speech to a gathering of French-speaking countries in Senegal last year, Mr Hollande spoke of a “reign of terror” in Islamist-held Mali, where sharia law has been applied in the furthest north.</p>

<p>法国在马里军事干预中的确是有着主导作用。法国向联合国安理会起草的一份授权非洲当地军队收复叛军占据领土的决议在去年10月一致通过。去年在塞内加尔举行的法语国家会议中，奥朗德谈到在伊斯兰教为主的马里的恐怖统治，伊斯兰教反政府已深入马里最北方地区。</p>

<p>France is particularly worried that the Sahel is becoming an “Afrighanistan”—a breeding ground for terrorists—thanks in part to modern weaponry that has spilled over the Libyan border after the war there. France itself has been named as a target by groups based in the north; this weekend, as the airstrikes began, the country raised its terrorism-security alert. France also has strong commercial links in the region, and there are currently eight French hostages in the region.</p>

<p>法国特别担心萨赫勒会成为另外一个“阿富汗”—恐怖分子的温床—部分原因是自利比亚边境爆发的内战来，先进武器的使用向周边国家扩展。法国已成为马里北部的基地叛军报复目标，当空袭开始之时，法国在上周末提高反恐预警方案级别。法国在该地区拥有强大经济联系，反叛组织目前仍挟持8名法国人质。</p>

<p>Mr Hollande had also made clear that it was no longer his intention for France to play the role of regional gendarme, stepping in to prop up African rulers, as has been the post-colonial tradition under the Fifth Republic. “Françafrique”, the opaque mesh of military, political and commercial ties, was over, he claimed. Until now, he had insisted that France would offer no more than logistical support to a regional African force, which was laboriously being put together for this autumn.</p>

<p>奥朗德也明确表示，他不会采取像法兰西第五共和国的后殖民主义传统以往的做法，让法国充当该地区军队进行军事干预帮助非洲统治者已不再是他的意愿。他称，政治与商业相交织的不透明网即“法国非洲”已成过去式。他至今仍坚称法国将只对非洲地区军队提供后勤支持，并在今年秋季全力付诸实施。</p>

<p>Which is where the element of familiarity comes in. The reality, acknowledged privately by French sources, is that the Malian army was in no position to defend itself, and that the regional African force was going to take too long to assemble. Mr Hollande stressed that France was acting with a legal international mandate, and responding to a request from the Malian president, Dioncounda Traoré, for help. In a diplomatic breakthrough of sorts, Algeria granted France permission for fighter jets to fly over its airpace. Laurent Fabius, the French foreign minister, said on French radio on January 13th that France had little choice but to intervene urgently or Islamist forces might have made it to Bamako, with “appalling consequences”.</p>

<p>让人司空见惯的是：法国媒体私下报道马里军队没有能力进行自卫，而且非洲地区部队要花很多时间组建军队，这都是现实情况。奥朗德强调法国是在国际合法授权下采取行动，以及对马里总统迪翁昆达•特拉奥雷请求支援做出的回应。阿尔及利亚准许法国战机飞越其领空，这是外交上的一大突破。法国外交部长洛朗-法比尤斯在1月13日通过法国电台表示法国别无选择，只能迅速采取军事干预，否则伊斯兰叛军可能会在巴马科造成可怕的后果。</p>

<p>However much successive French presidents say that they want to put an end to post-colonial intervention in Africa, with few other takers for the job it usually proves irresistible at some point. Nicolas Sarkozy, Mr Hollande’s predecessor, had also promised a new era, only to end up sending the French army to help Côte d’Ivoire forcibly evict Laurent Gbagbo, the loser of that country’s presidential election, from office.</p>

<p>尽管法国总统连续强调法国想要结束在非洲的后殖民主义干预，而对于其他少数国家来说，这种干预在某些情况下通常是不可抗拒的，法国前任总统尼古拉-萨科奇曾许诺开辟一个新的时代，结果只是派遣法国军队帮助科特迪瓦共和国强迫总统竞选落选者洛朗•巴博下台。</p>

<p>The question now is how long the French are prepared to intervene, and how fast a decent African ground force can realistically be put in place. Mr Fabius has talked of “a question of weeks” for the French intervention. He insists that its main contribution is air power, with the few hundred special forces on the ground essentially picking out and verifying targets.</p>

<p>现在的问题是法国准备多长时间进行干预以及训练尚可的非洲陆军多快实现真正作战。法比尤斯表示法国干预是数周以来一直讨论的问题。他坚称空军以及主要辨认和确认袭击目标的几百地面特种部队是作战的主力。</p>

<p>It is the West African force that is supposed to carry out the operation to retake the north from Islamists, and there is a regional meeting on this now set for January 19th. Initial contingents of troops from Senegal, Niger, Burkina Faso, Nigeria and Togo are now due to arrive within days. But a properly manned force will still take time to assemble. France, in short, is likely to find itself involved for a while. Mr Hollande himself has stated that the French operation would last “as long as necessary”.</p>

<p>据称西非军队将采取行动从“伊斯兰教支持者”手中夺取北部地区，1月19号将对此问题举行地区会议。塞内加尔，尼日尔，布基纳法索，尼日利亚以及多哥首次派遣军队，将在几天之内到达北部地区作战。但是组建一支组织严密的军队仍需时日。总之，法国可能还将继续进行干预。奥朗德本人也表示只要有需要，法国将会一直采取行动。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform in China-中国改革任道重远]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/12/reform-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-12T20:10:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/12/reform-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Great expectations</strong><br/>
<strong>殷切希望</strong></p>

<p>Reform of the labour-camp system would be welcome, but more change must come soon</p>

<p>劳教制度改革实属欢迎，但必须有更多实质性改革</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jan 12th 2013 | from the print edition</p>

<p>IN HUNAN province last August, Tang Hui was sentenced to 18 months in a labour camp. Her crime was to demand tougher sentences for the men who had kidnapped and raped her 11-year-old daughter. In days gone by, Ms Tang would simply have disappeared. In the age of the microblog, thousands of incensed middle-class people took up her case. Ms Tang was released, and on January 7th the government announced that the labour-camps system would be reformed (see article).</p>

<p>去年8月，湖南（信访妈妈）唐辉被判处8个月劳教。她的罪名是要求对绑架且强奸她11岁女儿的罪犯处以更重刑法。在过去，像唐辉这样的事件很容易被淡化。但在微博无处不在的时代，数以千计愤世嫉俗的中产阶级在微博上评论她的事件。因此唐女士被提前释放，中国政府在1月7号宣布对劳教制度进行改革。</p>

<p>In Guangzhou last week, allegedly under orders from the provincial propaganda chief, an editorial in Southern Weekend, a reformist newspaper, was altered before publication (seearticle). The original called for greater respect of rights enshrined in China’s constitution. The amended version praised the Communist Party and China’s political system. Some Southern Weekend staff called a strike and supporters protested outside their offices in Guangzhou, chanting political slogans of a sort rarely heard on China’s streets since 1989.</p>

<p>上周，广州省委宣传部长私自命令改动“改革系”报社《南方周末》的一篇社论（即新年贺词）。原文章呼吁尊重中国宪法规定的权利（《中国梦，宪政梦》）。删改版本则赞美共产党和中国政治制度。《南方周报》一些员工为此进行罢工，支持者则在广州的报社总部办公楼外抗议声援，举起了自1989年以来在中国很少看到的政治标语。</p>

<p>In both cases, officials were in breach of China’s constitution. There is nothing new in that. The officials were behaving as officials always have behaved. What has changed is the expectations of the people. Chinese citizens can no longer be pacified with economic growth and slogans. They want political change. How Xi Jinping, China’s new leader, manages this growing pressure for reform will determine his, and his country’s, future.</p>

<p>中国官员在这两起事件中违反了国家宪法，这已不是什么新鲜事了。官员们的处理方法一如既往，而变化的则是老百姓的期待。中国公民不再满足于经济增长这样的口号，他们期待政治改革。中国新任领导人习近平如何处理这种不断上升的改革压力将决定着他和中国的命运。</p>

<p>The justice system and press freedom are core reasons for popular discontent. China’s reform-through-labour system, known as laojiao, was set up in 1957 under Mao Zedong. It is different from the mainstream system of prisons and labour camps whose inmates have been through the judicial system. Established to deal with “counter-revolutionaries”, laojiao camps are now reserved for petty criminals, prostitutes and petitioners who embarrass the government. People can be locked up in them without trial for up to four years. They are said to hold around 160,000 detainees, possibly more.</p>

<p>司法体制和出版自由是民怨的重要原因。中国的劳动改造制度-劳教，于1957由毛泽东建立。它与主要的监狱制度和劳改营（犯人都是通过司法体系判刑）不同。劳改制度建立的初衷是打击反革命派（右派），而现在则针对轻微违法的犯罪人员，嫖妓者以及令政府难堪的请愿者。无需通过审判程序，就可以将这些人最长关押四年之久。据说这样的拘留者已有16万之多，甚至更多。</p>

<p><strong>Hard labour and free speech</strong>
<strong>强迫劳役和言论自由</strong></p>

<p>How serious the plans for reform are remains unclear. The microblog of a senior legal journalist quoted a senior legal official saying that the government would “stop using” thelaojiao system within a year. Hours later, however, Xinhua, the official news agency, reported that the system would be “reformed”, not abolished. Previous promises of reform have come to nothing; and even if detainees are to be allowed a lawyer and a judicial hearing, China’s legal system offers defendants few protections. Even so, many analysts are encouraged.</p>

<p>改革的前景尚不明朗。一位资深的法律新闻记者在微博上引用了一位高级法律官员的话说政府将在一年内停止劳教制度。然而，几个小时之后，官方喉舌新华社报道称劳教制度不是被废除，而是被改良。之前信誓旦旦的改革落得一纸空文；即便是允许劳改拘留人员有律师辩护以及司法听证，中国的法律体系仅对他们提供很少的法律保护。就算如此，许多政治观察者还是很受鼓舞。</p>

<p>Since the early 1990s there has been an implicit deal in China between rulers and ruled—that the rulers would ensure prosperity so long as the ruled did not demand too much freedom. Now many people seem to be reneging on the deal. They’ve got the prosperity, and they want the freedom too. As fast as internet censors delete critical articles and tweets, more angry middle-class people join the debate and start posting new complaints. On January 7th Yao Chen, a famous film star with more than 30m followers on her microblog, quoted Alexander Solzhenitsyn in support of the Southern Weekend journalists: “one word of truth outweighs the whole world.” Even people within the establishment are calling for political change. Last month 72 respected citizens, mostly academics and lawyers, signed a petition calling for radical reform.</p>

<p>自上个世纪90年代初开始，中国官方和民众有一个隐含的“买卖”&mdash;即只要民众不要求过多的自由，官方将会保证社会繁荣。现在似乎许多民众对此“食言”，他们已有繁荣的生活，也需要自由。批评性文章和社交网络已经发现就很快被网络审查制度删除，越来越多对此不满的中产阶级对此参与辩论，不断的刊登新的不满评论。1月7日，著名电影明星姚晨和其3000万微博粉丝引用索尔仁尼琴（俄罗斯）的一句话支持《南方周末》记者：“一句真话能比整个世界的分量还重。”甚至连党内人士也呼吁政治改革。上个月，72位德高望重的公民（大部分是学术者和律师）共同签署了一份提倡根本性改革的请愿书。</p>

<p>For liberal Westerners, ending censorship and labour camps is a moral imperative. For Mr Xi, a pragmatic authoritarian, the calculation is different, but if he knows what is good for him and his country, he will arrive at the same answer. The party’s efforts to maintain control through repression are leading to instability, not stability. Reform is risky, but avoiding it is riskier still.</p>

<p>对于西方的自由主义者，结束审查制度和劳改营是一种道德需要。对于务实派的习来说，想法却不同，但是倘若他知道怎么样才能对他和国家来说有利，他则会给出和前者一样的答案。共产党竭尽全力通过镇压来维持对人们的控制力，结果导致社会的不稳定，而非安定。改革是很冒险，但是不改革仍然是更加冒险的事情。</p>

<p>Mr Xi clearly understands the strength of popular feeling, particularly on the issue of corruption and official extravagance. As he tours the country, he has made much of avoiding the usual elaborate banquets. “Four dishes and a soup” has become the media shorthand for his more frugal, more open approach. But slogans against graft will no longer placate China’s people. Mr Xi needs to start changing the system. One photo posted online in support of the striking journalists showed a dozen men and women holding posters that read: &ldquo;Four dishes and a soup is not real reform. Press freedom is real reform.&rdquo;</p>

<p>习清楚的明白民心所向，特别是关于腐败和官员奢侈浪费的问题。当他在全国范围内视察是，尽量避免以往的奢华宴会。“四菜一汤”已成为媒体对他更为节俭和开放态度的简称。习近平需要着手改革制度。网上流传一张支持罢工记者的照片，很多人举着海报，上面写道：“四菜一汤不是真正的改革，新闻自由才是王道。”</p>

<p>Correction: The original version of this leader wrongly stated that the &ldquo;four dishes and soup&rdquo; slogan was seen on a banner in Guangzhou this week, rather than in a photo posted online. This was corrected on January 11th. We apologise for the error.</p>

<p>纠正：我们之前错误报道习的“四菜一汤”原版本来自本周广州标语，而是网上流传的照片。该错误已于1月11号纠正，我们对此表示歉意。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afghanistan’s Fearful Future-阿富汗严峻的未来局势]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/afghanistan-fearful-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T18:40:06+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/afghanistan-fearful-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>So long, buddy</strong><br/>
<strong>军事密友难说再见</strong></p>

<p>As it ponders what kind of force to leave in Afghanistan after 2014, the White House has started talking about a “zero option”</p>

<p>美国政府已掂量在阿富汗“零驻军”</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jan 12th 2013 | from the print edition</p>

<p>FOR all the smiles and handshakes, this week’s visit to Washington, DC, by Afghanistan’s president, Hamid Karzai, was a tense affair. Mr Karzai was due to meet President Barack Obama on January 11th to discuss the scope and size of America’s military presence in his country after the end of 2014, when almost all of NATO’s combat troops are due to leave.</p>

<p>阿富汗总统卡尔扎伊于这周对美国进行访问，所有微笑和握手也预示着这次紧张的会晤。卡尔扎伊1月11号会见与奥巴马总统 ，就2014年底之后美国在阿富汗驻扎军队的范围和规模展开拉锯战，北约作战部队计划在2014年底从阿富汗撤军。</p>

<p>Mr Karzai may have overplayed his hand. He knows that a bilateral security agreement with America will be vital. Yet the shrillness of some of Mr Karzai’s criticisms of America’s conduct of the war has only played into the hands of those in the administration who would like to be shot of Afghanistan. Nothing is likely to be decided for several months—the agreement does not have to be signed until November—but there is now talk of a so-called zero option, which would see the departure of all American forces next year.</p>

<p>卡尔扎伊总统也许高估了自己的影响力。他知道与美国达成双边安全协议至关重要。然而卡尔扎伊对美国战争行为的强烈谴责正好被想要彻底摆脱阿富汗的美国政府官员所利用。在接下来的几个月，双方不太可能达成一致协议—最早也要到11月份才能决定签署双边协议&mdash;但是双方正在讨论的是所谓“零驻军”，即美军将于明年从阿富汗全部撤军。</p>

<p>Until very recently it had been assumed that America would want to keep at least 20,000 of its troops in Afghanistan, bolstered by a few thousand more from NATO allies. They would be there to continue the training of Afghan National Security Forces (ANSF) and to provide essential capabilities that the Afghans still lack and have come to depend upon when fighting the Taliban alongside Western forces. These include air transport for logistics and medical evacuation, surveillance and intelligence, and close air support. In addition, America would retain special forces and armed drones to stop al-Qaeda’s leadership regrouping in Pakistan’s tribal areas or returning to the terrorist group’s old training grounds in Afghanistan itself.</p>

<p>最近，外界认为美国想要继续在阿富汗至少驻军2万人，北约盟国也会驻军数千人。他们将继续训练阿富汗国家安全部队以及加强阿富汗锁仍缺乏的重要作战能力，而且与西方军队共同对抗塔利班的时候必须依靠这种作战能力。其中包括航空物流运输，医疗后送，监控与侦查，以及近距空中支援。另外，美国将继续保留特种部队以及武装无人机阻止基地组织在巴基斯坦部落地区进行领导重组或返回在阿富汗本土的恐怖组织老训练场所。</p>

<p>For the Afghans, it seemed self-evident that America would want to keep bases in their country as a way of maintaining its influence in a region full of security threats, whether from Iran or from a failing Pakistani state armed to the teeth with nuclear weapons. They also believed assurances from the Americans and the wider world that they would not be abandoned, and that, after spending so much blood and treasure, the West would not allow Afghanistan to descend into chaos and civil war yet again.</p>

<p>对于阿富汗人来说，美国想继续保持在阿富汗的美军基地，以维持其在充满安全威胁地区（无论是在伊朗而或衰败的巴基斯坦还是充斥着核武器的地区）的影响力，这一点似乎是不言而喻的。他们也相信美国以及国际社会对他们做出的保证，即国际不会对他们置之不顾，而且已花费了大量财力以及丧失了众多作战人员，西方国家绝不会让阿富汗再一次陷入混乱和内战。</p>

<p>Mr Karzai and other Afghan political leaders are sensitive about their country’s sovereignty. But they have no intention of emulating the Iraqis, who brought an abrupt end to the presence of American troops by refusing to sign a new status of forces agreement providing immunity from prosecution for foreign soldiers.</p>

<p>卡尔伊扎和其他阿富汗政治领导人敏感的还是他们国家的主权问题。但是他们不打算效仿伊拉克（伊拉克拒绝签署一项驻美军豁免权的新美军地位协议，从而阻止美军驻军伊拉克）。</p>

<p>Yet they appear to have underestimated how fast the appetite in Mr Obama’s administration has waned for keeping a significant military presence in Afghanistan after 2014. Acute budgetary pressures; the draining of public support for involvement in a war most believe long ago to have been lost; and a belief in some quarters that drones and the intelligence networks that have been built up over the past decade are all that is needed for American security: all have chipped away at the notion of leaving behind a substantial force. On January 8th Ben Rhodes, a deputy national security adviser at the White House, confirmed that leaving no troops behind after 2014 was one of the options under active consideration.</p>

<p>然而，奥巴马政府对2014年之后继续保持在阿富汗大型驻军规模的欲望已减弱，他们似乎低估这一点。 严重的财政压力；大部分人认为长期卷入战争是奥巴马的公众支持率下降；美国一些地区普遍认为无人机和过去几十年来建立的情报网络都应该用于美国安全。1月8日， 美国副国家安全顾问Ben Rhodes证实美国正在积极讨论2014年在阿富汗零驻军的计划。</p>

<p>How much of this should come as a surprise? In the vice-presidential election debate last October, when asked about the drawdown timetable for Afghanistan, Joe Biden said: “We are leaving. We are leaving in 2014. Period.” Since Mr Biden has frequently argued for America having the lightest possible footprint in Afghanistan, his remark got little attention. But in November, when the American commander of the NATO-led international coalition, General John Allen, told his bosses at the Pentagon that he favoured a slow drawdown of combat troops over the next two years and a residual force of at least 15,000 to be provided by America alone, he was told to come back with lower estimates.</p>

<p>这一计划在多大程度上才算得上一个惊喜？在去年10月进行的副总统竞选辩论中，当问及从阿富汗撤军的时间计划时，乔-拜登说：“我们正在撤军，我们将于2014年完全撤军。”拜登不断主张在阿富汗进行少量驻军，很少有人注意他说话的内容。但是到11月，当美国北约领导的国际联军指挥官John Allen将军告诉其在国防部上司，他支持在未来两年作战部队逐渐从阿富汗撤军以及美国继续驻军1万五的军力，他了解到撤军的数目要低于估计的数目</p>

<p>Unfortunately for General Allen, at about the same time he found himself embroiled in the fallout from the sudden resignation of David Petraeus as director of the Central Intelligence Agency. It may have weakened his bargaining position. This month General Allen offered revised proposals for a force ranging from about 3,000 to 9,000. Most military experts, however, still believe that an international force of around 30,000 is needed to support the ANSF after 2014.</p>

<p>这对于Allen将军是不幸的，同时他也发现自己卷入中央情报局局长David Petraeus 突然辞职的余波当中。这也许会削弱他的谈判地位。Allen将军于这个月提交了修订后的提案，建议在阿富汗驻军3000到9000。然而，大部分军事专家坚持认为2014年之后需要3万国际部队支援阿富汗国家安全部队。</p>

<p>Yet it now appears that the troop levels under consideration by the president range between 6,000 and none. His choice of defence secretary, Chuck Hagel, a former Republican senator whom the president nominated this week, is unlikely to challenge those numbers. Mr Hagel has long been a sceptic when it comes to Afghanistan and has talked of “looking for the exit”. Even if the higher force figure gets the go-ahead, allies will be reluctant to contribute to it, concluding that America is more than halfway out of the door and that such a minimal force can achieve little beyond a small training mission in Kabul and securing the air base at nearby Bagram for limited counter-terrorism operations.</p>

<p>然而，美国总统考虑的驻军范围似乎是少于6000。奥巴马这周钦定的新任国防部长Chuck Hagel(前共和党参议员)不太可能去质疑这一数字。当涉及到阿富汗时，Hagel一直都是持怀疑态度以及讨论寻找对策。尽管更高的驻军数目得到批准，北约同盟国不愿增派各自的部队，由此可以看出美国已占一半以上的驻军力量，而且这样的小型驻军力力量除了在喀布尔进行规模小的训练任务和在巴格拉附近保护空军基地而进行有限的反恐行动之外，并不能有多少效果。</p>

<p>Despite an improving combat performance, it is highly uncertain whether the ANSF will cope. Hastily recruited and trained, the ANSF is still a work in progress. It was deliberately denied heavy weapons or much of an air force on the assumption that America would provide key “enablers” for years to come. It now takes the lead security role in about 85% of the country by population, and overall levels of violence are slightly down on previous years. But according to the Pentagon’s latest report on the progress of Afghan forces, only one out of 23 brigades is capable of operating without any outside help. It now looks as if the ANSF will be on its own in southern Afghanistan, where the Taliban is strongest, as well as in the wild east of the country which borders the lair in North Waziristan of the Haqqani network.</p>

<p>虽然阿富汗国家安全部队在作战能力上有了一定的改善，但是该部队是否能够单独作战仍然十分的不确定。经过匆忙的招募和训练，ANSF的作战能力还在不断的加强。假如美国将来向阿富汗提供关键武器，重型武器或空军部队不列入其范围。ANSF现已在全国85%人口地区的安全事务中起着重要作用，暴力事件在这几年来总体水平略有下降。但是根据美国国防部关于阿富汗部队进展的最新报告，在没有外援的情况下，仅有1/23的部队能够单独作战。现在看来ANSF在塔利班势力最强的阿富汗南部地区和与北瓦济里斯坦边境地区哈卡尼激进组织巢穴交界的东部荒野地区靠自己单独作战了。</p>

<p>As well as a security transition, a crucial political transition is also under way, with a presidential election due in 2014 (Mr Karzai is constitutionally barred from standing again). Whether Mr Obama decides on a force of 6,000 or on no troops at all, Afghans going to the polls 16 months from now will be facing much bleaker prospects than many might have expected only a few months ago.</p>

<p>进行安全工作移交工作的同时，一场重要的政权更替也在进行着，2014年阿富汗将进行总统选举（根据该国宪法，卡布扎伊不会再次连任）。关于奥巴马是否决定在阿富汗驻军6000人或是零驻军，在接下来的16个月里，阿富汗民众参与投票将面临比数月之前所期待的还要更为暗淡的前景。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
