<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: 翻译 | 小马宝嘟嘟的Mommy]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/tags/fan-yi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-19T20:10:23+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessie125.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jessie]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[niechao125@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sarkozy under formal investigation-萨科齐受到正式调查]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/sarkozy-under-investigation/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T20:52:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/sarkozy-under-investigation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>French politics</strong><br/>
<strong>法国政治</strong></p>

<p>Mar 19th 2013, 20:11 by S.M. | NEW YORK</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/03/blogs/charlemagne/20130323_eup504.jpg" alt="萨科齐受到正式调查" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>“A THUNDERBOLT”, is how one French paper greeted the news that Nicolas Sarkozy was placed under formal judicial investigation, late on March 21st. The former French president is to be investigated for “abuse of frailty”, in connection with an illegal party-financing case linked to Liliane Bettencourt, the elderly billionaire heiress to the L’Oréal cosmetics empire.</p>

<p>尼古拉斯•萨科齐于3月21日受到正式的司法调查，法国媒体将这场调查称之为“（政治界和法律界的）地震”。这位法国前总统因涉嫌收取法国亿万富翁、欧莱雅集团女继承人莉莉亚娜•贝当古的非法政治献金而受到调查。</p>

<p>The Bettencourt case, which began as a dynastic dispute and turned into a saga that mixes alleged tax evasion, a tropical island, domestic servants, fabulous wealth and political party-financing, has been underway for several years. Nearly a dozen people have been put under formal investigation, including Eric Woerth, the former treasurer of Mr Sarkozy’s UMP party and an ex-minister. Until now, it looked as if Mr Sarkozy had escaped such a fate. Last November investigating judges held him for 12 hours of questioning, as a witness in the case, but decided not to pursue a formal investigation.</p>

<p>“贝当古事件”始于家族内斗，后演变为涉及偷税漏税，热带岛屿，家佣，巨额财富以及政治竞选筹资的家族传奇，并连续上演多年。将近十几个人接受了正式调查，其中包括萨科奇所在的人民运动联盟（注释1）的前预算部长埃里克•沃尔斯。至今为止，萨科齐似乎已逃脱这一立案调查。去年11月，调查法官对萨科齐进行了12小时的问询，只是作为“需要律师在旁协助的证人”而接受问询，法官决定不对其进行正式调查。</p>

<p>On March 21st, however, investigating judges in Bordeaux questioned Mr Sarkozy again, and confronted him with various witnesses, including Mrs Bettencourt’s former butler, Pascal Bonnefoy, and other former domestic staff. This time, the investigating judge decided that he had enough evidence to go ahead.</p>

<p>然而，调查法官于3月21日在波尔多市向萨科奇进行了再一次的问询，并与多名证人进行了对质，包括贝当古女士的前管家帕斯卡•博纳富瓦以及其他几位前家佣。调查法官认为他这次已有足够的证据对萨科奇进行正式调查。</p>

<p>The case centres around whether or not Mr Sarkozy requested or received illegal sums from Mrs Bettencourt to help to finance his successful 2007 election campaign. Under French law, no private individual can contribute more than €4,600 ($5,960). Investigators are looking into allegations that €150,000 was transferred by Mrs Bettencourt’s former wealth manager to Mr Sarkozy’s party. The heiress’s former butler, whose tape of private conversations at her house triggered part of the investigation, alleges that there have been several meetings between Mr Sarkozy and the Bettencourts. The family’s mansion is in Neuilly, a posy suburb of Paris where Mr Sarkozy was mayor for many years.</p>

<p>这一事件聚焦于萨科齐是否要求或者获得贝当古女士的非法资金为自己2007年的成功竞选筹资。根据法国法律的规定，个人的政治献金不能超过4600欧元（5960美元）。贝当古的私人理财经理曾将15万欧元转入萨科齐竞选团队“金库”，调查人员正对这一事件进行调查。这位女继承人的前管家在房子里录下贝当古的秘密谈话也受到调查，该管家称萨科奇和贝当古家族会面频繁。该家族的宅邸位于巴黎的花园式纳依市，萨科齐曾在该市做了多年的市长。</p>

<p>For his part, Mr Sarkozy has denied all allegations. According to leaked testimony after his hearing by investigators last November, he said that: “The Bettencourts never gave me a penny, and I never asked anything of them”. The former president acknowledges dining with the Bettencourts at their mansion before his election, and meeting Liliane Bettencourt once afterwards, but in neither case, he says, did he request donations. Mr Sarkozy’s lawyer has called the decision to put his client under formal investigation “inconsistent” and “unfair”, and said that he will appeal.</p>

<p>萨科齐本人对这些指控加以否认。根据去年11月的调查听证会泄露的证词，他说：“贝当古家族从来没有给我一分钱，我也从未向他们问过钱”。这位法国前总统承认在他参与竞选之前曾在贝当古家族的宅邸与他们一起吃过饭，之后还和莉莉亚娜•贝当古见过一面，但是在这两次会面中绝对没有向他们提出捐款要求。萨科齐的律师表示，对萨科齐进行正式调查是“前后矛盾，不公平的决定”，他还将提出上诉。</p>

<p>As politicians digested the news, some UMP members seized on the idea of a conspiracy. Christian Estrosi, a former minister under Mr Sarkozy, denounced an “obvious hint of politics”, noting that the judge’s decision came two days after a Socialist minister, Jérôme Cahuzac, resigned in connection with a tax-fraud investigation. Henri Guaino, a deputy and former Elysée adviser to Mr Sarkozy, said that the judge had &ldquo;dishonoured&rdquo; the justice system. Others did not go this far, but did not hesitate to criticise the judicial decision. François Fillon, Mr Sarkozy’s former prime minister, declared the move “extravagant”.</p>

<p>当此事从政界中淡化，人民运动联盟的一些成员利用了“阴谋论”这一说法。萨科齐手下的前部长克里斯蒂安•埃斯特鲁斯谴责这一调查是明显的政治行为，并且指出法官是在杰罗姆•卡于扎克因涉嫌税务欺骗而离职的两天后的做出的这一决定。萨科齐的前代理顾问亨利•盖伊诺称法官是败坏国家的司法体系。虽然有些人认为没有严重到这个地步，但是也直言不讳的批判这一司法决定。萨科齐手下的前总理弗朗索瓦•菲永表示这一立案调查行为“荒谬之极”。</p>

<p>Although Mr Sarkozy is presumed innocent during a formal investigation, this sort of probe can go on for years, and can mark public opinion even if the suspect is acquitted. It comes at a particularly awkward time for the former president, who had begun to hint at a political come-back in time for the 2017 presidential election, something he had previously ruled out after his defeat last year by François Hollande. Polls even suggested that the French had begun to forgive him. One, in Paris-Match magazine, shows that, if a run-off vote were held today, 53% would back Mr Sarkozy compared with just 44% for Mr Hollande.</p>

<p>虽然一场正式调查推测萨科齐可能是无辜的，但是这一调查可以进行数年，即便犯罪嫌疑人无罪释放，多少也会受到舆论的影响。这一正式调查来的也真不是时候，这位法国前总统在之前暗示将重回政坛，参加2017年的总统竞选（去年被弗朗索瓦•奥兰德击败后，萨科齐曾否认继续参与总统竞选）。民意调查显示，法国人民也开始渐渐遗忘萨科奇。《巴黎竞赛报》上的一项民意测试显示：如果在现在进行一场决赛选举的话，萨科齐将拥有53%的支持率，而奥兰德只有44%。</p>

<p>It would be a mistake, however, to assume that this rules out for ever Mr Sarkozy’s return. He could yet be acquitted. And the French have a remarkably forgiving approach even to those found guilty of political wrongdoing. Indeed, Mr Sarkozy himself knows something about this. Alain Juppé, a one-time conservative prime minister, was once convicted for political corruption in connection with a fake jobs scandal at the Paris town hall. Mr Sarkozy brought him back into government, and appointed him foreign minister.</p>

<p>如果说这次正式调查使萨科齐重返政坛的梦破碎了，那就大错特错了，他有可能被宣告无罪。而且法国人的饶恕程度超乎想象，他们甚至能宽恕那些有政治不当行为的人。萨科齐本人对此也有所了解。前保守派总理阿兰•朱佩曾涉嫌在市政厅“设虚职领薪”的政治腐败行为被判处监禁。后来萨科齐让他回归政坛，任命为外交部长。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syria: Entanglement at home and abroad-叙利亚纠缠于国内外势力的交锋]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/Syria/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-22T20:52:08+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/22/Syria</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>The rebels are buffeted by internal ructions and regional diplomacy</strong><br/>
<strong>反对派在内乱和地区外交的双面夹击中前行</strong></p>

<p>Mar 30th 2013 | BEIRUT |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130330_MAP004_0.jpg" alt="萨科齐受到正式调查" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p><strong>Has Khatib resigned or not?</strong><br/>
<strong>哈提卜是否真正辞职了？</strong></p>

<p>EARLIER this year things had been going rather well, militarily and politically, for Syria’s eternally fractious opposition and its rebel allies. Western governments had promised to channel more aid to the new Syrian National Coalition, an umbrella group in exile, for passing on to fighters battling Bashar Assad’s regime on the ground. Moaz al-Khatib, the coalition’s head, had emerged as a cannier and more popular politician than his predecessors seeking to unite Syria’s opposition. Yet on March 24th it was thrown into disarray when Mr Khatib resigned.</p>

<p>今年早些时候，叙利亚极端反对派及其盟友在军事行动和政治上都进展得相当不错。西方国家曾承诺向流亡“伞形集团”，即新成立的叙利亚国家联盟提供更多的援助，派遣歼击机对巴沙尔•阿萨德政府进行地面打击。在力图联合叙利亚反对势力上，现任国家联盟领导人穆瓦兹•哈提卜比前任更为精明，且是一位更受欢迎的政治家。然而，3月24日哈提卜的辞职，使得叙利亚再一次陷入混乱。</p>

<p>A widely respected former preacher at one of Damascus’s biggest mosques, Mr Khatib had become frustrated by the coalition’s refusal to broaden its membership and listen to new ideas. A case in point was the recent election of Ghassan Hitto to be prime minister of an interim government. Disgruntled members of the opposition accused the Muslim Brotherhood of empowering Mr Hitto, a hitherto little-known businessman who had spent many years in Texas. Several coalition members resigned in protest, while the head of the opposition’s military wing, Selim Idriss, said he would not accept Mr Hitto’s authority.</p>

<p>曾在大马士革其中一家最大的清真寺担任牧师且广受尊敬的哈提卜对该联盟拒绝扩大阵营以及听取新的建议的行为感到很失望。最近选举加萨尼・希托为“过渡政府”总理就是这样的一个事例。愤愤不平的反对者指责“穆斯林兄弟会”授权给多年在（美国）德克萨斯州经商且迄今鲜为人知的希托。有几位联盟成员辞职以示抗议，反对势力的军事派首领塞利姆•埃德瑞斯（自由军总参谋长）表示他不会接受希托当局。</p>

<p>Mr Khatib, with an American nod, has been wary of forming an interim government, thinking that it would make it harder for the opposition to negotiate with the Syrian regime, which he had controversially declared himself open to doing. The Qataris and the Muslim Brotherhood, which apparently favour Mr Hitto, take a harder line, insisting that Mr Assad should go as a precondition for any negotiations.</p>

<p>获得美国首肯的哈提卜哈提卜在建立一个“过渡政府”上一直都是小心行事，他认为很难让反对派和叙利亚政府进行谈判，他曾经主张和叙政府公开谈判而颇受争议。大力支持希托的卡塔尔和穆斯林兄弟会对此采取更加强硬的态度，强调谈判的前提就是阿萨德下台。</p>

<p>Such turmoil could turn the coalition into “a dead body”, says Fawaz Tello, an independent member of the opposition. Rivalry between foreign backers is partly to blame, says Salman Shaikh, who heads the Qatari branch of the Washington-based Brookings Institution, a think-tank. The opposition took Syria’s official seat at an Arab League meeting on March 26th—in Qatar. Mr Khatib, however, still headed the Syrian delegation, perhaps a sign that Qatar recognises his importance.</p>

<p>一位独立的反对派成员Fawaz Tello表示，这样的骚动可能会使该联盟解体。驻华盛顿的智库布鲁金斯学会多哈研究中心主任萨勒曼•谢赫称，国外支持势力的竞争是造成这一事态的部分原因。3月26日，反对派取代叙利亚政府参加了在卡塔尔举行的阿盟峰会，但仍是哈提卜率领叙利亚代表团出席此会，这也许表明卡塔尔意识到他的重要性。</p>

<p>In any event, Western governments may find it increasingly hard to influence the fighters in the field, let alone the opposition in exile. Recently the United States and several European countries have intensified their efforts to aid the rebels. Britain and France want to arm them, despite the recent refusal of the majority of European Union members to lift the current arms embargo.
不管怎么样，西方国家也许会发现越来越难以影响到叙利亚国内的反对势力了，更不用说流亡在外的反对派了。美国和欧洲几个国家最近加大了对反对派的援助。尽管最近多数欧盟成员国拒绝解除对叙利亚的武器禁运，英国和法国还是想对其提供武器。</p>

<p><strong>Hush-hush</strong><br/>
<strong>秘密行动</strong></p>

<p>The American administration remains loth to arm the opposition directly but the CIA has, at the least, been quietly sharing intelligence and training fighters. According to an investigation by the New York Times, the agency has been involved in a covert operation to arm the rebels and has been trying to vet the groups that receive arms through Turkey and Jordan, paid for by Gulf Arabs. It has also apparently sought to block the transfer of anti-aircraft weapons, lest they fall into jihadist hands.</p>

<p>美国政府仍不愿直接向反对派提供武器，但是至少中央情报局一直在秘密地提供情报和训练飞行员。《纽约时报》的一份调查报告指出中央情报局秘密地向反对派援助武器，试图帮助让反对派通过土耳其和约旦，并且由海湾阿拉伯国家支付费用来获得武器。情报局还力图限制防空武器的转移，以免这些武器落入激进分子的手中。</p>

<p>According to Hugh Griffiths of the Stockholm International Peace Research Institute (SIPRI), a Swedish think-tank, Qatari planes started to fly in weapons in January last year. Jordan and Saudi Arabia later got involved. The number of flights increased from December, with large consignments of weapons bought in Croatia. “At a conservative estimate they have transferred at least 3,500 tonnes,” says Mr Griffiths. “If it all were to get into Syria—which it hasn’t—it would definitely change the balance of power.”</p>

<p>瑞典智库-斯德哥尔摩国际和平研究所专家休•格里菲思表示，去年一月，卡塔尔空军开始运送武器装备，沙特和约旦空军也随后加入，自12月以来，从克罗地亚采购大量武器的飞机数量不断增加。格里菲思说：“保守估计的话，他们至少已经交付3500吨武器装备，如果这些武器全部进入叙利亚-虽然目前还没有-终将打破双方的军事平衡。”</p>

<p>One aim of Western policy is to counter Mr Assad’s allies, who are still trying to bolster his regime. America’s secretary of state, John Kerry, recently failed on a trip to Baghdad to persuade the Iraqi government to stop letting Iranian planes fly weapons through Iraq’s airspace. But some say Mr Assad has been getting fewer arms from Russia and Iran than the opposition has been getting from elsewhere. Hizbullah, the Lebanese party-cum-militia, may be helping Mr Assad to create an irregular force to fight alongside his army.</p>

<p>西方政策的一个目的是反击仍在支持阿萨德政府的国家。美国国务卿约翰•克里最近在访问巴格达时，没能说服伊拉克政府阻止伊朗的运载武器飞机经过伊拉克领空。但是有人认为阿萨德从俄罗斯和伊朗获得的武器要比从别的地方得到武器的反对派少得多，黎巴嫩真主党（政党和民兵组织）也许会帮助阿萨德创建一支非正规军和他的军队一起作战。</p>

<p>Western governments may be too late to achieve their aim of boosting moderates among the increasingly Islamist-leaning rebels. Islamist fighters, including Jabhat al-Nusra, which America considers a terrorist group, are better armed and organised. Some weapons, including M79 anti-tank missiles meant for more moderate groups, seem to have fallen into the hands of Jabhat al-Nusra and other Islamists.</p>

<p>西方国家想要在日益倾向伊斯兰教的反对派中实现温和战略，可能为时已晚。美国认为包括Jabhat al-Nusra在内的伊斯兰教武装分子是恐怖主义组织，他们装备齐全且很有组织。一些武器，如原本为温和反对组织提供的M79反坦克导弹似乎已落入Jabhat al-Nusra和其他伊斯兰教武装分子的手中。</p>

<p>As international involvement grows, Syria’s neighbours are struggling to avoid being dragged in. Turkey and Jordan fear that Mr Assad may retaliate against them. On March 26th Jordan closed its main border crossing with Syria.Two days before, Israel, which has kept out of the fight, fired a missile into Syria after its troops were shot at on the Golan Heights. Clashes have broken out in the Lebanese city of Tripoli, where Lebanese Sunni fighters allied to Syria’s rebels have become bolder. As foreigners get entangled, a risk is growing that Syria’s war will spill over its borders.</p>

<p>随着国际干预的增多，叙利亚周边国家尽力避免牵涉其中，土耳其和约旦担心阿萨德会报复他们。3月26日，约旦关闭了通往叙利亚的主要边境通道。两天前，还未牵扯到这场战争的以色列向戈兰高地南部叙利亚境内发射了一枚导弹，造成叙利亚武装人员受伤。黎巴嫩（北部）城市的黎波里爆发了冲突事件，支持叙利亚反对派黎巴嫩逊尼派武装人员在该市也愈发活跃。随着国外势力的介入，叙利亚战火可能会向其周边国家扩散。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barack Obama in Israel-奥巴马首次访问以色列]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/obama-in-israel/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-19T15:22:48+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/19/obama-in-israel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>How much can the president do?</strong><br/>
<strong>奥巴马总统在巴以关系中能发挥多大的作用？</strong></p>

<p>Mar 19th 2013, 20:11 by S.M. | NEW YORK</p>

<p><img src="http://photocdn.sohu.com/20130322/Img369867836.jpg" alt="奥巴马首次访问以色列" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>ON THE eve of Barack Obama’s first trip to Israel as president, commentators are lobbing a lot of unsolicited advice his way. At the Washington Post, Jennifer Rubin recommends channeling George W. Bush, who affirmed the Jews’ biblical tie to the land and avoided all criticism of Israeli settlements in his 2008 speech to the Knesset. In a New York Times op-ed, from the opposite perspective, Rashid Khalidi insists that Mr Obama “must forthrightly oppose the occupation and the settlements and support an inalienable Palestinian right to freedom, equality and statehood.”</p>

<p>在奥巴马奔赴以色列开启他连任总统后的首次出访（注释1）之前，一些评论家对他这次“值不值得”访问提出很多的激辩。《华盛顿邮报》专栏作者珍妮弗•鲁宾（注释2）建议参照乔治•布什2008年在以色列议会演讲中提出的建议，即肯定以色列在该地区的宗教归属性，以及避免对以色列定居点的批判。而拉希德•卡里迪不支持这种观点，在《纽约时报》专栏报导中，他坚决认为奥巴马必须直截了当地反对以色列占领并定居（加沙地带）行为，支持巴勒斯坦人民享有自由，平等及国家独立的权利，这些权利是不可剥夺的。</p>

<p>The president is unlikely to tack in either direction. If his previous statements are any guide, he will steer a middle path: affirming the unshakable bond between America and Israel, affirming the rights of Israelis and Palestinians to live in peace and security, pressuring both sides to recognise the rights and interests of the other, and gamely encouraging the parties to return to the table for peace talks.</p>

<p>But such platitudes are unlikely to bear much fruit, as my colleague pointed out a few weeks ago, and all the advice is merely a projection of different perspectives on the conflict. Mr Khalidi came close to admitting the limited role the American president can expect to play when he wrote that “peace has to be made between Palestinians and Israelis, not between Mr Obama and his critics”, but he still framed the question as “what should Barack Obama&hellip;do about the Israeli-Palestinian conflict?”</p>

<p>奥巴马不可能只走其中一条“路线”。如果推断他之前的讲话内容，可以看出他将会采取“中间路线”：强调美以两国牢不可破的关系，强调巴以两国人民有享有安定生活的权利，促使两国认可对方的权利及利益，鼓励两方重新进行和平谈话。我同事在几个星期之前指出这种陈词滥调不可能有太多的效果，所有的这些建议只不过是隐射奥巴马对巴以冲突问题的不同看法而已。当卡里迪写到：“巴以两国必须实现和平，而不仅仅是奥巴马和对其批判者之间的和平”，言外之意指美国总统希望能在巴以之间发挥有限的作用，但是卡里迪还是提出来了一个问题：奥巴马在巴以冲突中应该怎么做？</p>

<p>As we explained in last week&rsquo;s paper, one thing Mr Obama can do is tell both sides that two states is the only solution. But the administration is dampening already low expectations. The president has said that his primary goal on his tour of Ramallah, Tel Aviv and Jerusalem is simply “to listen”. An adviser has stated that the president will focus on &ldquo;the broader role of public opinion in peacemaking&rdquo;. As the the Los Angeles Times reports, Mr Obama has some work to do making friends with the Israeli public:</p>

<p>就如我们在上周报道中所解释的，奥巴马能做的一件事是：告诉双方，唯一的解决办法就是两国方案。巴以对和平谈判已不抱太大希望，但是美国政府的做法更是火上浇油，奥巴马说，这次拉姆安拉市，特拉维夫市及耶路撒冷之行的主要目的仅仅是为了“倾听”。一位顾问称：奥巴马此行主要是讨论公众舆论在和平问题上发挥的更大作用。据《洛杉矶时报》报道，奥巴马得下些功夫才能和以色列民众称兄道弟。</p>

<p>A poll published Friday in the Maariv newspaper found that 38% of Israelis defined Obama&rsquo;s attitude toward their country as &ldquo;hostile&rdquo; compared with 33% who found it &ldquo;favorable.&rdquo; More worrisome for Obama, only 10% of respondents said their opinion of the president was favorable, while the rest said their view was indifferent, unfavorable or even &ldquo;hateful.&rdquo; Other surveys have found more positive views, but Obama clearly does not enjoy the sort of demonstratively warm relationship with the Israeli public that his two predecessors had.</p>

<p>周五（以色列）《晚报》刊登的民意调查显示：38%的以色列人民认为奥巴马对以的采取敌对态度，而33%则觉得他的态度是友好的。让奥巴马更加郁闷的是，参与民意调查的人中，只有10%对奥巴马的评价不错，其他的人的态度则是冷淡，或是不喜欢，有人甚至讨厌。虽然其他的问卷调查显示出更多以色列人们对他的正面评价，但是，奥巴马明显没有像前两任总统那样享受这种与以色列人们之间的友好关系。</p>

<p>But charming average Israelis is at best a first, small step toward helping the two sides settle their differences. Even popular American presidents have had a very hard time brokering deals between Israelis and Palestinians. Just ask Bill Clinton, beloved by Israelis, who visited the region four times during his presidency, choreographed the historic handshake between Yitzhak Rabin and Yasser Arafat at the White House in 1993 and invested heart and soul into 14 days of Camp David talks in 2000. In his memoir, Mr Clinton summarised the final status agreement that wasn’t:</p>

<p>但是取悦每一个以色列人充其量是帮助巴以双方解决分歧的第一小步。可是受欢迎的美国总统们都难以帮助巴以两国达成一致协议。你可以问问深受以民喜欢的比尔•克林顿，他在就任总统期间四次出访以色列，1993年精心安排伊扎克•拉宾（注释3）与亚西尔•阿拉法特（注释4）的历史性会面，2000年全心投入历时14天的戴维营会谈（注释5）。克林顿在回忆录里总结这一最终没有达成协议的会谈：</p>

<p>I said these parameters were nonnegotiable and were the best I could do, and I wanted the parties to negotiate a final status agreement within them. After I left, Dennis Ross and other members of our team stayed behind to clarify any misunderstanding, but they refused to hear complaints. I knew the plan was tough for both parties, but it was time – past time – to put up or shut up. The Palestinians would give up the absolute right of return; they had always known they would have to, but they never wanted to admit it. The Israelis would give up East Jerusalem and parts of the Old City, but their religious and cultural sites would be preserved; it had been evident for some time that for peace to come, they would have to do that. The Israelis would also give up a little more of the West Bank and probably a larger land swap than Barak’s last best offer, but they would keep enough to hold at least 80 percent of the settlers. And they would get a formal end to the conflict. It was a hard deal, but if they wanted peace, I thought it was fair to both sides.</p>

<p>“我说，这些前提条件是不容商讨的，也是我能提供的最佳方案，我希望双方在此条件之内磋商并达成一个最终决议。我离开之后，丹尼斯•罗斯和其他成员留在那里澄清任何误解，但不愿倾听他们的抱怨。我知道双方都很难接受这个方案，但是时候做出最后的抉择了，不成功则成仁（其实时机早就过去了）。巴方必须放弃让以方归还全部土地的要求，他们早就知道必须放弃这一想法，但就是不愿承认。若以色列放弃东耶路撒冷及一部分部分耶路撒冷旧城，但是他们的宗教及文化遗址还是会保留下来，实现和平的时机已非常明显，他们必须去实现它。以色列也需要放弃约旦河西岸的一些土地，或许交换的土地要比巴拉克最后要求的还要多一些，但是他们能有足够的领土供80%以上的人居住。他们能正式的结束这一冲突。虽然这份协议很难达成，但如果他们都希望和平的话，我想这对双方都是公平的。</p>

<p>The big picture hasn’t changed much since 2000: the sticking points remain Jerusalem, land swaps and the Palestinian right of return. But some details make an agreement today even less likely. Binyamin Netanyahu and Mahmoud Abbas are constrained ideologically and practically in ways Mr Rabin and Mr Arafat were not: Bibi is no peacemaker, and the division of Palestinian leadership between Mr Abbas’s Fatah in the West Bank and the militant Hamas in Gaza makes it much harder for Mr Abbas to act. The number of Jewish settlers has more than doubled, multiplying facts on the ground and complicating any agreement on territory. Instability in Egypt, turmoil in Syria and the hostility of Iran pose immediate and near-term threats which overshadow the long-simmering, existential conundrum of the Palestinian question.</p>

<p>自2000年戴维营会谈结束后，巴以局势还是没有太大改观：症结仍然是耶路撒冷的归属，土地交换以及巴勒斯坦要求以方归还土地问题。但是现在双方已不太可能在一些细节问题上达成协议了。本亚明•内塔尼亚胡和穆罕默德•阿巴斯都受到意识形态以及现实状况的约束，而拉宾与阿拉法特没有受到这种约束的影响：《圣经》不是和事佬，巴勒斯坦领导层的两派纷争（阿巴斯在西约旦河的法塔赫势力与加沙地带的哈马斯（注释6）军事力量）让阿巴斯的和谈计划难上加难。犹太定居者的数量增加了一倍多，使得两国就领土达成协议复杂化。当前埃及社会不稳定，叙利亚局势动荡，伊朗的敌视态度对世界构成直接和暂时性威胁，这也冲淡了长期以来存在的巴勒斯坦问题。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1: 这是奥巴马就任总统以来首次访问以色列，也是他连任以来的首次出访。奥巴马只在2008年以总统竞选人的身份造访过该国。</p>

<p>注释2：珍妮弗•鲁宾（Jennifer Rubin）是《华盛顿邮报》博客作者，新保守主义作家珍妮弗•鲁宾在《华盛顿邮报》上的博客“向右转”（Right Turn）既有报道又有评论，她经常触及外交政策问题，只要博客上一有的新内容似乎就能成为新闻。在《评论》杂志上发表了引发热议的《犹太人为什么憎恨萨拉•佩林》等文章后，鲁宾的名字总是伴随着争议。</p>

<p>注释3：伊扎克•拉宾：以色列政治家、军事家。1974年至1977年出任以色列总理；1992年起再次出任总理，直至1995年被刺身亡。他是首位出生于以色列本土的总理，首位被刺杀和第二位在任期间辞世的总理。1994年10月14日，阿拉法特、佩雷斯、拉宾分享诺贝尔和平奖。</p>

<p>注释4：亚西尔•阿拉法特（1929年8月27日—2004年11月11日），全名拉赫曼•阿卜杜勒•拉乌夫•阿拉法特•古德瓦•侯赛尼，毕生致力于争取恢复巴勒斯坦人民合法民族权利的正义事业。1989年，当选巴勒斯坦国总统。自1993年起是巴勒斯坦当局的领导人、自1969年起任巴解组织主席及巴解组织最大派别法塔赫的领导人，1996年，巴勒斯坦民族权力机构成立后，阿拉法特任主席，是1994年诺贝尔和平奖的获得者之一。病逝于2004年，享年75岁。</p>

<p>注释5：戴维营会谈：美国，以色列和巴勒斯坦三国就巴以冲突进行的秘密会谈，历时21天。</p>

<p>注释6：哈马斯：由“伊斯兰”、 “抵抗”、“运动” 三个阿拉伯语缩写而成。哈马斯成立于1987年12月，创始人为谢赫•艾哈迈德•亚辛。集宗教性、政治性为一体的哈马斯主张用武力消灭巴土地上的犹太复国主义者，反对同以色列和平共处，主张建立一个以耶路撒冷为首都的独立的巴勒斯坦国。哈马斯拥有正式成员２万多人及下属军事组织。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pakistan & Iran: Gas, but not the useful sort-“西气东输”非权宜之计]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/16/gas/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-16T20:42:13+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/16/gas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Gas, but not the useful sort</strong><br/>
<strong>“西气东输”非权宜之计</strong></p>

<p>Barren ground for a new pipeline
在贫瘠的土地上修建一条新天然气管道</p>

<p>Mar 16th 2013 | ISLAMABAD |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/print-edition/20130316_ASP002_0.jpg" alt="Pakistan &amp; Iran: Gas" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>IT WAS smiles and handshakes all round on Pakistan’s border with Iran, as the presidents of the two countries posed on March 11th to mark the start of the construction of the Pakistani part of a pipeline that is supposed to bring Iranian natural gas to a country starved of energy. Blackouts cripple industry and bring daily misery to Pakistani households. The new pipeline is supposed to be completed by the end of 2014.</p>

<p>3月11日，巴基斯坦和伊朗两国总统面带微笑，互相握手，在巴伊边境出席天然气管道项目巴方段（注释1）的奠基仪式，这条天然气管道计划将向巴提供伊朗天然气，以缓解能源不足危机。供电量不足（灯火管制）使巴基斯坦工业一蹶不振，人们每晚在黑暗中度日。该新管道预计在2014年底竣工。</p>

<p>Yet ending misery appears not to be among the chief political motives. Rather, Iran hopes that the project will lessen the country’s international isolation. Pakistan’s relations with its neighbour have usually been chilly. But under President Asif Ali Zardari, they have warmed. That is indicative of Pakistan’s tilt away from the United States, which lobbied the government in Islamabad against the deal and which has been pushing the idea of an alternative pipeline running from Turkmenistan, through war-ravaged Afghanistan, and then into Pakistan and India. Instead, Pakistan has also begun talks with Iran about an oil refinery at its Gulf port of Gwadar. Pakistan recently decided to hand control of the new deep-sea port there to the Chinese, another development that concerns the United States, not to mention India.</p>

<p>然而，结束巴基斯坦人民的这种困境并不是伊朗的主要政治目的，恰恰相反，伊朗希望这个项目能缓解本国的国际孤立状态。但巴总统扎尔达里加强与伊朗的关系，这也表明巴基斯坦与美国关系渐行渐远，美国反对巴基斯坦政府参与这一项目，并一直提出建设一条从土库曼斯坦出发，途径饱受战争蹂躏的阿富汗，最后到达巴基斯坦和印度的天然气管道。与此同时，巴基斯塔已开始与伊朗就在瓜达尔海湾港口建立一家炼油厂进行对话。巴基斯坦最近已决定把这个深海港口的控制权移交给中国，这一事态的发展是美国忧心忡忡，更不用说印度了。</p>

<p>The new pipeline comes from the giant South Pars gasfield and will snake into southern Pakistan. Iran has already built all but the final 320km (200 miles) of its bit of the pipeline, according to the deputy oil minister, Javad Owji. Now Pakistan has to build about 800km.</p>

<p>这条管道从（伊朗）南帕尔斯油气田进入巴基斯坦南部。伊朗石油部副部长贾瓦德•奥吉称，伊朗计划在伊方段铺设800公里管道，剩余320公里（200英里）已差不多完成。</p>

<p>That it has to pass through the insurgency-ridden province of Balochistan is only one cause for doubting its completion. It is also not clear how Pakistan, which is strapped for cash, will finance its part of the pipeline, especially if hit by international sanctions for dealing with Iran. What is more, this is the last week that the current government, led by Mr Zardari’s Pakistan Peoples Party, has in office. According to polls, the opposition party of Nawaz Sharif, who is close to Iran’s foe, Saudi Arabia, looks set to lead the next government after an election, likely in May.</p>

<p>这条管道必须经过暴乱频繁的巴基斯坦的俾路支省，这使得人们质疑管道能否顺利完成。由于资金缺乏，巴基斯坦能否提供巴方段管道建设的费用还是未知数，如果因与伊朗的合作而受到国际制裁，那就更不好说了。而且扎尔达里政府于上周完成（五年）任期。据民意调查显示，与伊朗宿敌沙特关系密切反对派纳瓦兹•谢里夫很可能在五月进行的总统大选后成为下一任政府领导人。</p>

<p>For five years, Mr Zardari’s administration has sat on the country’s energy crisis, with little action beyond get-rich-quick schemes for his cronies. The Iranian gas is not cheap. Exploiting Pakistan’s domestic reserves, which produce gas at about half the price, has been neglected. So, too, have imports of liquefied natural gas. Little has been done to deal with appalling inefficiencies in the country’s electricity system.</p>

<p>扎尔达里政府在这五年任期里对国家的能源危机坐视不理，没有付出什么行动，而是致力于为其亲信寻求一夜暴富的方法。伊朗石油价格不低，利用巴基斯坦的国内储备生产价格要低一半的石油并没有受到关注，所以进口液化天然气就更不用说了。该国的电力系统运作出奇的低效，政府也没有采取什么措施来解决这个问题。</p>

<p>But even though the announcement of the Iranian pipeline looks like a gimmick, the Americans’ idea of gas all the way from Turkmenistan is a pipe dream. Beleaguered Pakistanis have longer to wait before gas flows into homes, or blackouts are a thing of the past.</p>

<p>但是即便这次伊方管道项目的开工仪式看起来像一个小把戏，美国层想要建设一条从土库曼斯坦进入巴基斯坦的天然气管道，这想法已成白日梦了。在家家户户能够使用到天然气，或灯火管制成为过去式之前，困难重重的巴基斯坦还得需要等上一段很长的时间。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：3月11日，巴基斯坦和伊朗两国在边境举行的输气管道铺设的奠基仪式。伊朗已经完成了在本国境内的管道铺设，现在开始铺设的巴基斯坦段的总长为785公里。</p>

<p>注释2：巴基斯坦国民议会于2013年3月16日完成5年任期，现期满解散。巴基斯坦内阁也于同日解散。临时政府预计在未来几天内组建完成，新一轮大选将于5月举行。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[China's one-child policy-中国的独生子女政策]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/one-child-policy/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-15T10:02:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/03/15/one-child-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>A low-fertility trap in China&rsquo;s largest city</strong><br/>
<strong>中国最大都市-上海陷入低生育率危机</strong></p>

<p>Mar 15th 2013, 12:41 by J.P</p>

<p><img src="http://images.qianlong.com/mmsource/imghylanda/20130311/29/14978900502636975149.jpg" alt="独生子女" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>THIS week The Economist looks at the backlash against the one-child policy in China. The article points out that the bureaucracy created to run the policy, the family-planning commission, has lost its separate identity and will be merged with the health ministry into a new Health and Family Planning Commission. Normally in China (as elsewhere) power and bureaucracy go together, so this loss of bureaucratic autonomy probably signals a loss of influence, and may presage scrapping the policy itself (though officials say that won’t happen).</p>

<p>《经济学家》了解下本周有关中国独生子女政策的反对呼声。这篇文章指出中国政府撤销曾经成立的计划生育委员会（负责实施计划生育政策），将其与国家卫生部的职责整合组建国家卫生和计划生育委员会。在中国（其他国家也一样），权利和国家政府一般是联系在一起的，因此这次官僚自主性（注释1）的缺失也许意味着政府影响力的下降，或许预示这项计划生育政策终会取消（虽然官方对此予以否认）。</p>

<p>But even if it does, how much difference would ending the one-child policy make? Our report focuses on Shanghai and, by chance, China’s biggest city has a great deal of evidence that bears on that question. Most of it suggests the answer is not much.</p>

<p>但就算是取消这项政策，又会有多大的影响呢？ 我们本次报道主要聚焦上海，碰巧这座中国最大的城市（上海）拥有关于这一问题的大量事实，且大部分证明：影响并不大。</p>

<p>Under the current policy, adults who were only children themselves are permitted to have two children. According to research by Stuart Basten of Oxford University*, that provision applies to 70% of the city’s couples. In other words, the weight of the one-child policy bears down relatively lightly on Shanghai. Even so, Shanghainese couples have extremely low fertility. The city’s total fertility rate—the number of children a woman can expect to have during her lifetime—was a mere 0.64 in 2002-03 (one of the lowest rates ever recorded in peacetime) before rising slightly to a still-low 0.89 in 2007. The Shanghainese are not having larger families even though they are allowed to.</p>

<p>当前的计划生育政策允许都是独生子女的成人生第二胎，牛津大学的斯图尔特-巴斯顿的研究显示，上海有70%的夫妇都享有这项规定，换句话说，独生子女政策对上海造成的压力相对比较少。即便是这样，沪籍夫妇的生育率相当的低。该城市的总生育率 — 每个妇女一生孕育的孩子—2002至2003年仅为0.64人（创和平时期以来的最低点），2007年生育率缓慢上升，为0.89人，但仍然很低。即便这一政策使上海人能抚养更多的小孩，但是他们都不想拥有大家庭。</p>

<p>The reason is that the one-child policy seems to have changed social norms. After two generations of growing up alone, people now expect to have only one child. In 2003 and 2008, the city’s family-planning bureaucrats (the Shanghai Municipal Population and Family Planning Commission) asked 38,000 men and women aged 20-45 about how many children they wanted. They found the average ideal family size was just 1.07, with 81% of respondents saying they wanted only one child and just 15% saying they wanted a second. Admittedly, not all the respondents would necessarily be allowed a second child, and some people may have been extremely cautious about replying to any questions from some of the feared and hated bureaucrats in China. All the same, the figure is strikingly low. It is also worth noting that the share of those saying they wanted no children doubled between the two surveys, though only to 8%.</p>

<p>原因在于独生子女政策似乎改变了社会规则。自两代人都是出生在独生子女家庭，他们都希望只生一个小孩。在2003年和2008年，上海计划生育机构（上海市人口和计划生育委员会）对38000位年龄在20-45岁的男女进行了问卷调查，即他们想要几个孩子。调查发现，他们理想中的家庭平均人口为1.07人，这些人中有81%称有一个孩子就够了，只有15%的人想要两个孩子。当然，他们并不是都能准许生第二胎，有些人可能在回答中国一些疑心重重及让人反感的官方机构提出的问题时表现得相当谨慎。不管怎么说，这数字出奇地低。值得注意的一点是，在这两次调查中发现，丁克族的比例翻了一倍（尽管只占8%）。</p>

<p>This does not mean the one-child policy has had no effect (though a few demographers do argue that). Nor does it mean the policy is alone responsible for changing social norms. The cost of educating children and the difficulty of finding accommodation big enough for a family with two children are also factors. But the one-child policy does seems to have forced desired family size down further and faster than would have happened without it. And now that expectations of a small family have taken root, they may well stay low, even if the policy that gave rise to them is scrapped.</p>

<p>这并不是说独生子女政策没有什么作用（尽管一些人口学家都认为影响力不大）。也不是意味着这项政策只是为了改变社会规则。子女受教育的费用以及很难找到供一家四口居住的房子也是其中的原因。但是独生子女政策似乎迫使家庭理想规模变小，并且这一变化速度快于没有政策的情况。因为现在“小型家庭”观念已深入人心，所以即便引发这一观念的政策被取消，这些观念还有可能保持低下。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：官僚自主性：是指官僚机构或个人超越其法定的地位和职能，超越政治家的控制，在公共决策过程中发挥主导作用的现象。官僚自主性现象由来以久，可以说它是伴随着政府的产生而产生，但在现代民主制建立之前，它合理而自在地存在着，而作为一个“问题”被提出在西方则是近一百多年的事，因其对政治与行政二分原则的背离而受到关注的，近几十年已发展成为所有现代政府面临的普遍而又难以克服的问题，并成为政治学研究的重点之一。政治学研究官僚自主性问题的主要动因在于揭示官僚制与民主政治之间的悖论问题，即官僚制因民主政治发展的需要而建立，但其发展本身实际上又损害着民主政治发展的基本原则。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
