<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: 翻译 | 小马宝嘟嘟的Mommy]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/tags/fan-yi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T08:26:25+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessie125.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jessie]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[niechao125@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social-impact bonds-社会效益债券]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/social-impact-bonds/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T19:40:16+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/23/social-impact-bonds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Commerce and conscience</strong><br/>
<strong>商业与良知</strong></p>

<p>A new way of financing public services gains momentum
一种公共服务融资方法取得很大发展</p>

<p>Feb 23rd 2013 |From the print edition</p>

<p>AT HALF past six on a wet morning in central London, the city is already busy. Baristas are setting up inside coffee shops. Office cleaners are at work. And outreach teams from charities and local councils are on early-morning shifts to find rough sleepers and get them off the streets.</p>

<p>早上六点半，烟雨笼罩的伦敦市中心已开始熙熙攘攘，人们已忙碌起来。咖啡师在咖啡厅着手准备营业，办公室的清洁员打扫卫生，慈善外展队和市政委员会进行早班执勤，寻找露宿人员，并将其带离街道。</p>

<p>For most teams the priority is to find people who are newly homeless and help find them accommodation quickly, before they become settled in a pattern. Kath Sims, an outreach worker for a homelessness charity called St Mungo’s, is not looking for the new arrivals, however. She is trying to locate people in a specific group of 415 habitual rough sleepers, with the aim of prising them from the streets.</p>

<p>对于大多数外战队来说，最重要的是找到无家可归的人们，在他们习惯这种居无定所的生活模式之前，尽快帮助他们安顿下来。Kath Sims是（伦敦）无家可归者慈善组织“圣芒戈魔法”的一名外展工作者，她并没有寻找新的露宿者，而是试图找到415名当地习惯性露宿者形成的一个特殊群，让他们不再流浪街头。</p>

<p>That puts her at the front line of a big financial experiment, too. Her work is being funded by an instrument called a “social-impact bond” (SIB), which promises returns to private investors if social objectives are met. The bond raised £5m ($8m) from investors, to be shared between St Mungo’s and another organisation called Thames Reach (responsible for another 400-or-so homeless people).</p>

<p>这也使她站在一项大型金融试验的最前线，她所进行的工作得到了一家名为“<a href="http://china.cat.com/cat/images/Cat_logo.gif%E2%80%9D%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E7%9A%84%E8%B5%9E%E5%8A%A9%EF%BC%8C%E8%AF%A5%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E6%89%BF%E8%AF%BA%EF%BC%8C%E5%A6%82%E6%9E%9C%E8%BE%BE%E5%88%B0%E7%A4%BE%E4%BC%9A%E7%9B%AE%E6%A0%87%EF%BC%8C%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E6%8A%95%E8%B5%84%E8%80%85%E5%B0%86%E4%BC%9A%E8%8E%B7%E5%BE%97%E5%9B%9E%E6%8A%A5%E3%80%82%E8%BF%99%E5%AE%B6%E5%80%BA%E5%88%B8%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E4%BB%8E%E6%8A%95%E8%B5%84%E8%80%85%E8%9E%8D%E8%B5%845%E7%99%BE%E4%B8%87%E8%8B%B1%E9%95%91%EF%BC%88%E7%BA%A68%E7%99%BE%E4%B8%87%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%83%EF%BC%89%EF%BC%8C%E4%B8%BA">http://china.cat.com/cat/images/Cat_logo.gif%E2%80%9D%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E7%9A%84%E8%B5%9E%E5%8A%A9%EF%BC%8C%E8%AF%A5%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E6%89%BF%E8%AF%BA%EF%BC%8C%E5%A6%82%E6%9E%9C%E8%BE%BE%E5%88%B0%E7%A4%BE%E4%BC%9A%E7%9B%AE%E6%A0%87%EF%BC%8C%E4%B8%AA%E4%BA%BA%E6%8A%95%E8%B5%84%E8%80%85%E5%B0%86%E4%BC%9A%E8%8E%B7%E5%BE%97%E5%9B%9E%E6%8A%A5%E3%80%82%E8%BF%99%E5%AE%B6%E5%80%BA%E5%88%B8%E6%9C%BA%E6%9E%84%E4%BB%8E%E6%8A%95%E8%B5%84%E8%80%85%E8%9E%8D%E8%B5%845%E7%99%BE%E4%B8%87%E8%8B%B1%E9%95%91%EF%BC%88%E7%BA%A68%E7%99%BE%E4%B8%87%E7%BE%8E%E5%85%83%EF%BC%89%EF%BC%8C%E4%B8%BA</a> “圣芒戈魔法”和另一家名为“泰晤士关爱”（负责400人左右的无家可归者）共享用。</p>

<p>The cash will fund a three-year programme, the success of which is measured by everything from the number of nights that the rough sleepers spend on the streets to their visits to hospital. As targets are met, payments will flow to investors from the Greater London Authority (GLA), the SIB’s commissioning body.</p>

<p>这些钱能资助一个为期3年的计划项目，其成功与否取决于露宿者晚上留宿街头的天数及去医院就诊的次数。如果达到预期的目标，“社会效益债券”机构的委托方即伦敦政府将会付款给投资者。</p>

<p>The arrangement suits all parties. The rough sleepers are frequent users of government services, including accident-and-emergency wards. Cutting their number should save the GLA enough money to fund payments to investors if goals are met. At a time when public spending is under pressure, the taxpayer stumps up only if results are achieved. Investors have the prospect of a return to entice them, of up to 6.5% if targets are met.</p>

<p>这一安排适用所有机构。露宿者是政府公共服务（包括事故急诊室）的“频繁用户”。如果达到目标，露宿者人数的减少是英国政府有足够的资金支付投资者。当公共支出面临不足之时，纳税人只要在目标实现的前提下进行纳税。投资者们有望得到收益回报来吸引纳税人的资金，如果目标实现的话，收益回报可能会高达6.5%。</p>

<p>As for organisations like St Mungo’s, they get upfront funding for a longer period than they would in a normal government contract. That matters. One of the people Ms Sims checks in on is a long-time rough sleeper with a history of violence, a drug habit to feed and a string of prison sentences. She needs time to build a relationship with him: stopping to say hello and roll him a cigarette is part of that process. Coaxing him into a hostel is not the right approach: he’d only end up in a fight and have an eviction on his record, which would make it much harder eventually to place him in permanent accommodation. The priority is to get his drug abuse under control by shifting him to methadone, at which point it becomes possible to think about accommodation. It all takes time.</p>

<p>对于如“圣芒戈魔法”的机构来说，相比一个正常的政府合同，他们获得前期资金的周期较长。这一点很重要。西姆女士探访了一位长期留宿街头的流浪者，他是一个有着暴力前科且多次服刑的吸毒人员。她需要时间和他建立一种关系：对其问好和为其卷烟是建立关系的一部分。哄劝他前往旅社不是一个权宜之策：这样会使他最终以打架的罪名而受到驱逐，从而更难为他安置到长期的住处。首先帮助他服用美沙酮，使他的毒品滥用得到控制，这样才有可能考虑安居的问题，这一过程需要时间。</p>

<p>The homelessness SIB is one of 14 that have now been issued or are in development in Britain, which pioneered the instrument back in 2010 with a bond funding a prisoner-rehabilitation programme in Peterborough. The idea is also winning fans elsewhere. New York city launched a SIB last year tackling recidivism among inmates at Rikers Island prison; Goldman Sachs is among the investors. Work is under way on three more American SIBs, one in New York state and two in Massachusetts. Jeffrey Liebman, a Harvard University professor who is providing technical assistance on all three, has just invited applications from other state and local governments to receive help setting up SIBs: 28 applied.</p>

<p>无家可归 “社会效益债券”现已发行或在英国得到发展，该债券早在2010年开创这一先河，即在（加拿大）彼得伯勒赞助一项“囚犯康复计划”。这一想法也获得世界各地人们的支持。纽约市在去年启动了“社会效益债券”计划，处理雷克岛监狱囚犯的再犯问题。高盛集团也在投资者之列。现已有另外三项美国“社会效益债券”工作正在进行中：一项位于纽约州，两项在马萨诸塞州。对这三项计划提供技术援助的哈佛大学教授杰弗里•利布曼邀请其他州和地方政府的申请接受建立“社会效益债券”机构：已有28个州和地方政府获得批准。</p>

<p>And there is rising emerging-market interest in SIBs, where they go under the name of “development-impact bonds”. According to Michael Belinsky of Instiglio, a start-up devoted to designing SIBs in poor countries, there is less scope for government savings to pay back investors in emerging markets because social safety nets are thinner. So international-development agencies are more likely to act as sponsors. Mr Belinsky is working on potential SIBs in India, to improve educational outcomes for girls in Rajasthan, and in Colombia, to reduce teenage-pregnancy and school drop-out rates.</p>

<p>“社会效益债券”以“发展影响债券”之名面向社会，有着不断上涨的新兴市场利率。致力于在贫穷国家建立“社会效益债券”的新兴公司Instiglio的迈克尔•别林斯基称：因为社会保障体系日趋薄弱，政府偿还新兴市场投资者的储蓄没有多大盈余。因此国际发展机构更有可能作为赞助商。别林斯基先生现在印度致力于即将发展的“社会效益债券”，为（印度）拉贾斯塔邦和哥伦比亚的女孩改善教育成果，降低少女怀孕率和学校失学率。</p>

<p>As the buzz about SIBs increases, the questions will also become more searching. Projects which take many years to have an effect (the impact of pre-school education on university admissions, say) will not interest investors. Good data are crucial for measuring outcomes: that can be a problem in developing countries.</p>

<p>随着有关建立“社会效益债券”的风声四起，问题也变得更加的透彻。需要多年才能产生效果的项目工程（例如，学前教育对大学招生录取的影响）不会引起投资者的兴趣。良好数据对衡量成果至关重要：在发展中国家可能是一个问题。</p>

<p>The hardest questions concern the returns that investors will demand if SIBs are to attract serious amounts of money. The Peterborough SIB dangles an annualised return of up to 13% if reoffending rates go down by enough; but investors lose everything if recidivism does not fall by at least 7.5%. That sort of equity risk is not going to appeal to many, acknowledges Nick Hurd, the British government minister for civil society. “SIBs need to evolve so that they become more like a debt instrument.”</p>

<p>涉及回报最难的问题是：如果“社会效益债券”吸引大量资金，投资者将会有所要求。如果再犯率大大下降，彼得伯勒“社会效益债券”机构年回报率达到13%，这一点仍有待推敲，如果再犯率高于7.5%以上，投资者将血本无归。很多人对这种股票风险不“感冒”。英国政府民间团体部长尼克赫德表示： “社会效益债券”需要改进，变得更像一种类似的债务证券。</p>

<p><strong>Sibling rivals</strong><br/>
<strong>同行竞争对手</strong></p>

<p>Signs of just such an evolution are becoming apparent. The New York city SIB reinforces Goldman’s reputation for dealmaking as much as its philanthropic image: a guarantee from Bloomberg Philanthropies, a foundation, caps the amount of money the bank can lose if recidivism targets are not met. Some think this model, with philanthropists ensuring that a portion of investors’ principal is returned, is the way to bring in more capital.</p>

<p>这种改善的迹象变得越来越明显。位于纽约市的“社会效益债券”机构加强高盛公司交易声誉和慈善形象：彭博慈善基金会的担保规定了再犯率没有达到预期目标的银行损失上限额。有些人认为，除了慈善家确保投资者的一部分本金得到回报，这一模式是吸引更多资金的方法。</p>

<p>Another option is to blend the returns from SIBs with other assets. Allia, a British charity devoted to social investment, this month made a SIB available to retail investors for the first time. Of every £1,000 invested, £780 goes to a fixed-rate loan to a social-housing provider, which when repaid with interest will give investors their money back. Another £200 will go into an SIB providing therapeutic support to troubled children in Essex, which offers investors the potential for a return. (Fees eat up the other £20.) These are still early days, but big ideas often start small.</p>

<p>另一个方法是融合“社会效益债券”机构的收益和其他资产。英国慈善机构“阿利亚”致力于社会投资，这个月首次将“社会效益债券”提供给零售投资者。每1千英镑的投资资金里，780英镑作为固定利率贷款提供给社保住房提供者，一旦本息和利息得到偿付，投资者的资金将会得到偿还。剩余的200英镑将投入“社会效益债券”，为埃塞克斯的困难儿童提供医学治疗，这也为投资者提供了潜在的收益。（还有20英镑用于其他费用）现在还是起步阶段，千里之行，始于足下。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blood bars and debt bunnies-血库酒吧和债务兔]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/02/blood-bars/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-02T18:00:56+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/02/02/blood-bars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Clicking your way to sound financial habits</strong><br/>
<strong>一路点击，测试理财习惯</strong></p>

<p>Feb 2nd 2013 | ATLANTA |From the print edition</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130202_FNP002_0.jpg" alt="Blood bars and debt bunnies" /></p>

<p>ONE way to learn basic financial literacy is to sit in a classroom and listen to someone drone on about retirement accounts and financial charges. An alternative is to run a nightclub for vampires and rake in money by getting your customers the blood-type they want, while socking away enough cash for retirement (a long one—you’re undead).</p>

<p>学习理财常识的一个方法就是：坐在教室听某人喋喋不休的讲着退休金账户以及融资费用相关的知识。另外一种方法就是开一家吸血鬼夜总会，给他们提供所需血型，大捞一笔，或者为退休存储足够的钱（如果你是不死之身，这一过程遥遥无期）。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>That is the scenario of “Bite Club”, a video game created by Doorways to Dreams (D2D) Fund, a Boston-based non-profit organisation that works on improving the finances of low- and middle-income consumers. D2D released its first prototype game in 2009, and its library now totals five games. The other titles include “Farm Blitz”, which challenges players to harvest crops from Uncle Felix’s farm while staving off ravenous rabbits (the bunnies represent debt); and “Celebrity Calamity”, in which you are a money manager who keeps a Hollywood starlet happy by keeping her out of debt.</p>

<p>这是波士顿非盈利机构“梦想基金之门”（注释1）创作的电子游戏《齿痕俱乐部》中的情节，该基金会致力于改善中低收入消费者的财政状况。2009年，“通向梦想基金会”发布首个《虐杀原形》游戏（注释2），其程序库现共有5种游戏。其他游戏分别是《农场闪电战》，即要求玩家避开贪婪的兔子（兔子代表债务），从菲利克斯大叔的农场收获农作物，以及《名人灾难》，在这个游戏中，玩家扮演一位资金经理人，让一位好莱坞新秀远离债务困扰，使其无后顾之忧。</p>

<p>Although the scenarios vary, the five games share a few crucial attributes. Like “Angry Birds” or “Tetris”, they have no extensive back stories and are easy to understand. They rely on real-world decision-making: players have to spend on necessary expenses while also saving for retirement and avoiding excess debt.</p>

<p>尽管情节迥异，但是这五种游戏有着共同的一些重要特性。如《愤怒的小鸟》和《俄罗斯方块》，不需要许多的背后操作指示，容易理解。这些游戏依靠现实决策：玩家必须花费必要的费用，同时也得为退休储蓄资金，避免过多债务。</p>

<p>Most importantly, they seem to help people. D2D recently released a paper showing the results of a randomised control trial, in which participants took financial self-confidence and financial-knowledge quizzes and then were assigned either to play “Farm Blitz” or to read a pamphlet before taking the quizzes again. Both groups improved on both measures, and although the pamphlet-readers improved more, the comparison that matters most is not whether D2D’s games are better than reading, but whether they are better than nothing.</p>

<p>最为重要的是，他们似乎是在帮助人们。“梦想基金之门”最近发布的一份报告显示了一次随机控制试验的结果，在这个试验中，参与者进行金融自信和金融知识测试，然后被指定玩《农场闪电战》或者阅读说明书之后再进行测试。在这两种测试措施中，两组都有所改善，尽管说明书阅读者的改善效果更佳，这一比较最重要的不在于“梦想基金之门”游戏要比阅读说明书要好，而是在于聊胜于无。</p>

<p>Financial-literacy education can be off-putting, after all. D2D’s least popular game is “Refund Rush”, in which players act as a financial adviser helping clients decide what to do with their tax refunds. Wouldn’t you choose vampires?</p>

<p>毕竟，金融扫盲教育可能会使人感到不愉快，“梦想基金之门”欢迎指数最低的游戏《职业理财师》，玩家扮演一位金融顾问，帮助客户决定如何利用退税资金。为何不选择吸血鬼呢？</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1：D2D FUND（“梦想基金之门”）官网：<a href="http://www.d2dfund.org/">http://www.d2dfund.org/</a></p>

<p>注释2：虐杀原形（Prototype）是由Radical Entertainment公司制作，美国动视发行于2009年6月9日发售的开放式科幻自由动作冒险游戏，玩家将扮演一位由病毒集合成的生物体，还要与军队和各种变异生物战斗。该游戏以高超的自由度、肆无忌惮破坏与暴力杀戮为卖点，应用Radical公司独立开发的钛合金游戏引擎IV(Titanium game engine)，游戏的风格类似侠盗猎车手系列，不同的是，当主角抓住路人或敌人时便可以吸收他们的记忆、能力，甚至能变成他们的样子以进行伪装。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[War crimes in Bangladesh: Justice delayed-孟加拉迟来的正义]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/26/bangladesh/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-26T20:34:09+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/26/bangladesh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>A first conviction for war crimes sparks controversy</strong><br/>
<strong>首次对战争罪行的定罪引发争议</strong></p>

<p>Jan 26th 2013 |From the print edition</p>

<p>MORE than 41 years after the deaths of as many as 3m people in Bangladesh’s war of secession from Pakistan, a Bangladeshi war crimes tribunal has given its first verdict. On January 21st it sentenced Abul Kalam Azad to death in absentia for genocide and murder committed during the nine-month war in 1971. The verdict is being seen as a victory for Sheikh Hasina, the prime minister, and her Awami League party, who have made the tribunal an important part of her term in office.</p>

<p>孟加拉国曾为脱离巴基斯坦引发的战争致使3百万人丧生，近42年过去了，如今孟加拉国战争军事法庭对此进行首次裁决，于1月21日对阿布尔•卡拉姆•阿扎德在1971年长达9个月的战争中所犯下的种族灭绝及屠杀罪行进行缺席审判，处以死刑。这一裁决是谢赫•哈西娜总理和其人民联盟政党的一大胜利，也是她任期的一个重要垫脚石。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Bangladeshis have waited decades for justice and the aims of the tribunal are broadly popular, but critics say the process has been politicised to target allies of Sheikh Hasina’s main opponent, former prime minister Khaleda Zia, head of the Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP). There have also been questions raised about its impartiality. In December The Economist reported on contacts by e-mail and Skype between the presiding judge in one of the tribunals and a lawyer in Belgium who was not an official part of the court. The judge eventually resigned and was replaced. The verdict on Mr Azad came from a second tribunal.</p>

<p>孟加拉国期待正义已有数年，这次审判的目的深得人心，但是批评家认为这次裁决已被政治化，主要是针对谢赫•哈西娜&lt;注释1>即孟加拉国国民党领导人兼前总理卡莉达•齐亚。也有很多人质疑这次裁决的公正性。12月，《经济学家》报道此次审判的其中一位首席法官和一位比利时律师联系的邮件内容及网络电话记录，这位法官最终辞职，被取而代之。第二次开庭审判对阿扎德做出了判决。</p>

<p>In the judgment Mr Azad is described as a former leader of the youth wing of Jamaat-e-Islami, a party in then East Pakistan and still Bangladesh’s biggest Islamic party today. Its youth wing was the main source of paramilitaries supporting Pakistan in its efforts to prevent East Pakistan’s independence. Its members are alleged to have abducted and murdered dozens of civilians. Mr Azad himself was accused of killing at least 12 Hindus and of rape. He then became a well-connected political figure in Bangladesh and a presenter of popular Islamic television programmes. He fled the country last year and is believed to be in Pakistan.</p>

<p>这次审判把阿扎德描绘成伊斯兰大会党青年团前领导人，该党现在仍然是孟加拉国（当时的东巴基斯坦）最大的伊斯兰党。这一青年团是协助巴基斯坦人们阻止东巴基斯坦独立的主要辅助军事力量，该团成员也涉嫌绑架和杀害许多的平民百姓。阿扎德本人被指控杀害至少12名印度教徒和涉嫌强奸罪。他曾在孟加拉国政治界人脉广泛，而且在炙手可热的伊斯兰电视节目中担任主持人。他去年叛逃孟加拉国，据信现在在巴基斯坦。</p>

<p>Mrs Zia has found it impossible to distance her party from Jamaat-e-Islami, an ally whose support the BNP needs if it is to win the election, likely to take place this year. Among the ten other senior figures to be tried are two leading party officials, both former ministers in Mrs Zia’s 2001-2006 government. It may be that almost the entire leadership of Jamaat will be hanged before the polls. So, too, may two members of Mrs Zia’s party, including one of her close advisers. Sheikh Hasina will hope that the taint of 1971 will make the BNP-Jamaat alliance so toxic to voters that she will be returned to power.</p>

<p>齐亚（音译）&lt;注释2>觉得不能和伊斯兰教党对立，因为孟加拉国国民党需要该联盟的支持，来赢得今年可能举行的大选。十个被审的高级官员中有两个是大会党重要官员，而且还曾在齐亚2001—2006年执政期间担任部长。整个伊斯兰教领导势力也许会在民意调查之前全军覆没，齐亚所在党派的两名成员（其中包括她的一名亲密顾问）也不例外，谢赫•哈西娜希望1971年发生的这一丑闻来丑化该国国民党-伊斯兰教联盟，从而使自己获得选民的支持，重新执掌政权。</p>

<hr />

<ol>
<li><p>谢赫•哈西娜（1947年9月28日－），孟加拉国总理。哈西娜出生于1947年9月28日，其父是孟加拉国国父、首任总统谢赫•穆吉布•拉赫曼。1975年8月15日，其父穆吉布及其亲属15人在首都达卡被政变军人杀害，哈西娜当时在德国，幸免于难。1981年2月，哈西娜出任孟加拉国人民联盟主席。1996年6月23日至2001年7月15日之间出任孟加拉国总理。2008年12月29日举行的议会大选中，哈西娜率领的人民联盟取得压倒性胜利，再次获得组阁权.</p></li>
<li><p>卡莉达•齐亚 (Begum Khaleda Zia)1945年8月15日生于迪纳杰布尔县。她是孟加拉国前总统齐亚•拉赫曼的遗孀。卡莉达•齐亚1960年入苏伦德拉纳特学院学习，1963年毕业。在校期间与齐亚•拉赫曼上尉结婚。1981年5月齐亚•拉赫曼遇刺后，她开始步入政坛，1982年3月任孟加拉国民族主义党副主席，1984年当选主席。1991年2月，民族主义党在大选中获胜。同年3月，卡•齐亚出任总理，成为孟加拉国历史上第一位女总理。2001年10月至2006年10月再次出任总理。</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Literary protest-笔尖上的抗议]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/literary-protest/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-23T21:20:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/23/literary-protest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Local hero</strong><br/>
<strong>平民英雄</strong></p>

<p>Jan 23rd 2013, 4:52 by The Economist | CHENGDU</p>

<p><img src="http://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/original-size/images/2013/01/blogs/analects/li_chengpeng.jpg" alt="李承鹏" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>LIU XIAOBO, China’s first non-Tibetan to wear the laurel of a Nobel peace prize, languishes quietly in prison and the artist known as Ai Weiwei remains better known abroad than at home. But a number of writers and activists whose names are not so famous overseas have gained a following within China by daring to tweak the tail of the Communist Party.</p>

<p>中国第一位获得诺贝尔和平奖的非藏族人士刘晓波遭囚禁，静度余生，著名艺术家艾未未在国内的知名度远不及在国外的知名度。但是许多不为国外所熟知得作家和积极份子敢于揭共产党所短，在国内得到许多人的支持。</p>

<p>Perhaps chief among them would be a former sports writer, Li Chengpeng. Mr Li has recently stirred up a storm with a new book, a collection of sharp essays on his country’s social ills, titled “Everybody in the World Knows”. During his book tour in January he was adored by fans, physically attacked by enemies and finally silenced by the Chinese authorities.
也许这些人的主要人物是前体育记者李承鹏，他的新书《全世界人民都知道》是一部辛辣批判国家的社会弊病的杂文集，在最近弄得满城风雨。在一月的新书签售活动中，李承鹏受其粉丝追捧，遭受其反对者掌掴并被官方禁言。</p>

<p>Thousands of supporters turned out to meet the author in Chengdu, Beijing and Shenzhen. On January 12th, just before he appeared at his book signing in Chengdu, Mr Li took stock of the rules that had been laid down for the aunch and announced to his 6.7m followers on Sina Weibo, China’s homegrown version of Twitter: “I am not allowed to speak, not allowed to give opening remarks, I am not even allowed to say ‘Happy New Year’ or ‘Thank you all’.” Instead he wore a black mask over his mouth and the words “I love you all” written on his shirt. The crowd roared its approval, and snapped up copies of his book by the armload.</p>

<p>数千支持者在成都，北京和深圳参加他的签售会。1月·12日，在他四川签售活动之前，李仔细估量了上级对这次签售活动所下达的命令并在微博（中国版本的推特）上对其670万关注者说：“不准我说话，不准我致开场白，连“新年好，谢谢你们”也不准说。”他戴着黑色的口罩，在其衬衫上写上“我爱你们”。在场的群众欢呼雀跃，抢购李的新书。</p>

<p>His reception in Beijing went less smoothly. One self-proclaimed Maoist hurled a kitchen knife at him and another punched him in the face. Some Maoists regard him as a traitor for his criticism of the Communist Party. Since the knife-throwing incident, and then further cries of treason at the book signing in Shenzhen, the police have chosen to rein in Mr Li. He texted at least one reporter to explain that he was being taken away for a chat. An appearance in Guangzhou was cancelled suddenly.</p>

<p>他的北京签售也并非顺利。一位自称“毛派”人士向李扔了一把菜刀，某人对李脸上“赠”与一掌掴。李承鹏因批判共产党，一些“毛派”人士将其视为“汉奸”。自深圳新书签售会上的掷刀事件以及随即的“卖国贼”呼声，警方已对李进行约束，李对相关记者证实他被警方带走就此事做笔录，广州签售会也随即取消。</p>

<p>Li Chengpeng is no stranger to threats and government pressure. Working as a sportswriter from the early 1990s to 2009, he chose to focus his reporting on rampant corruption, which culminated in a book called “Chinese Football: The Inside Story”, published in January 2010. It detailed match-fixing and bribery across the country and brought down the wrath of incensed trainers, “patriotic readers” and government censors. Chen Yiming, trainer of the Chongqing Lifan club, brought a suit against Mr Li in 2009 which succeeded in incurring fines of 200,000 yuan ($32,000) and the demand that the published reporting be retracted publicly. Mr Li refused and in December 2012 a Guangzhou court overturned the verdict on appeal. Mr Li was found not guilty of libel, and his articles were judged to be “non-damaging”. Mr Chen, the trainer, was forced to pay the court’s costs.</p>

<p>李承鹏对威胁和政府的施压已是司空见惯。他在90年代初期至2009年期间从事体育专栏报道工作，之后专注报道泛滥猖獗的腐败问题，其书名为《中国足球内幕》，并在2010年1月出版，详细介绍了全国假球和贿赂等黑幕，以及打击了足球教练员的嚣张气焰。重庆力帆俱乐部教练陈亦明（音译）在2009年对李提起诉讼，成功胜诉，法院判决李赔偿20万（3.2万美元）以及召回发表的足球报道，李承鹏拒绝接受并上诉，2012年12月广州一家法院推翻这一判决。李承鹏被判无罪，其文章也被判定对社会没有危害。教练员陈不得不支付法庭费用。</p>

<p>Seasoned at playing the provocateur, Mr Li moved from reporting on sport to writing essays on politics and society soon after the Sichuan earthquake of 2008, which killed more than 80,000 people. His writing on the struggles of common people after the disaster brought his work to a whole new audience of internet-savvy young Chinese. He went on to publish a novel in 2011, “Li Kele Protests Demolitions”. Mr Li’s “Li Kele” was an immediate hit; the descriptions of ordinary people who united together to fight faceless forces and venality propelled the writer into the arms of a more organized new audience: China’s advocates for social reform.</p>

<p>李承鹏在发起“挑衅活动”方面有丰富的阅历，他以前是报道体育新闻，自2008年四川地震（死亡人数超过8万）之后不久，他开始写有关政治方面的文章。对老百姓灾后重建的文章吸引了网络上一批全新的年轻人。2011年，他出版了一本小说《李可乐抗拆记》，这本书立即得到强烈反响，小说中关于平民老百姓联合反抗幕后势力以及腐败问题的描绘使作者融入一个更有组织的新读者群：中国社会改革的提倡者。</p>

<p>Later that year Mr Li announced that he would be running for public office in Chengdu as an independent. Although his election campaign was never allowed to get under way (candidates for office are carefully screened by the Communist Party and eventually Mr Li failed his background check), he gained a new degree of credibility. Here, it seemed, was a man who would back up his words with actions.</p>

<p>此后，李承鹏宣布将以无党派身份竞选成都公职，虽然他的竞选活动尚未允许启动（竞选公职的候选人需经过共产党的精心筛选，李最终未能通过背景调查），但是他的公信力获得提高，还有一个人似乎用行动来支持李的文章。</p>

<p>At the book launch in Chengdu, an elderly man named Liu Shahe sat behind Mr Li. Mr Liu is one of the signatories of Charter 08, the document demanding a list political reforms that Liu Xiaobo, the Nobel laureate, was jailed for drafting. Mr Li tweeted Mr Liu’s words to him—“You man of words, just keep writing”—and said the encouragement from the older man had reduced him to tears.</p>

<p>在成都签售会上，一位老人站在李的身后，老人名叫流沙河，是《08宪章》的其中一名签署者，该文书要求一系列政治改革，诺贝尔奖获得者刘晓波因起草该文书被囚禁。李在微博上写上刘对他所说的话-“文人，写下去即是胜利”&ndash;称这位老人的鼓励让他潸然泪下。</p>

<p>Since that relatively thunderous clap, Mr Li seems to be trying to turn his volume down a notch. In a recent post to his blog, Li said he would be doing small events only, with friends and close supporters. He urged his fans to pay attention to “bigger issues like corruption, food safety and pollution” and not focus so much on the man and his book.</p>

<p>自这件事传得沸沸扬扬以来，李似乎试图低调行事。他在最近的一篇博文中说他将和朋友以及联系密切的支持者只做做小事，他敦促粉丝们关注更大的问题，如腐败，食品安全，污染问题等，而不是过多集中在他本人和这本书上。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia: Forced into extinction-沙特阿拉伯：被迫消失在历史长河中]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/21/arabia-forced-extinction/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-21T19:40:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/21/arabia-forced-extinction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Forced into extinction</strong><br/>
<strong>被迫消失在历史长河中</strong></p>

<p>Jan 21st 2013, 18:25 by M.R. | CAIRO</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/blogs/pomegranate/20130126_map501.jpg" alt="沙特阿拉伯：被迫消失在历史长河中" /></p>

<!--more-->


<p>LIKE much that moves in Twitter-mad Saudi Arabia these days, it started with a single message. A lady in Dammam, the hub of the oil industry on the kingdom’s Gulf coast, tweeted a complaint from a local shopping mall. Agents of the Committee for the Promotion of Virtue and Prevention of Vice (CPVPV), she said, were causing an unpleasant scene. The government-salaried vigilantes, a bearded auxiliary police force familiarly known to Saudis as the Hayaa, had marched officiously into an educational exhibit featuring plaster models of dinosaurs, turned off the lights and ordered everyone out, frightening children and alarming their parents.</p>

<p>就如最近发生在沙特阿拉伯的诸多事件，“推特”（音译）的流行，导火线源于一条的简单短信，这一事件也不例外。沙特阿拉伯波斯湾海岸石油港口达曼一位女士在“推特”发微博抱怨当地一家购物商场。她称“扬善惩恶委员会”工作人员是造成这一不愉快场面的罪魁祸首。政府自卫队即沙特人们熟识的满面胡须的“哈亚”辅助警察队强行进入以一家恐龙石膏模型的教育展览馆，切断电源并命令所有人离开，使孩子们及其父母受到惊吓。</p>

<p>It was unclear precisely why the religious police objected to the exhibit, which apparently had been innocently featured at shopping centres across the Gulf for decades. Malls are one of the few public spaces where Saudis mix socially, and so often draw the Hayaa’s attentions. Gone, however, are the days when its agents can go about their business unchallenged.</p>

<p>该展览馆数年来一直是海湾购物中心的特色,宗教警察为何反对这一展览的目的尚不明确。购物中心是沙特人社交的少数公共场所之一，因此常常引起哈亚的注意。然而，委员会工作人员不能像以前那样为所欲为的处理问题了。</p>

<p>Within minutes of the incident, a freshly minted Arabic Twitter hashtag, #Dammam-Hayaa-Closes-Dinosaur-Show, was generating scores of theories about their motives. Perhaps, suggested one, there was a danger that citizens might start worshipping dinosaur statues instead of God. Maybe it was just a temporary measure, said another, until the Hayaa can separate male and female dinosaurs and put them in separate rooms. Surely, declared a third, one of the lady dinosaurs had been caught in public without a male guardian. A fourth announced an all-points police alert for Barney the Dinosaur, while another suggested it was too early to judge until it was clear what the dinosaurs were wearing.</p>

<p>在该事件发生后的几分钟之内，一个刚形成的阿拉伯“推特”主题标签（达曼-哈亚关闭恐龙展览）引起了关于宗教警察动机的诸多推测。有人认为，人们可能会信仰恐龙而不是上帝，这也许是一种危险；有人则觉得这也许只是哈亚区分雌雄恐龙且将其放置在单独房间之前的一个临时措施；当然，还有人则宣称一只雌性恐龙在没有雄性恐龙的“保护下”，当众被人”猥亵“；另外还有人称所有现场警察提高对巴尼恐龙标本警惕，而其他人认为，除非先了解恐龙身上穿的什么，现在评价还为时过早。</p>

<p>Several contributors injected bawdy innuendo into their comments. Noting that one of the displays showed a dinosaur riding on the back of another, one message declared that this was obviously sexually suggestive and possibly could be categorised as a Westernising influence. &ldquo;I confess,&rdquo; declared one penitent, &ldquo;I saw a naked dinosaur thigh and felt aroused.&rdquo; Another tweet provided this helpful tip to the suspicious CPVPV: &ldquo;No, no, that long thing is a tail!&rdquo;</p>

<p>一些撰稿人在其评论中进行了含沙射影的讽刺，指出有一展览展出一只恐龙骑在另外一只恐龙的背上，有人称这明显暗含“性”内容且可能将其视为是西化影响的产物。一位忏悔者称，”我承认，赤裸的恐龙大腿刺激了我的性欲望。“另外一位”推特“用户向多疑的扬善惩恶委员会提供了一条有益的建议：”不，不，这长长的东西是一条尾巴！“</p>

<p>But most of the messages singled out the religious police for ridicule. &ldquo;They worried that people would find the dinosaurs more highly evolved than themselves,&rdquo; explained one. &ldquo;It’s the Hayaa that should be stuffed and mounted so future generations can learn about extinct animals,&rdquo; quipped another. This message adopted a more pedantic tone: &ldquo;Dinosaurs are a paleontological life form from an ancient geological era, and our clerics are a paleontological life form from an ancient social era.&rdquo; &ldquo;Hello? Stone Age? We have some of your people; can you please come and collect them?&rdquo; pleaded one tweep. Another wrote: &ldquo;If the dinosaurs were still alive they’d be saying, thank God for extinction.&rdquo;</p>

<p>但是大多数评论针对宗教警察进行讥讽。有人解释，”他们担心人们会发现恐龙的进化比他们更加高级“。有人嘲弄，”哈亚应该有标本让后代了解灭绝了的动物。“ 这条评论采用了一种更为迂腐的语气：”恐龙是古老地质时期的一种古生物学生命形式，牧师是古老社会时期的一种古生物学生命形式。一位“推特”用户“ 用恳求的语气讽刺 ，”拜托？石器时代？我们有你们的一些同类，麻烦来“收了”他们？“另一位用户写道：“如果恐龙现在还没有灭绝，它们可能会为自己的灭绝而感谢上帝。”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
