<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: 翻译 | 小马宝嘟嘟的Mommy]]></title>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/tags/fan-yi/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-15T07:54:49+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jessie125.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jessie]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[niechao125@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[French foreign policy-法国外交政策]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/french-foreign-policy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-14T21:20:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/french-foreign-policy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>France goes it alone</strong>
<strong>单打独斗</strong></p>

<p>Jan 14th 2013, 12:55 by S.P. | PARIS</p>

<p><img src="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/full-width/images/2013/01/blogs/charlemagne/20130119_eup501.jpg" alt="法国外交政策" /></p>

<p>FRANCE’S decision on January 11th to begin air strikes against Islamist rebel positions in northern Mali, designed to prevent “the establishment of a terrorist state” in the African Sahel, contained elements of both surprise and familiarity.</p>

<p>法国决定1月11日对马里北部伊斯兰叛军武装据点进行空袭，以防止其在非洲撒赫勒地区建立恐怖主义国家，这一决定让人惊讶但又有点司空见惯。</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The surprise was that François Hollande, the president, a Socialist leader not known for decisive action and untried in foreign policy, moved so swiftly to order French fighter jets and attack helicopters into action. Using warplanes based both in France and at a permanent base in nearby Chad, the French struck rebel columns advancing out of Islamist-held territory and towards Bamako, the Malian capital. Such groups, with ties to Al-Qaeda, have ruled a big chunk or the north of the country since March last year.</p>

<p>众所周知，法国总统兼社会党领导人弗朗索瓦•奥朗德在外交政策上不会果断决策和进行尝试性行动，而这次却迅速下令法国战机和武装直升机采取行动，这一反差让人感到惊讶。从法国开赴的战机以及乍得长期基地的战机击败驻在伊斯兰教领土至马里首都巴尔科地区的叛军部队。自去年3月以来，这个与基地组织联系的团伙占领马里大部分地区或北部地区。</p>

<p>The French government said that the weekend air strikes, part of what it is calling Operation Serval, had stopped the rebel advance, and helped Malian troops to regain control of the town of Konna; one French helicopter pilot was killed, as well as a dozen Malian soldiers. On the third day of air attacks, the French struck deeper into Islamist-held territory, targeting training camps and logistics centres, according to Jean-Yves Le Drian, the defence minister.</p>

<p>法国政府称周末进行的“薮猫行动”空袭打击已阻止叛军进攻，帮助马里军队收复了孔纳镇，已有一位法国直升机飞行员和十二位马里士兵丧生。法国国防部长Jean-Yves Le Drian称，空袭的第三天，法军深入挺进伊斯兰教地区，重点打击叛军训练营和物流中心，</p>

<p>France has certainly been in the lead in pushing for intervention in Mali. It drafted a United Nations Security Council resolution authorising a regional African force to retake rebel-held territory, which was unanimously passed last October. In a speech to a gathering of French-speaking countries in Senegal last year, Mr Hollande spoke of a “reign of terror” in Islamist-held Mali, where sharia law has been applied in the furthest north.</p>

<p>法国在马里军事干预中的确是有着主导作用。法国向联合国安理会起草的一份授权非洲当地军队收复叛军占据领土的决议在去年10月一致通过。去年在塞内加尔举行的法语国家会议中，奥朗德谈到在伊斯兰教为主的马里的恐怖统治，伊斯兰教反政府已深入马里最北方地区。</p>

<p>France is particularly worried that the Sahel is becoming an “Afrighanistan”—a breeding ground for terrorists—thanks in part to modern weaponry that has spilled over the Libyan border after the war there. France itself has been named as a target by groups based in the north; this weekend, as the airstrikes began, the country raised its terrorism-security alert. France also has strong commercial links in the region, and there are currently eight French hostages in the region.</p>

<p>法国特别担心萨赫勒会成为另外一个“阿富汗”—恐怖分子的温床—部分原因是自利比亚边境爆发的内战来，先进武器的使用向周边国家扩展。法国已成为马里北部的基地叛军报复目标，当空袭开始之时，法国在上周末提高反恐预警方案级别。法国在该地区拥有强大经济联系，反叛组织目前仍挟持8名法国人质。</p>

<p>Mr Hollande had also made clear that it was no longer his intention for France to play the role of regional gendarme, stepping in to prop up African rulers, as has been the post-colonial tradition under the Fifth Republic. “Françafrique”, the opaque mesh of military, political and commercial ties, was over, he claimed. Until now, he had insisted that France would offer no more than logistical support to a regional African force, which was laboriously being put together for this autumn.</p>

<p>奥朗德也明确表示，他不会采取像法兰西第五共和国的后殖民主义传统以往的做法，让法国充当该地区军队进行军事干预帮助非洲统治者已不再是他的意愿。他称，政治与商业相交织的不透明网即“法国非洲”已成过去式。他至今仍坚称法国将只对非洲地区军队提供后勤支持，并在今年秋季全力付诸实施。</p>

<p>Which is where the element of familiarity comes in. The reality, acknowledged privately by French sources, is that the Malian army was in no position to defend itself, and that the regional African force was going to take too long to assemble. Mr Hollande stressed that France was acting with a legal international mandate, and responding to a request from the Malian president, Dioncounda Traoré, for help. In a diplomatic breakthrough of sorts, Algeria granted France permission for fighter jets to fly over its airpace. Laurent Fabius, the French foreign minister, said on French radio on January 13th that France had little choice but to intervene urgently or Islamist forces might have made it to Bamako, with “appalling consequences”.</p>

<p>让人司空见惯的是：法国媒体私下报道马里军队没有能力进行自卫，而且非洲地区部队要花很多时间组建军队，这都是现实情况。奥朗德强调法国是在国际合法授权下采取行动，以及对马里总统迪翁昆达•特拉奥雷请求支援做出的回应。阿尔及利亚准许法国战机飞越其领空，这是外交上的一大突破。法国外交部长洛朗-法比尤斯在1月13日通过法国电台表示法国别无选择，只能迅速采取军事干预，否则伊斯兰叛军可能会在巴马科造成可怕的后果。</p>

<p>However much successive French presidents say that they want to put an end to post-colonial intervention in Africa, with few other takers for the job it usually proves irresistible at some point. Nicolas Sarkozy, Mr Hollande’s predecessor, had also promised a new era, only to end up sending the French army to help Côte d’Ivoire forcibly evict Laurent Gbagbo, the loser of that country’s presidential election, from office.</p>

<p>尽管法国总统连续强调法国想要结束在非洲的后殖民主义干预，而对于其他少数国家来说，这种干预在某些情况下通常是不可抗拒的，法国前任总统尼古拉-萨科奇曾许诺开辟一个新的时代，结果只是派遣法国军队帮助科特迪瓦共和国强迫总统竞选落选者洛朗•巴博下台。</p>

<p>The question now is how long the French are prepared to intervene, and how fast a decent African ground force can realistically be put in place. Mr Fabius has talked of “a question of weeks” for the French intervention. He insists that its main contribution is air power, with the few hundred special forces on the ground essentially picking out and verifying targets.</p>

<p>现在的问题是法国准备多长时间进行干预以及训练尚可的非洲陆军多快实现真正作战。法比尤斯表示法国干预是数周以来一直讨论的问题。他坚称空军以及主要辨认和确认袭击目标的几百地面特种部队是作战的主力。</p>

<p>It is the West African force that is supposed to carry out the operation to retake the north from Islamists, and there is a regional meeting on this now set for January 19th. Initial contingents of troops from Senegal, Niger, Burkina Faso, Nigeria and Togo are now due to arrive within days. But a properly manned force will still take time to assemble. France, in short, is likely to find itself involved for a while. Mr Hollande himself has stated that the French operation would last “as long as necessary”.</p>

<p>据称西非军队将采取行动从“伊斯兰教支持者”手中夺取北部地区，1月19号将对此问题举行地区会议。塞内加尔，尼日尔，布基纳法索，尼日利亚以及多哥首次派遣军队，将在几天之内到达北部地区作战。但是组建一支组织严密的军队仍需时日。总之，法国可能还将继续进行干预。奥朗德本人也表示只要有需要，法国将会一直采取行动。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reform in China-中国改革任道重远]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/12/reform-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-12T20:10:36+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/12/reform-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Great expectations</strong>
<strong>殷切希望</strong></p>

<p>Reform of the labour-camp system would be welcome, but more change must come soon</p>

<p>劳教制度改革实属欢迎，但必须有更多实质性改革</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jan 12th 2013 | from the print edition</p>

<p>IN HUNAN province last August, Tang Hui was sentenced to 18 months in a labour camp. Her crime was to demand tougher sentences for the men who had kidnapped and raped her 11-year-old daughter. In days gone by, Ms Tang would simply have disappeared. In the age of the microblog, thousands of incensed middle-class people took up her case. Ms Tang was released, and on January 7th the government announced that the labour-camps system would be reformed (see article).</p>

<p>去年8月，湖南（信访妈妈）唐辉被判处8个月劳教。她的罪名是要求对绑架且强奸她11岁女儿的罪犯处以更重刑法。在过去，像唐辉这样的事件很容易被淡化。但在微博无处不在的时代，数以千计愤世嫉俗的中产阶级在微博上评论她的事件。因此唐女士被提前释放，中国政府在1月7号宣布对劳教制度进行改革。</p>

<p>In Guangzhou last week, allegedly under orders from the provincial propaganda chief, an editorial in Southern Weekend, a reformist newspaper, was altered before publication (seearticle). The original called for greater respect of rights enshrined in China’s constitution. The amended version praised the Communist Party and China’s political system. Some Southern Weekend staff called a strike and supporters protested outside their offices in Guangzhou, chanting political slogans of a sort rarely heard on China’s streets since 1989.</p>

<p>上周，广州省委宣传部长私自命令改动“改革系”报社《南方周末》的一篇社论（即新年贺词）。原文章呼吁尊重中国宪法规定的权利（《中国梦，宪政梦》）。删改版本则赞美共产党和中国政治制度。《南方周报》一些员工为此进行罢工，支持者则在广州的报社总部办公楼外抗议声援，举起了自1989年以来在中国很少看到的政治标语。</p>

<p>In both cases, officials were in breach of China’s constitution. There is nothing new in that. The officials were behaving as officials always have behaved. What has changed is the expectations of the people. Chinese citizens can no longer be pacified with economic growth and slogans. They want political change. How Xi Jinping, China’s new leader, manages this growing pressure for reform will determine his, and his country’s, future.</p>

<p>中国官员在这两起事件中违反了国家宪法，这已不是什么新鲜事了。官员们的处理方法一如既往，而变化的则是老百姓的期待。中国公民不再满足于经济增长这样的口号，他们期待政治改革。中国新任领导人习近平如何处理这种不断上升的改革压力将决定着他和中国的命运。</p>

<p>The justice system and press freedom are core reasons for popular discontent. China’s reform-through-labour system, known as laojiao, was set up in 1957 under Mao Zedong. It is different from the mainstream system of prisons and labour camps whose inmates have been through the judicial system. Established to deal with “counter-revolutionaries”, laojiao camps are now reserved for petty criminals, prostitutes and petitioners who embarrass the government. People can be locked up in them without trial for up to four years. They are said to hold around 160,000 detainees, possibly more.</p>

<p>司法体制和出版自由是民怨的重要原因。中国的劳动改造制度-劳教，于1957由毛泽东建立。它与主要的监狱制度和劳改营（犯人都是通过司法体系判刑）不同。劳改制度建立的初衷是打击反革命派（右派），而现在则针对轻微违法的犯罪人员，嫖妓者以及令政府难堪的请愿者。无需通过审判程序，就可以将这些人最长关押四年之久。据说这样的拘留者已有16万之多，甚至更多。</p>

<p><strong>Hard labour and free speech</strong>
<strong>强迫劳役和言论自由</strong></p>

<p>How serious the plans for reform are remains unclear. The microblog of a senior legal journalist quoted a senior legal official saying that the government would “stop using” thelaojiao system within a year. Hours later, however, Xinhua, the official news agency, reported that the system would be “reformed”, not abolished. Previous promises of reform have come to nothing; and even if detainees are to be allowed a lawyer and a judicial hearing, China’s legal system offers defendants few protections. Even so, many analysts are encouraged.</p>

<p>改革的前景尚不明朗。一位资深的法律新闻记者在微博上引用了一位高级法律官员的话说政府将在一年内停止劳教制度。然而，几个小时之后，官方喉舌新华社报道称劳教制度不是被废除，而是被改良。之前信誓旦旦的改革落得一纸空文；即便是允许劳改拘留人员有律师辩护以及司法听证，中国的法律体系仅对他们提供很少的法律保护。就算如此，许多政治观察者还是很受鼓舞。</p>

<p>Since the early 1990s there has been an implicit deal in China between rulers and ruled—that the rulers would ensure prosperity so long as the ruled did not demand too much freedom. Now many people seem to be reneging on the deal. They’ve got the prosperity, and they want the freedom too. As fast as internet censors delete critical articles and tweets, more angry middle-class people join the debate and start posting new complaints. On January 7th Yao Chen, a famous film star with more than 30m followers on her microblog, quoted Alexander Solzhenitsyn in support of the Southern Weekend journalists: “one word of truth outweighs the whole world.” Even people within the establishment are calling for political change. Last month 72 respected citizens, mostly academics and lawyers, signed a petition calling for radical reform.</p>

<p>自上个世纪90年代初开始，中国官方和民众有一个隐含的“买卖”&mdash;即只要民众不要求过多的自由，官方将会保证社会繁荣。现在似乎许多民众对此“食言”，他们已有繁荣的生活，也需要自由。批评性文章和社交网络已经发现就很快被网络审查制度删除，越来越多对此不满的中产阶级对此参与辩论，不断的刊登新的不满评论。1月7日，著名电影明星姚晨和其3000万微博粉丝引用索尔仁尼琴（俄罗斯）的一句话支持《南方周末》记者：“一句真话能比整个世界的分量还重。”甚至连党内人士也呼吁政治改革。上个月，72位德高望重的公民（大部分是学术者和律师）共同签署了一份提倡根本性改革的请愿书。</p>

<p>For liberal Westerners, ending censorship and labour camps is a moral imperative. For Mr Xi, a pragmatic authoritarian, the calculation is different, but if he knows what is good for him and his country, he will arrive at the same answer. The party’s efforts to maintain control through repression are leading to instability, not stability. Reform is risky, but avoiding it is riskier still.</p>

<p>对于西方的自由主义者，结束审查制度和劳改营是一种道德需要。对于务实派的习来说，想法却不同，但是倘若他知道怎么样才能对他和国家来说有利，他则会给出和前者一样的答案。共产党竭尽全力通过镇压来维持对人们的控制力，结果导致社会的不稳定，而非安定。改革是很冒险，但是不改革仍然是更加冒险的事情。</p>

<p>Mr Xi clearly understands the strength of popular feeling, particularly on the issue of corruption and official extravagance. As he tours the country, he has made much of avoiding the usual elaborate banquets. “Four dishes and a soup” has become the media shorthand for his more frugal, more open approach. But slogans against graft will no longer placate China’s people. Mr Xi needs to start changing the system. One photo posted online in support of the striking journalists showed a dozen men and women holding posters that read: &ldquo;Four dishes and a soup is not real reform. Press freedom is real reform.&rdquo;</p>

<p>习清楚的明白民心所向，特别是关于腐败和官员奢侈浪费的问题。当他在全国范围内视察是，尽量避免以往的奢华宴会。“四菜一汤”已成为媒体对他更为节俭和开放态度的简称。习近平需要着手改革制度。网上流传一张支持罢工记者的照片，很多人举着海报，上面写道：“四菜一汤不是真正的改革，新闻自由才是王道。”</p>

<p>Correction: The original version of this leader wrongly stated that the &ldquo;four dishes and soup&rdquo; slogan was seen on a banner in Guangzhou this week, rather than in a photo posted online. This was corrected on January 11th. We apologise for the error.</p>

<p>纠正：我们之前错误报道习的“四菜一汤”原版本来自本周广州标语，而是网上流传的照片。该错误已于1月11号纠正，我们对此表示歉意。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Afghanistan’s fearful future-阿富汗严峻的未来局势]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/afghanistan-fearful-future/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-11T18:40:06+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/11/afghanistan-fearful-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>So long, buddy</strong>
<strong>军事密友难说再见</strong></p>

<p>As it ponders what kind of force to leave in Afghanistan after 2014, the White House has started talking about a “zero option”</p>

<p>美国政府已掂量在阿富汗“零驻军”</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Jan 12th 2013 | from the print edition</p>

<p>FOR all the smiles and handshakes, this week’s visit to Washington, DC, by Afghanistan’s president, Hamid Karzai, was a tense affair. Mr Karzai was due to meet President Barack Obama on January 11th to discuss the scope and size of America’s military presence in his country after the end of 2014, when almost all of NATO’s combat troops are due to leave.</p>

<p>阿富汗总统卡尔扎伊于这周对美国进行访问，所有微笑和握手也预示着这次紧张的会晤。卡尔扎伊1月11号会见与奥巴马总统 ，就2014年底之后美国在阿富汗驻扎军队的范围和规模展开拉锯战，北约作战部队计划在2014年底从阿富汗撤军。</p>

<p>Mr Karzai may have overplayed his hand. He knows that a bilateral security agreement with America will be vital. Yet the shrillness of some of Mr Karzai’s criticisms of America’s conduct of the war has only played into the hands of those in the administration who would like to be shot of Afghanistan. Nothing is likely to be decided for several months—the agreement does not have to be signed until November—but there is now talk of a so-called zero option, which would see the departure of all American forces next year.</p>

<p>卡尔扎伊总统也许高估了自己的影响力。他知道与美国达成双边安全协议至关重要。然而卡尔扎伊对美国战争行为的强烈谴责正好被想要彻底摆脱阿富汗的美国政府官员所利用。在接下来的几个月，双方不太可能达成一致协议—最早也要到11月份才能决定签署双边协议&mdash;但是双方正在讨论的是所谓“零驻军”，即美军将于明年从阿富汗全部撤军。</p>

<p>Until very recently it had been assumed that America would want to keep at least 20,000 of its troops in Afghanistan, bolstered by a few thousand more from NATO allies. They would be there to continue the training of Afghan National Security Forces (ANSF) and to provide essential capabilities that the Afghans still lack and have come to depend upon when fighting the Taliban alongside Western forces. These include air transport for logistics and medical evacuation, surveillance and intelligence, and close air support. In addition, America would retain special forces and armed drones to stop al-Qaeda’s leadership regrouping in Pakistan’s tribal areas or returning to the terrorist group’s old training grounds in Afghanistan itself.</p>

<p>最近，外界认为美国想要继续在阿富汗至少驻军2万人，北约盟国也会驻军数千人。他们将继续训练阿富汗国家安全部队以及加强阿富汗锁仍缺乏的重要作战能力，而且与西方军队共同对抗塔利班的时候必须依靠这种作战能力。其中包括航空物流运输，医疗后送，监控与侦查，以及近距空中支援。另外，美国将继续保留特种部队以及武装无人机阻止基地组织在巴基斯坦部落地区进行领导重组或返回在阿富汗本土的恐怖组织老训练场所。</p>

<p>For the Afghans, it seemed self-evident that America would want to keep bases in their country as a way of maintaining its influence in a region full of security threats, whether from Iran or from a failing Pakistani state armed to the teeth with nuclear weapons. They also believed assurances from the Americans and the wider world that they would not be abandoned, and that, after spending so much blood and treasure, the West would not allow Afghanistan to descend into chaos and civil war yet again.</p>

<p>对于阿富汗人来说，美国想继续保持在阿富汗的美军基地，以维持其在充满安全威胁地区（无论是在伊朗而或衰败的巴基斯坦还是充斥着核武器的地区）的影响力，这一点似乎是不言而喻的。他们也相信美国以及国际社会对他们做出的保证，即国际不会对他们置之不顾，而且已花费了大量财力以及丧失了众多作战人员，西方国家绝不会让阿富汗再一次陷入混乱和内战。</p>

<p>Mr Karzai and other Afghan political leaders are sensitive about their country’s sovereignty. But they have no intention of emulating the Iraqis, who brought an abrupt end to the presence of American troops by refusing to sign a new status of forces agreement providing immunity from prosecution for foreign soldiers.</p>

<p>卡尔伊扎和其他阿富汗政治领导人敏感的还是他们国家的主权问题。但是他们不打算效仿伊拉克（伊拉克拒绝签署一项驻美军豁免权的新美军地位协议，从而阻止美军驻军伊拉克）。</p>

<p>Yet they appear to have underestimated how fast the appetite in Mr Obama’s administration has waned for keeping a significant military presence in Afghanistan after 2014. Acute budgetary pressures; the draining of public support for involvement in a war most believe long ago to have been lost; and a belief in some quarters that drones and the intelligence networks that have been built up over the past decade are all that is needed for American security: all have chipped away at the notion of leaving behind a substantial force. On January 8th Ben Rhodes, a deputy national security adviser at the White House, confirmed that leaving no troops behind after 2014 was one of the options under active consideration.</p>

<p>然而，奥巴马政府对2014年之后继续保持在阿富汗大型驻军规模的欲望已减弱，他们似乎低估这一点。 严重的财政压力；大部分人认为长期卷入战争是奥巴马的公众支持率下降；美国一些地区普遍认为无人机和过去几十年来建立的情报网络都应该用于美国安全。1月8日， 美国副国家安全顾问Ben Rhodes证实美国正在积极讨论2014年在阿富汗零驻军的计划。</p>

<p>How much of this should come as a surprise? In the vice-presidential election debate last October, when asked about the drawdown timetable for Afghanistan, Joe Biden said: “We are leaving. We are leaving in 2014. Period.” Since Mr Biden has frequently argued for America having the lightest possible footprint in Afghanistan, his remark got little attention. But in November, when the American commander of the NATO-led international coalition, General John Allen, told his bosses at the Pentagon that he favoured a slow drawdown of combat troops over the next two years and a residual force of at least 15,000 to be provided by America alone, he was told to come back with lower estimates.</p>

<p>这一计划在多大程度上才算得上一个惊喜？在去年10月进行的副总统竞选辩论中，当问及从阿富汗撤军的时间计划时，乔-拜登说：“我们正在撤军，我们将于2014年完全撤军。”拜登不断主张在阿富汗进行少量驻军，很少有人注意他说话的内容。但是到11月，当美国北约领导的国际联军指挥官John Allen将军告诉其在国防部上司，他支持在未来两年作战部队逐渐从阿富汗撤军以及美国继续驻军1万五的军力，他了解到撤军的数目要低于估计的数目</p>

<p>Unfortunately for General Allen, at about the same time he found himself embroiled in the fallout from the sudden resignation of David Petraeus as director of the Central Intelligence Agency. It may have weakened his bargaining position. This month General Allen offered revised proposals for a force ranging from about 3,000 to 9,000. Most military experts, however, still believe that an international force of around 30,000 is needed to support the ANSF after 2014.</p>

<p>这对于Allen将军是不幸的，同时他也发现自己卷入中央情报局局长David Petraeus 突然辞职的余波当中。这也许会削弱他的谈判地位。Allen将军于这个月提交了修订后的提案，建议在阿富汗驻军3000到9000。然而，大部分军事专家坚持认为2014年之后需要3万国际部队支援阿富汗国家安全部队。</p>

<p>Yet it now appears that the troop levels under consideration by the president range between 6,000 and none. His choice of defence secretary, Chuck Hagel, a former Republican senator whom the president nominated this week, is unlikely to challenge those numbers. Mr Hagel has long been a sceptic when it comes to Afghanistan and has talked of “looking for the exit”. Even if the higher force figure gets the go-ahead, allies will be reluctant to contribute to it, concluding that America is more than halfway out of the door and that such a minimal force can achieve little beyond a small training mission in Kabul and securing the air base at nearby Bagram for limited counter-terrorism operations.</p>

<p>然而，美国总统考虑的驻军范围似乎是少于6000。奥巴马这周钦定的新任国防部长Chuck Hagel(前共和党参议员)不太可能去质疑这一数字。当涉及到阿富汗时，Hagel一直都是持怀疑态度以及讨论寻找对策。尽管更高的驻军数目得到批准，北约同盟国不愿增派各自的部队，由此可以看出美国已占一半以上的驻军力量，而且这样的小型驻军力力量除了在喀布尔进行规模小的训练任务和在巴格拉附近保护空军基地而进行有限的反恐行动之外，并不能有多少效果。</p>

<p>Despite an improving combat performance, it is highly uncertain whether the ANSF will cope. Hastily recruited and trained, the ANSF is still a work in progress. It was deliberately denied heavy weapons or much of an air force on the assumption that America would provide key “enablers” for years to come. It now takes the lead security role in about 85% of the country by population, and overall levels of violence are slightly down on previous years. But according to the Pentagon’s latest report on the progress of Afghan forces, only one out of 23 brigades is capable of operating without any outside help. It now looks as if the ANSF will be on its own in southern Afghanistan, where the Taliban is strongest, as well as in the wild east of the country which borders the lair in North Waziristan of the Haqqani network.</p>

<p>虽然阿富汗国家安全部队在作战能力上有了一定的改善，但是该部队是否能够单独作战仍然十分的不确定。经过匆忙的招募和训练，ANSF的作战能力还在不断的加强。假如美国将来向阿富汗提供关键武器，重型武器或空军部队不列入其范围。ANSF现已在全国85%人口地区的安全事务中起着重要作用，暴力事件在这几年来总体水平略有下降。但是根据美国国防部关于阿富汗部队进展的最新报告，在没有外援的情况下，仅有1/23的部队能够单独作战。现在看来ANSF在塔利班势力最强的阿富汗南部地区和与北瓦济里斯坦边境地区哈卡尼激进组织巢穴交界的东部荒野地区靠自己单独作战了。</p>

<p>As well as a security transition, a crucial political transition is also under way, with a presidential election due in 2014 (Mr Karzai is constitutionally barred from standing again). Whether Mr Obama decides on a force of 6,000 or on no troops at all, Afghans going to the polls 16 months from now will be facing much bleaker prospects than many might have expected only a few months ago.</p>

<p>进行安全工作移交工作的同时，一场重要的政权更替也在进行着，2014年阿富汗将进行总统选举（根据该国宪法，卡布扎伊不会再次连任）。关于奥巴马是否决定在阿富汗驻军6000人或是零驻军，在接下来的16个月里，阿富汗民众参与投票将面临比数月之前所期待的还要更为暗淡的前景。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[America's fiscal challenges-美国财政挑战]]></title>
    <link href="http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/07/american-fiscal-challenges/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T19:19:56+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jessie125.github.io/blog/2013/01/07/american-fiscal-challenges</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>It&rsquo;s not them, it&rsquo;s you</strong>
<strong>根源不在他们，而是你们自己</strong></p>

<p>Jan 7th 2013, 20:23 by R.M. | WASHINGTON, DC</p>

<p>ANN LYNN of Scottsdale, Arizona, wrote a letter to the New York Times last week that sums up the thinking of many Americans regarding the country&rsquo;s fiscal outlook.</p>

<p>来自（美国）亚利桑那州的斯科茨代尔城市的ANN LYNN上周向纽约时报写了一封信，信中总结了许多美国人对国家财政前景的想法。</p>

<p>“However much we raise taxes and/or try to cut spending, we will constantly be thwarted if Washington does nothing about government waste. I would have no objection to paying taxes (within reason) if only I did not know that so much goes right down the drain!”</p>

<!--more-->


<p>“如果国家对政府浪费熟视无睹,无论我们再怎么提高税收和（或）努力削减开支，我们也会不断遭受财政危机困扰。要是我不知道这么多开支全部都付之东流，我本来是愿意在合理范围内向政府缴税的。”</p>

<p>My holidays were spent with a political crowd who share Ms Lynn&rsquo;s aversion to &ldquo;government waste&rdquo;, which they would define broadly to include money spent on welfare queens and food-stamp fraudsters, as well as unnecessary government workers and unwanted public services. In fact, they would include most of the stimulative outlays enacted under Barack Obama. This wasteful spending needs to be reined in or America will go the way of Greece, they say.</p>

<p>我的整个假期就是与一群政治人士讨论关于Lynn反感“政府浪费”的问题，他们广泛定义“政府浪费”，其中包括福利皇后（注释1）和冒领食品券行为以及不必要的政府员工开支和公共设施服务。事实上，奥巴马制定的大多数刺激性支出都可以被划入这种所谓的“政府浪费”。他们指出，如果这种浪费性的支出行为不得到控制，美国将重蹈希腊的覆辙。</p>

<p>You can see why many Americans are opposed to raising revenue in an effort to close the budget gap. They don&rsquo;t like the things they believe their money is buying. Fortunately, as the economy recovers, their money is buying less of these things. In fact most of the story behind America&rsquo;s recent string of large deficits is slump-related, a result of lower tax revenues due to the underperforming economy, and increased spending on things like unemployment insurance, food stamps and Medicaid. As the economy recovers, revenues increase and safety-net spending declines, the debt-to-GDP ratio should return to a relatively stable level in the short term.</p>

<p>你可以看出为什么许多的美国人都反对增加财政收入以缩小预算缺口这个计划。他们认为自己正为一些政府支出买单，而对这些支出，他们并不喜欢。值得庆幸的是，随着经济状况的好转，他们的税金花在所谓“政府浪费”上的份额也减少了。事实上，美国最近一系列大规模赤字背后的许多类似情况与经济衰退有关，经济不佳造成税收减少，而对诸如失业保险，食物券和医疗补助的支出却与日俱增。当经济复苏，财政收入增加，社会福利支出减少时，债务占国内生产总值比率在短期内应该恢复到一个相对稳定的水平。</p>

<p>The longer-term fiscal outlook is more bleak, but my holiday crowd does not distinguish between the distinct challenges. They again blame &ldquo;waste&rdquo; and those they call &ldquo;the takers&rdquo;. Some people are hooked on government handouts, they say, echoing a common refrain from last year&rsquo;s election battle. In keeping with the remarkable disconnect between the actual takers and their perception of reality, none of my group acknowledges their own enjoyment of government social programmes.</p>

<p>虽然从长期来看，财政前景惨淡，但是在假期和我一起参与讨论的政党对这些明显挑战的认识却没什么不同。他们将责任归咎于这种“浪费行为“和他们所称的“索求者”。他们认为，有些人依赖政府救济（这一说法在去年美国大选中已司空见惯）。社会福利的真正索取者和他们对现实的认识之间有着显著的偏差，与此相一致的，和我讨论的小组成员中没人意识到自己享受的政府社会福利项目。</p>

<p>Many Americans don&rsquo;t like the things they believe their money is buying. But their bill is hardly reduced by cutting payments to the jobless, dependent moochers they see as the cause of the country&rsquo;s fiscal troubles. Last year the Center on Budget and Policy Priorities ran the numbers and found</p>

<p>他们不喜欢他们所缴税金所买的东西。他们将失业者和吃皇粮的人视为国家财政困难的根源。但减少对这这人的救济支出也很难使他们的税单减少。去年，预算和政策优先中心分析数据发现：</p>

<p>“People who are neither elderly nor disabled — and do not live in a working household — received only 9 percent of [entitlement] benefits. Moreover, the vast bulk of that 9 percent goes for medical care, unemployment insurance benefits (which individuals must have a significant work history to receive), Social Security survivor benefits for the children and spouses of deceased workers, and Social Security benefits for retirees between ages 62 and 64. Seven out of the 9 percentage points go for one of these four purposes.”</p>

<p>“那些既非年老，残疾且非来自工薪家庭的人只享受到9%的国家福利。而且，这9%的福利主要是医疗服务，失业保险（受益者必须有足够的工作经历才能享有）， 在职人士过世后其子女和配偶所获得的社会保障遗眷福利，以及62-64岁退休人员享有的社会保障福利。在这仅有的9%的福利中，7/9只能享有其中一项福利。”</p>

<p>The story is similar when looking at discretionary programmes—if there is a pure &ldquo;entitlement society&rdquo;, it is small and poorly funded.</p>

<p>社会补充福利的情况也类似 - 如果说有一个纯粹的“福利社会”，那么这个社会规模小而且资助缺乏。</p>

<p>There is a reason politicians often do not specify which spending cuts they&rsquo;re talking about in budget negotiations: the popular ones (see cuts to foreign aid) don&rsquo;t add up. And, in general, Americans do like the programmes that primarily drive the country&rsquo;s fiscal imbalances—notably Social Security (20% of the budget) and Medicare (21%, taken with Medicaid and CHIP). Most of us do or will (hopefully) benefit from those programmes. That leaves us with the uncomfortable reality that we, not the jobless moochers, are the problem.</p>

<p>政客们通常没有详细说明预算谈判中所讨论的财政削减的原因：民众都支持削减的项目（如对外援助）数额不足以填补漏洞，总的来说，美国人不喜欢那些作为国家财政失衡主要推手的福利项目。—尤其是社会保障福利（占20%的财政）和医疗服务（占21%，还包括医疗补助与儿童健保项目）。乐观的来说，大部分人能或将要享受这些福利项目。这么一来，我们面对一个令人不安的现实：即我们才是问题的所在，而非那些啃福利的失业者。</p>

<p>Greg Mankiw, an economist and former advisor to Mitt Romney, made clear the challenge facing America in a column two weeks ago: &ldquo;Ultimately, unless we scale back entitlement programs far more than anyone in Washington is now seriously considering, we will have no choice but to increase taxes on a vast majority of Americans.&rdquo; My colleague notes that Jonathan Chait is confident that Americans will choose tax hikes over cuts to their own entitlements. But is that really the calculation most Americans are making? Most are still in denial over their role in America&rsquo;s fiscal drama. And as long as they are able to find convenient scapegoats for the country&rsquo;s fiscal challenges they will oppose the infliction of pain on themselves. Someone needs to tell these people, it&rsquo;s not them, it&rsquo;s you.</p>

<p>两周以前，经济学家兼为罗姆尼前顾问Greg Mankiwa在一专栏明确指出美国面临的挑战：“从长远来看，除非仔细考虑超过以往任何缩减福利项目的计划，否则我们只能对大部分美国民众提高征税。”我同事说Jonathan Chait深信美国人宁愿选择增加赋税而不愿减少他们享有的福利。但是这真的是大部分美国人所考虑的吗？大部分人仍然在不愿意承认他们在这场美国财政闹剧中所扮演的角色。而且只要能够找到国家财政困难的替罪羔羊，他们不会感到痛苦。需要有人告诉这些人，根源不是他们，还是你们自己。</p>

<hr />

<p>注释1: 福利皇后：美国总统奥巴马出台的一项福利政策，主要是针对那些没有从事物质生产，为美国繁衍后代做出贡献的黑人中年妇女。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
